<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dr.Sebi</string>
    <string name="herb">Herbs</string>
    <string name="cell_food">Cell Food</string>
    <string name="diet_plan">Diet Plan</string>
    <string name="game">Game</string>

    <!-- Herbs -->
    <string name="bladderwrack_details">
        It has high levels of mucilage, iodine, potassium, and other organic compounds.
        Especially, in iodine, it is very rich and an early source of this mineral.
        Benefits include
        thyroid improvement, weight loss, better vision, anti-aging,
        boost heart health, improves womens health and more.
    </string>
    <string name="blessed_thistle_details">
        Blessed Thistle has an ability to cure numerous ailments.
        It is also known as Holy Thistle or St. Benedicts Thistle.
        PPHerbalists indeed call it a gift from God, particularly for women,
        as it facilitates in resolving many female related problems.
        It increases milk supply and also treats hormone imbalance.
        Furthermore, it also contains astringent compounds that shrink inflamed tissues and dilate peripheral blood vessels.
        Benefits include
        Antibacterial, anti-inflammatory, anti-microbial, promotes digestive health,
        stimulates appetite, helpful for upset stomach, shrinks inflamed tissues,
        stimulates milk supply, protects liver, and helps in treating jaundice, fevers, and arthritis
    </string>
    <string name="blue_vervain_details">
        It is a slender and an erect perennial plant, that has green to reddish stems and tooted leaves,
        it is also known as Verbena Hastata and American Vervain.
        Research shows that its leaves and flowers contain many active components.
        They have antispasmodic, antipyretic, and diuretic properties.
        Furthermore, it also assists in soothing the nervous system, detoxifying the body,
        lowering inflammation, and alleviating chest congestion.
        Benefits include
        Antibacterial, antimicrobial, detoxifies body, treats respiratory disorder,
        cardio-protective, boosts gum health, keeps nervous system healthy, anti-anxiety relaxant,
        relieves depression, eases menstruation, anti-inflammatory, and reduces swelling.
    </string>
    <string name="burdock_root_details">
        They are about a meter in height with broad, heart-shaped leaves.
        The top of their leaves are deep green, while the underside is light green.
        Furthermore, its stems, which are almost 5 feet in length, have red-purple tubular flowers
        that after a few weeks turn into seed-heeds with hooked spines. All the parts of
        the Burdock plant can be used for certain medical conditions.
        But, its 2 to 3 feet root, which is brownish and has almost similar shape carrot,
        possesses the actual benefits. It grows to its actual length near its harvesting time.
        When it comes to health benefits, the properties of this root are exceptional and uncountable.
        It is a powerhouse of antioxidants and protects cells in the body from damage.
        Due to its multiple types of powerful antioxidants,
        herbalists use it for treating and preventing different health conditions.
        Benefits include
        Natural diuretic, reduce body weight, skin healer, combat cancer, removes toxins from blood,
        improves arthritis, fight tonsillitis, prevent infection, control heart rate and blood pressure,
        regulate cholesterol levels in the blood, and cure diabetes.
    </string>
    <string name="cascara_sagrada_details">
        It is a natural, potent herb. It is produced from the bark of the Rhamnus Purshiana tree.
        The other common names of Cascara Sagrada are bitter bark, buckthorn, chitem bark, and sacred bark.
        It has the ability to treat many issues like digestive problems, muscle and joint pains,
        hemorrhoids, and anxiety. Furthermore, it is quite effective against many major diseases like cancer too.
        Researchers have investigated its application in cancer treatment.
        They have discovered that its active constituent emodin can inhibit cancer growth through a precise mechanism.
        Other than that, the same active constituent, emodin, is antimicrobial and anti-inflammatory.
        It prevents bacteria and shows promising results against inflammation too.
        Benefits include
        Antimicrobial, anti-inflammatory, anti-fungal, prevents cancer, treats constipation,
        protects against liver diseases, diminish the occurrence of hemorrhoids,
        improves emotional well-being, protects against amnesia, and cures anxiety.
    </string>
    <string name="chaparral_leaf">
      Also known as creosote bush and jarilla hembra, is a strong healing herb.
        It is famous for curing the incurable. It is tough to guess its potency just by looking at it,
        as it has small leaves. But, herbalists reveal that they have exceptional healing abilities.
        They cleanse your body and protect you against many deadly diseases. The chaparral has many benefits,
        but people call it the cure for incurable because of its anti-cancer properties.
        It is anti-tumor agent, nor-dihihydroguairetic, and inhibits the energy producing ability of cancer cells.
        Moreover, it also slows down cell proliferation and does not let the disease cause any damage to DNA.
        Chaparral contains numerous other properties that give this herb an edge over other herbs.
        For example, it has Tricyclic Lignans compounds, which are anti-HIV agent.
        They are immensely powerful and known as a natural anti-viral treatment option.
        In addition, this herb can be used for alleviating rheumatic pain, stomach pain, chicken pox, and snake bite pain as well.
        Benefits include
        Anti-cancer, anti-HIV, treats acne, cures diabetes, promotes weight loss, purifies blood,
        prevents skin infections, heals minor wounds, alleviate arthritis and back pain.
        It also treats urinary tract infections, menstrual disorders and premenstrual syndrome.
    </string>
    <string name="contribo_details">
        Contribo is a very unique herb. It grows along stream and in other wet areas.
        It is notable for its use in western herbal medicine.
        Various cultures around the world use Contribo for treating numerous diseases.
        Even ancient Greeks, Romans, and Byzantines have used it in their pharmaceutical
        recipes to treat a variety of health conditions. Their experts utilized this herb to
        treat conditions like kidney ailments, bladder stones, gout, snakebite,
        uterine complaints, and insomnia. There are numerous ways to use this herb.
        Some people soak it in water before relishing it as a cup of tea,
        while others use it with honey and olive oil.
        Herbalists recommend using its water as a lotion too, specifically for treating wounds and skin infections.
        Modern-day researchers are investigating Contribo properties even more.
        According to them, it holds a lot more power than you can imagine.
        For example, when you infuse it in water and consume it, it gives your body immense power to fight with cold and flu.
        Its properties are a lot more powerful and effective than many famous medicines.
        Fortunately, they are without any kind of side effects too. In addition, if you have some appetite issues,
        Contribo can assist in that as well. It enhances the appetite and aids in improving your overall health.
        There are some precautions that you must consider before using this herb.
        Experts believe one should avoid continuous use of Contribo as it contains aristolochic acid.
        Because of its poisonous nature, continuous use of it can damage human health in the long run
        Benefits include
        It’s a remedy against poisonous effects of snake bite, alleviates fever,
        enhances appetite, heals bruises and wounds, treats kidney ailments,
        bladder stones, uterine complaints, beneficial for women giving birth, and builds strength against cold.
    </string>
    <string name="damiana_details">
        Damiana is a wild shrub. It is aromatic and belongs to the Turneraceae plant family.
        It is popular among herbalists since the ancient Aztec time. They find this herb in abundance in Mexico,
        Central America, and West Indies to treat different ailments. According to historians, the name of this herb comes for the Greeks.
        They used to call it Daman or Damia, which means to tame or subdue.
        They used its leaves in herbal smoking blends and in liquors as well to calm their nerves.
        It helped them in increasing sexual desires too. And, the modern researchers confirm this.
        They have confirmed Damiana effects in a lab study on rats.
        It showed its aphrodisiac properties and increased the desires in those rats which were either sexually sluggish or fatigued.
        It also reduced their anxiety and made them appear calmer.
        The native people of Mexico still use this herb to increase their energy and boost their sexual potency.
        They indeed treat their potency and menstrual problems through Damiana.
        Therefore, if you specifically deal with anxiety, depression, nervousness, tension, or sexual problems,
        you can not get anything better than this herb. It is herbal healing process, and a gods gift, without any kind of side effects.
        There are many other health benefits of Damiana.
        For example, it reduces gastric emptying rate, protects against liver diseases, promotes weight loss, and et cetera.
        It is packed with vitamins and minerals, boosts sexuality, improves sexual satisfaction,
        reduces vaginal dryness, promotes weight loss, treats headache, depression, and constipation,
        enhances mood, and boosts mental and physical stamina.
    </string>
    <string name="eyebright_details">
       Eyebright, also famous as Euphrasia meaning well-being and Meadow Eyebright, is from the family of Orobanchaceae.
        It is often found in alpine or sub-alpine meadows where snow is common.
        Its leaves have jagged, toothy edges, which are quite different from other plants.
        Also, the flowers of eyebright have different variations.
        They are usually in white, yellow, and red color with a yellow spot in throat.
        This plant was known to classical herbalists.
        However, 21st century researchers and herbalists are taking great interest in it too.
        Their researches are proving its strength when it comes to treating eye redness, eye swelling, and visual disturbance.
        They reveal, any eye issue, caused by blepharitis and conjunctivitis, can be relieved by eyebright.
        Furthermore, it can also assist in reducing eye inflammation. You can use it as an eye wash or eye drops.
        There are many other health benefits of this herb.
        Experts recommend eyebright for treating hay fever, sinusitis, upper respiratory tract infections,
        nasal irritations, seasonal allergies, and bronchial colds.
        The most interesting thing about eyebright is it heals skin wounds too quite quickly.
        It is made into a poultice and used on the wound topically.
        Benefits include
        Treats eye conditions (eye redness, eye swelling, visual disturbance), hay fever,
        upper respiratory tract infections, seasonal allergies, nasal irritations.
        It also heal skin wound, skin infections like acne, and skin inflammation.
        It facilitates in tightening skin too.
    </string>
    <string name="hydrangea_details">
        Hydrangea is more than just a beautiful flowering plant.
        It is an ornamental and medicinal plant found in North America, South America, and Asia.
        It has 70-75 species too, that’s why its properties depend on its specie too.
        However, most species share the same benefits. The roots of Hydrangea plant contain many phytochemicals and nutrients like calcium,
        zinc, and selenium. Therefore, they are greatly important for herbalists,
        as they use it to treat numerous health conditions. Some people attempt to use the leaves of Hydrangea plants too.
        However, herbalists don’t recommend that all. Since, their leaves contain toxic substances.
        They should never be consumed for recreational or medicinal purposes. Its popularity grew in the 1730s when English people used its roots,
        which contains several active alkaloids, to treat simple health conditions like cold and fever.
        The most common use of Hydrangea is to treat kidneys and bladder.
        Since, the chemicals in this herb cause increase urine output which assist in treating urinary tract problems.
        Experts confirm its diuretic properties through numerous lab test and researches.
        They state that the increase in the flow of urine remove impurities from your body.
        This not only treats kidneys, but also improves your overall health.
        Apart from this, one of the most important compounds of Hydrangea, halofuginone, cures autoimmune disorders.
        It treats the disorder, while allowing your immune system to function normally as well.
        This same compound of Hydrangea also facilitates in treating malaria, enlarged prostate, kidney stones and blood sugar imbalances.
        In addition, the bark of this herb is as important as the root. It helps in relieving wounds, and sore muscles.
        Benefits include
        Treat wounds, sore muscles, burns, and sprain. It also facilitates in curing rheumatoid arthritis, multiple sclerosis,
        inflammatory bowel disease, urinary tract problems, and autoimmune disorders. One can use this herb for treat chronic chest pains as well.
    </string>
    <string name="lavendar_details">
        Nearly 40 plants in the mint family are known as Lavender. But, the most common form, which is packed with immense health benefits,
        is Lavandula Augustifolia. This lavender is available in almost all parts of the world. And, perhaps,
        that’s why it is widely used in its massive range of applications.
        Herbalists from all walks of life use it because of its powerful effects on human body.
        They use its stems, leaves, and flowers to treat many ailments. It is quite easy to identify Lavender.
        Its needle-like foliage has a balsam like scent. It is either in bluish green color or in gray.
        It has indeed the shades of these two colors. In addition, overall height of this plant is around three feet if the growing conditions are right.
        Lavender has many constituents that make it an important herb in the medical field.
        It constituents include terpinenol, cineole, borneol, camphor, rosmarinic acid, triterpenoids, flavonoids, linabol, and etc.
        Furthermore, it is aromatic, insect repellent, and sedative.
        Besides, medicinally, there are lots of other health benefits of Lavender too.
        For example, if you deal with chronic headaches or migraine, it can work as a head balm or essential oil to alleviate your pain.
        All you need is to just rub it on the temples at the first sign of head ache. Next, it also promotes deep sleep. Its scent is sedative.
        Trouble sleepers can slip into the dreamland while relishing its fragrances. It relaxes their mind and soothes muscles.
        Other than that, if you have skin issues like acne or rashes, infuse it in water and then use it on your skin.
        You can even take bath with it. Its antiseptic properties will banish all the acne and rash problems within a few days.
        It also cures bruises and scrapes, but it is better to use it as a cooling remedy for them.
        Keep its water bottle in the refrigerator for a few minutes before applying it on bruises or fresh scars.
        Benefits include
        Promotes sleep, reduce headache, treats chronic migraine issues, assists in curing skin diseases,
        heals bruises and scars, lessens anxiety and stress, possesses anti-inflammatory qualities,
        improves the quality of your hair, and protects heart health.
    </string>
    <string name="lilly_details">
        Lily of the valley is a flowering plant from the asparagus family.
        It blooms in late spring and is often found in the Northern Hemisphere in Asia and Europe.
        It sends up a single flower that has as many as 12 white small flowers.
        Herbalists call it by different names, such as May Bells and Marys Tears. Since, it is very special and different appearance.
        The leaves of lily of the valley are upright, glossy-green. They can reach a length of approximately 9 inches with 4-inch width.
        Furthermore, its bell shaped flowers have 5-10 mm diameter. They have sweet-scented petals that make it more mesmerizing.
        Because of this sweet-scent of lily of the valley, it is associated with happiness, humility, and vision of better world.
        And, thats why, it has significant role in mythological stories as well.
        Lily of the valley has many properties. It is antispasmodic, diuretic, laxative, emetic, and sedative.
        Furthermore, the effect of this plant is more gradual. Therefore, it does not pose toxic problem to the kidneys.
        But, if you would exceed its dosage or use it for a long term, it can cause some side effects.
        For that reason, herbalists do not recommend its use during pregnancy or lactation.
        They also do not utilize its red berries as well for medicinal purposes, as they are highly poisonous. They only use its leaves for treating ailments.
        Probably, because of these reasons, experts call it a restricted herb. According to them, it should be used only under the supervision of a qualified herbalist.
        However, it does not mean it is without any health benefits. Its benefits outweigh its cons.
        For example, this lily of the valley is known as a cardiac tonic too. It facilitates in curing many heart health issues.
        In addition, it also helps in easing mental problems like depression, stress, headaches, and melancholy.
        Benefits include
        Antispasmodic, diuretic, laxative, sedative, and emetic. It also eases mental problems, treats congestive heart failures,
        lessens chest pains caused by spasms, treats urinary tract infection, keeps digestion healthy, breaks kidney stones, and reduces swelling.
    </string>
    <string name="nettles_details">
        Nettles have been used for centuries to treat allergy symptoms. According to Dr. Andrew Wiel, a renowned author of Natural Medicine,
        when it comes to allergy relief, he knows of nothing more effective than nettle.
        Though, most people remember it because of its sting as it causes burning sensations, but in reality,
        this pain causing plant is a solution to treat their allergy issues. They can count on it, without getting worried regarding its side effects.
        It is the first plant that rises up in the spring and graces the world with green. You can find it in almost every part of the world.
        But, its ideal growing conditions are in the colder regions of Europe and Asia.
        The height of this plant is around 4 feet and it blooms from June to September. It has heart-shaped leaves with yellow and pink flowers.
        Though, it is a wild plant, but you can cultivate it on your own in a nitrogen-rich soil.
        The benefits of this herb have been studies extensively. They have shown promising signs in treating numerous diseases,
        such as Alzheimer, Arthritis, Asthma, Bladder Infection, and prostate enlargement.
        Professional herbalists believe that this entire plant is beneficial for human health.
        For that reason, they use its stems and leaves for making medicines.
        However, at the same time, they utilize its root too because of its immense pharmacological qualities.
        The combinations of these three parts of this plant allow them to treat many health issues. Since, each part has its own specific set of benefits.
        Despite its reputation as a stinging plant, research shows that it has antioxidant, antimicrobial, anti-ulcer, and analgesic properties.
        But, it is mostly famous for treating Benign Prostatic Hyperplasia and Urinary issues. It has chemicals that affect hormones that cause BPH.
        These chemicals assist in preventing prostate cancer cells too.
        Benefits include
        Antioxidant, antimicrobial, anti-ulcer, and astringent. It treats Benign Prostatic Hyperplasia, urinary issues,
        osteoarthritis and joint pain, hay fever, and skin diseases like eczema. It also promotes lactation, stimulates hair growth, and controls blood sugar.
    </string>
    <string name="prodijiosa_details">
        Prodigiosa, also known as Brickellia, is an immensely beneficial herb. It is a flowering plant that comes from the daisy family.
        It is quite easy to recognize this plant, as the leaves are rich green on the top and gray purple on the underside.
        The overall height is 70 centimeter while the leaves are up to 12 centimeters long.
        In Mexican and Native American herbal traditions, it has great importance in lowering blood sugar level and treating diabetes.
        In other parts of the world, it is famous as Love Leaf, Mystical Caribbean, and Arma poi.
        Some people indeed believe that if you want to grow your love, just write name of person you love and then place Prodigiosa leaf over it.
        It will connect the hearts and souls and make you fall in love even more. Other than that, in case you are dealing with headache or stress,
        all you need is to take its leaf and place it on your head for a few minutes. This will relieve tension and bring calmness.
        This shows its versatility and admiration in different parts of the world.
        Experts believe that the bitterness of this herb and other components are quite effective in treating many ailments.
        For example, if you are dealing with digestive problems, you can count on it, as its properties promote healthy digestion because of its bitterness.
        It actually improves the quantity and quality of the hydrochloric acid that assist in resolving upset stomach issues.
        Furthermore, it also releases the gastric hormone, which stimulates the function of all digestive organs, such as liver, stomach, and pancreas.
        Fortunately, when it comes to preparation of Prodigiosa, it is quite easy. All you need is to steep this herb in the boiling water for at least 10 minutes and enjoy it as tea.
        Benefits include
        Improves kidney function, promotes digestion, improves the quantity and quality of hydrochloric acid,
        evacuates bile from the gall bladder, controls elevated blood sugars, extremely beneficial in type-2 diabetes, and stimulates immune function.
    </string>
    <string name="purslane_details">
        Purslane is an edible weed with extraordinary value. Despite being classified by the USDA as a noxious weed,
        it is part of Dr. Sebi Approved food due to the vast array of antioxidants, vitamins and minerals that can be extracted from this herb.
        This herb is widely used in certain cuisines as a great addition to salads and many other recipes.
        Many describe the taste as a bit sour but mildly sweet. Since it is a succulent, the leaves are very crisp, which makes it a great add-on for salads.
        Health Benefits of Purslane, Rich in Omega-3 Fatty Acids. Purslane is one of the richest green plant sources of Omega-3 fats.
        It can lower triglyceride and cholesterol levels while increasing the healthy high density lipoprotein.
        Works as an Antioxidant. Purslane leaves have been found to possess higher amount of beta-carotene, ascorbic acid and alpha-tocopherol.
        Ascorbic acid and beta-carotene are known to have antioxidant qualities due to their ability to neutralize free radicals and
        even present certain cancers and cardiovascular disease. Aid in Weight Loss. Purslane contains very low calorie but a nutrition
        superstar with high dietary fiber. This means that you can easily feel full and satisfied after consuming a meal of purslane.
        Improve Gastrointestinal Diseases. In Traditional Chinese Medicine, purslane was widely used for treating nearly everything,
        from hemorrhoids to diarrhea and intestinal bleeding. Even today, it is used for a wide range of digestive condition.
        The digestive health benefits of purslane are mainly attributed to its natural compounds, including dopamine, citric acid, alanine,
        glucose, malic acid and many others. Strong Bones and Teeth. The wide array of minerals found in purslane work together to promote stronger
        bones and teeth. The elements necessary for building strong bone tissue include calcium, manganese, iron and magnesium.
        In addition, these minerals help speed up the healing process of bone which can prevent development of osteoporosis.
        Improved Circulation. The copper and iron found in purslane help stimulate red blood cell production.
        When there’s sufficient level of these minerals in the body, there’s more oxygen being delivered to different parts of the body,
        which increases healing of organs and cells and improves metabolic efficiency.
    </string>
    <string name="red_clover_details">
        Red Clover, or Trifolium Pratense, is a natural source of bioidentical estrogen. It is from the bean family, Fabaceae,
        with most prominent three leaves. Because of its unique design and number of leaves, it is famous as three-leaf clover too.
        You can easily find it in the regions of Asia, Europe, and Northwest Africa. This plant grows to 20-80 cm tall.
        Its each leaflet is 15-30 mm long and 8-15 mm broad. The color of these leaflets is green with pale crescent in the outer half of the leaf.
        Believe it or not, because of its outstanding medicinal properties (deobstruent, antispasmodic, expectorant, and sedative),
        Red Clover has become a source of economic stability in Chile. It is grown as a fodder crop, which increase soil fertility too.
        Scientists verify that this three-leaf clover also has hormone like chemicals – isoflavones.
        These valuable chemicals are almost impossible to find in any other herb.
        They exhibit antioxidant, anticancer, antimicrobial and anti-inflammatory properties. However,
        it doesn’t mean your diet should be high in isoflavones all the time, since, in large quantities, it can cause reproductive failure and liver disease.
        But, Red Clover possesses high nutritional value as well, which assist in treating many health conditions.
        It can reduce hypertension, boost immune system (because of high doses of vitamin C), neutralize free radicals,
        prevent infections, ease menstruation and menopause, lower cholesterol, detoxify body (by releasing excess toxins through increased urination),
        and stimulate healthy circulation for preventing cardiovascular distress.
        This herb is very potent. Therefore, herbalists don’t recommend high dosage of it.
        Just 85 milligrams of this herb on a daily basis can be considered safe for most adults.
        If you’re interested in making red clover tea, two spoons of its dried flowers in 8 ounces of hot water are enough.
        However, don’t opt for more than two tea-cups of Red Clover daily.
        Benefits include
        Detoxifies the blood, cleanses liver, keep arteries clear, reduces hypertension, boosts immune system, eases menstruation or menopause,
        maintains bone mineral density too, lowers inflammation of the skin, neutralizes free radicals, and prevents infection.
    </string>
    <string name="rhurbarb_details">
        Rhubarb Root, commonly called Chinese Rhubarb, Turkish Rhubarb, or Indian Rhubarb, has a long history of herbal usage.
        Though, it is popular in the entire world, but it is extensively used in traditional Chinese medicines.
        Chinese herbalists and botanists try to cultivate it on large scale in China to treat serious health issues like cancer and digestive complaints.
        This plant persists as a weed in many gardens, it can grow as much as six feet.
        The blade and leaves of this plant have high oxalic acid concentration. Therefore, professional herbalists avoid them,
        because of their poisonous nature, and only focus on its roots. They are first dried and then ground into a yellowish-orange powder.
        These roots are sour and bitter in taste, but their extract can be used as antispasmodic,
        anticholesterolemic, antiseptic, astringent, and diuretic. Moreover, these roots contain anthraquinones.
        It is a natural occurring compound which is antibacterial, antifungal, antiviral, and antioxidant.
        This compound protects from conditions likes cancer, diabetes, liver disease, kidney disease, and malaria.
        However, large doses of it can cause skin irritations. If you have dealt with dermatitis reactions,
        it is better to speak your doctor first to ensure the Rhubarb Roots is safe for you.
        Apart from this, there are lots of other health benefits of Rhubarb Roots. It treats conditions like diarrhea,
        constipation, stomach pain, gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding, anal fissures, liver and gall bladder complaints,
        menstrual problems, intestinal and autoimmune reactions. In addition, when you consume its extract before meals, it enhances appetite too.
        The extract of Rhubarb Root has been studied as a possible cure for cancer as well. Since, its aloe-emodin, chrysophanol,
        emodic, and gallic acid are anti-cancer agents. They also eradicate tumors inside the body.
        That’s why scientists and physicians have great interest in it. They are trying to explore its potential as herbal treatment for cancer.
        Benefits include
        Antispasmodic, anticholesterolemic, antiseptic, astringent, antibacterial, antifungal, antiviral, antioxidant and diuretic.
        It also treats hypertension, menstrual irregularities, elevated blood lipids, diarrhea, heartburn, constipation and stomach pain.
    </string>
    <string name="sage_leaves_details">
        Ancient Egyptians and Greek physicians have used Sage to treat sprains, swelling, ulcers, and bleeding.
        It was considered to have substantial healing properties. And, the modern, 21st century medical experts are confirming this too.
        According to them, it has terrific nutritional value which has shown promising signs in treating many diseases.
        Sage is native to southern Europe and the Mediterranean region. But you can find it in other warmer climates, such as in North America.
        It is actually a perennial woody herb, which has unbelievable impact on human health. It has grayish leaves and blue to purplish flowers.
        Among herbalists, it is also known as Salvia Officinalis, Garden Save, and Culinary Sage.
        Several lab tests have confirmed its tremendous nutritional value. Just one tablespoon of sage has 43 percent vitamin K,
        which is exactly the same amount our body needs to operate well. Also, it is an excellent source of fiber, vitamin C, vitamin A, vitamin E,
        calcium, iron, and magnesium. Researchers have also found B-vitamins such as riboflavin in them.
        They also play a significant role in keeping our body running like a well-oriented machine.
        Recent researches reveal that this special herb is not only for treating wounds and healing.
        Its right dosage can facilitate in treating snake bites, boosting female fertility, increasing memory retention, treating inflammation,
        curing issues like arthritis and gout, neutralizing free radicals, preventing Alzheimers disease, strengthening immune system,
        improving bone health, managing diabetes, and preventing gastric spasms.
        Furthermore, you can use this herb for treating many skin conditions like eczema, psoriasis, and acne.
        All you need is to apply its extracts on a regular basis to the affected area.
        This herb is most commonly used in tea form. You can also add it to food while cooking or sprinkle it over salads and sandwiches.
        Herbalists recommend only 400 mg of sage extract on a daily basis. Just use it in normal doses, as large doses can be toxic for you.
        Benefits include
        Sage is antiseptic, antibacterial, and antioxidant. It is an excellent source of fiber, vitamin C, vitamin A, vitamin E, calcium, iron, and magnesium.
        It also treats conditions like Alzheimer, weak immune system, arthritis, diabetes, and inflammation.
    </string>
    <string name="santa_maria_details">
        Santa Maria is native to Mexico, Central America, and South America. You can even find it in India, Australia, and parts of Africa.
        It is a flowering plant in the aster family – Asteraceae, also known as Parthenium Hysterophorus, Whitetop Weed, Gajar Ghans, and Famine Weed.
        The leaves of Santa Maria are quite simple, but they are not separated into leaflets.
        Some of them have teeth on their edges, while others are without them. Apart from this, the flowers are in white, yellow color with 4-5 mm width.
        In some areas, where the required temperature is right, this plant grows tremendously and affects crop productions too.
        Therefore, they are the most feared plants on the earth. Particularly, for farmers, it affects their livestock and invite lots of troubles for them.
        This is not a new herb. In reality, for centuries, it was used to lower fever and constipation.
        Our ancestors have used it for various other ailments as well, such as depression, vertigo, and kidney stones.
        They have used this herbs extract to treat wound and pains. Recent studies are showing that it still holds a lot of latent health benefits.
        It is rich in vitamins and minerals and has many other key components like volatile oil, sesquiterpene lactones, and sesquiterpenes (camphor).
        These features assist this plant in treating issues like arthritis, anxiety, stress, inflammation, migraines, blood clots, and blood pressure.
        If you are specifically dealing with heart health problems, Santa Maria can help in that too.
        It lowers the chances of experiencing atherosclerosis, heart attacks, and strokes.
        It actually reduces the production of prostaglandins that cause some serious cardiovascular issues.
        Bear in mind that it isn’t a perfect kind of herb. There are some side effects as well that can cause dermatitis and respiratory malfunctions in humans.
        However, its benefits still outweigh its cons. They are beneficial for many out of control ailments.
        Benefits include
        Santa Maria treats joint pain, difficult menses, migraine, arthritis, hair fall, fever, cancer, appetite issues, respiratory problems, dermatitis,
        blood pressure, blood clots, anxiety, stress, inflammation, bruises, headaches, swelling, difficult breathing, and coughs.
    </string>
    <string name="sarsaparilla_details">
        Sarsaparilla is a woody, thorny plant from the genus Smilax. It grows deep in the cover of the rainforest.
        You can easily find it in the warm, tropical area in the world. This plant has different names, including catbriers, carrion flowers, or prickly-ivys.
        However, the most common name, especially among the herbalists, is Smilax Ornata (formally Smilax Regelii).
        For thousands of years, Sarsaparilla has been used as herbal remedy. Especially, native populations in South and Central America used
        it to relieve a wide range of problems. Historians reveal that this plant was first introduced as herb near the end of Dark Ages.
        People used it to treat internal and external health problems. Unlike many other herbs, Sarsaparilla grows quite well.
        It climbs well and grows over 50 yards long. That’s why, they are known as evergreen shrubs and hanging vines too.
        They have clusters of red and purple berries, which can be in lustrous black color. And, these berries are popular among humans and birds too.
        This plant has gained popularity and respect mainly because of its root, as it has a high concentration of nutrients and organic compounds.
        Its root is tuberous in shape and can grow between 6-8 feet in length. Herbalists have used its powder in traditional medicines
        to treat symptoms of sexual impotence, headaches, cold, joint pain, and et cetera.
        However, recent scientific studies are confirming that its root is also beneficial for preventing cancer and tumor growth, liver damage,
        skin problems, and sexually transmitted diseases. It has many active chemical properties, such as antioxidants, saponins, plant sterols, flavonoid
        antioxidants, anti-inflammatory phytochemicals, and voltaic oils and acids. Fortunately, there are no known major side effects of using Sarsaparilla.
        Just avoid taking large doses of it on a consistent basis as it can cause stomach irritation due to saponins.
        Benefits include
        antioxidants, saponins, plant sterols, flavonoid antioxidants, anti-inflammatory phytochemicals, voltaic oils and acids, and trace minerals like iron,
        aluminum, and zinc. It treats sexual impotence, headaches, cold, joint pain, cancer, and immune system.
    </string>
    <string name="sea_moss_details">
        Irish Sea Moss is a nutritious healing sea vegetable. It has many other names as well, like Carrageen Moss and Chondrus Crispus.
        This amazing sea vegetable grows commonly around the shores of Ireland. That’s why, it is more famous as Irish moss, but it doesn’t only grow there.
        You can abundantly find it in the Atlantic coast of Europe and North America. Its color ranges from green to yellowish and dark purple to purplish brown.
        This sea moss is extremely valuable for our health because its 92 out of 100 minerals are found in our bodies.
        For that reason, Irish people rely on it to avoid starvation and support their health. Bear in mind,
        this doesn’t mean this herb is edible if it is directly coming from the sea. Since, it will have a rubbery and tough texture.
        First, you have to simmer it and then consume it as a liquid soup. You can also boil it inside milk to avail its benefits.
        In Jamaica, some people indeed boil it inside milk to make a thick drink that is aphrodisiac.
        When it comes to its nutritional profile, it is exceptional.
        It has 8.9 mg iron, 144 mg magnesium, 0.5 mg riboflavin, 0.1 mg copper, and 157 mg phosphorus.
        Furthermore, it is packed with many other special compounds like zinc, manganese, and calcium too.
        The best benefit of Irish sea moss is it creates a feeling of fullness.
        Therefore, it is perfect for those who are attempting to lose weight. Besides, it holds many other health benefits as well.
        For example, its anti-inflammatory properties make it perfect for injuries, skin, and pains.
        Furthermore, it supports emotional health, strengthens connective tissues, soothes digestive tract, prevents symptoms of cold and flu,
        and improves mental functioning.It is better to avoid its prolonged consumption of it as it functions as a blood thinner too.
        Benefits include
        Antiviral, antimicrobial, anti-inflammatory, and detoxifying agent.
        It supports emotional health, accelerates recovery from join injuries, suppress the appetite, strengthens connective tissues,
        treats sore throat and chest coughs, and improves mental functioning.
    </string>
    <string name="valerian_details">
        Other common names of Valerian are Valeriana Officinalis, Cut Finger, and Garden Valerian. Due its exceptional health properties,
        it is famous as all-heal herb too. Even its name indicates the meaning of strong and healthy in the Latin dictionary.
        It is a perennial plant, native to Europe and Asia. Its root has enormously important chemical like gamma aminobutyric acid (GABA),
        which facilitate in treating many brain related issues. If you deal with anxiety or stress or any kind of distress,
        it means you are struggling with low levels of aminobutyric acid (GABA) in the brain.
        Consistent use of Valerian increases the GABA levels and banishes all these symptoms. In other words,
        its properties contribute to a calming effect in body. You will often see its crude extract in the forms of capsules,
        which people use as a dietary supplement to relieve the symptoms of insomnia, stress, and anxiety.
        They believe it has sedative and anxiolytic effect, which is more natural and powerful than many other drugs.
        But, anti-anxiety effect isn’t the only thing. Valerian root has many other components that lower blood pressure,
        ease menstrual cramp, and improve stress management. Though, remember that it possess some minor side effects too,
        such as headache, dizziness, and stomach problems. In some cases, you can also deal with irritability and uneasiness.
        Professional herbalists do not recommend more than 900 mg of valerian extract each day. According to them,
        consuming its extracts 2 hours before the bedtime gives significant results, particularly if you are trying to soothe mind or cure insomnia.
        However, one should not use it for more than 28 days. Since, prolonged use of Valerian can increase the symptoms of insomnia and anxiety, even more.
        In addition, in case you are pregnant, avoid this herb to stay on the safe side, as it slows down the nervous system.
        Benefits include
        Magic sleep potion, hypnotic, antispasmodic, sedative, anxiolytic, nervous system tonic, and muscle relaxant.
        It is also high in selenium, tin, aluminum, iron, and magnesium. It lowers blood pressure, eases menstrual cramp, and reduces stress.
    </string>

    <!-- Oil -->
    <string name="avocado_oil_details">
       While avocado oil is best known for its uses in cooking, it can also contribute to skin care.
        The oil is an ingredient in many types of creams, moisturizers, and sunscreens. Eight benefits for the skin
        1. Moisturizes and nourishes - In addition to vitamin E, avocado oil contains potassium, lecithin, and many other nutrients that can nourish and moisturize the skin.
        The outermost layer of skin, known as the epidermis, easily absorbs these nutrients, which also help to form new skin.
        2. Relieves inflammation from psoriasis and eczema - The antioxidants and vitamins in avocado oil may help to heal the dry, irritated, and flaky skin associated with eczema and psoriasis.
        A person with a skin condition may wish to test a patch of skin first, to ensure that the oil does not trigger or aggravate their symptoms.
        3. Prevents and treats acne - When left on for short periods of time and rinsed off with warm water, avocado oil can keep skin hydrated without leaving an oily residue. This may reduce the risk of acne.
        Avocado oil also has anti-inflammatory effects, which can help to reduce the redness and inflammation associated with acne.
        4. Accelerates wound healing - Avocado oil may help wounds to heal more quickly. One 2013 study found that the essential fatty acids and oleic acid in avocado oil can promote collagen synthesis, which is the process of creating new connective tissue.
        The essential fatty acids in avocado oil were also found to help reduce inflammation during the healing process.
        More studies are needed in humans, however, to determine whether avocado oil can be used to treat wounds.
        5. Treats sunburned skin - The antioxidants in avocado oil may help to ease the symptoms of a sunburn. According to a 2011 review, the vitamin E, beta carotene, vitamin D, protein, lecithin, and essential fatty acids in the oil can support healing and soothe the skin.
        Other small studies have shown that consuming avocados may help to protect the skin from harmful UV radiation.
        6. Reduces signs of aging - The first signs of aging usually appear on the skin. Some studies have shown that consuming healthful fats, such as those found in avocados, can help the skin to retain its elasticity.
        However, researchers have yet to address whether applying avocado oil to the skin has the same effect.
        7. Improves nail health - While some people use avocado oil to heal dry, brittle nails, little scientific evidence confirms this benefit.
        However, using natural oils to keep the nails and surrounding skin soft may help to reduce breakage.
        8. Improves scalp health - Applying avocado oil to the scalp as a hot oil mask can help to reduce dandruff and other problems caused by a dry, flaky scalp.
        How to use - Avocado oil can be massaged into the skin, used in a face mask, or added to lotions, creams, shower gels, or bath oils. It can be used on skin daily without adverse effects.
        As a facial moisturizer - To use avocado as a facial moisturizer, a person can take the inside of an avocado peel and massage it onto their face. Leave the residue on for about 15 minutes, then rinse the face with warm water.
        Bottled avocado oil can also be used to moisture the face at night. Wash it off the following morning.
        In the bath - Adding a few tablespoons of avocado oil to a bath can leave the whole body feeling soft and help to prevent hot water from drying out the skin.
        It can also be mixed with a persons favorite bath oil, such as lavender or aloe vera.
        As a moisturizer - Combine avocado oil with other essential oils and massage the mixture into the skin after a bath. Pat the skin dry with a towel before using the oil.
        Avocado oil is also effective on its own and can be applied all over the body to keep skin soft.
        For scalp care - A person with a dry scalp may benefit from using avocado oil in a hot oil treatment. To heat the oil, pour 3–5 tablespoons into a small glass jar, and place the jar in a saucepan of recently boiled water.
        Test the temperature of the oil frequently, to prevent it from getting too hot. When the oil is warm, remove the jar from the water and gently massage the oil into the scalp.
        The oil can be left overnight and shampooed out in the morning. This may help to reduce dandruff and dry, flaky skin on the scalp.
        Treating dry, inflamed skin - To heal and soften rough, dry skin, mix equal amounts of avocado and olive oils, and apply the mixture to the skin once or twice a day.
        To give the mixture a scent, try one or two drops of an essential oil, such as lavender.
        Other health benefits of avocado oil - Research suggests that avocado oil can help to prevent several health issues, including diabetes and high cholesterol. A study from 2014 found avocado oil to have as many healthful benefits as olive oil.
        A 2017 study concluded that avocado oil could reduce the oxidative damage that causes kidney damage in people with type 2 diabetes. The result stems from oleic acid, a healthy fat, which is the primary component of the oil. More research is needed in humans, however, before this claim can be fully supported.
        In addition to fighting kidney damage, oleic acid is known for its ability to lower the risk of developing some cancers, preventing flare-ups of some autoimmune diseases, speeding up cell regeneration to promote healing, aiding in eliminating microbial infections, and reducing inflammation throughout the body.
        Another study reported that oleic acid may help to reduce inflammation and pain associated with arthritis.
        Risks - Side effects of avocado oil are rare, but it is possible to be allergic or avocados or their oil.
        The best way to rule out an allergy is to do a patch test. Apply a small amount of avocado oil to a 1-inch patch of skin on the inside of the arm. If no irritation occurs over a 24-hour period, the oil can be safely used on other parts of the skin.
        Anyone allergic to avocados should avoid contact with avocado oil.
    </string>
    <string name="coconut_oil_details">
        Coconut oil has a saturated fat content of 90 percent. Oils high in saturated fats have been found to increase the risk of cardiovascular and other diseases.
        However, coconut oil has grown in popularity in recent years, amid claims that it can do everything from supporting weight loss to slowing the progression of Alzheimers disease.
        Benefits - oconut oil contains 2.6 percent fewer calories than other fats. It has been said to provide various health benefits. Here are a few of them -
        Increasing good cholesterol - A component in coconut oil has been found to give good HDL cholesterol a nudge.
        Controlling blood sugar - It appears to preserve insulin action and insulin resistance in mice.
        Reducing stress - It has antistress and antioxidant properties, which could make it useful as an antidepressant, according to research in rodents.
        Shiny hair - It makes hair shinier, because it penetrates better than mineral oils.
        Healthy skin - It has been found to enhance protective barrier functions and have an anti-inflammatory effect on skin in humans.
        Preventing liver disease - It has reversed hepatosteatosis, a type of fatty liver disease, in rodents.
        Reducing asthma symptoms - Inhaling coconut oil has helped reduce asthma symptoms in rabbits.
        Fighting candida - Coconut oil has reduced colonization with Candida albicans in mice, suggesting it could be a treatment for candida.
        Improving satiety - One argument has been that coconut oil leaves people feeling fuller after eating, so they will not eat so much. However, other research has shown that this is not the case.
        Weight loss - It has reduced obesity and promoted weight loss in mice.
        Cautions -While a number of investigations have looked into coconut oil and its possible benefits, it should be noted that many of the studies supporting its benefits have not yet been carried out on humans.
        In addition, all high-fat foods and oils are high in calories. Adding in more calorie-dense food to a diet that already has plenty of calories will not result in weight loss.
        Types - Not all coconut oils are the same, and some are more healthful than others.
        Partially hydrogenated coconut oil - is just as harmful as other highly processed oils that contain trans fats. These are not healthful.
        Refined coconut oil - is extracted from chemically bleached and deodorized coconut meat.
        Virgin coconut oil - is extracted from the fruit of fresh, mature coconuts without using high temperatures or chemicals. It is considered unrefined, and it may offer health benefits.
    </string>
    <string name="grapeseed_oil_details">
        Grapeseed oil is a byproduct of winemaking. After wine is made by pressing grapes, grape seeds are left behind. Grapeseed oil is extracted from these leftover grape seeds. Grapeseed oil is used as a natural beauty product. Its also marketed as a healthy alternative to vegetable oil.
        Fast facts on grapeseed oil - Grapeseed oil is high in omega-6 fatty acids.
        The oil can be used in hair and on the skin as part of your beauty regimen.
        Buy expeller-pressed or cold-pressed oil for use in the kitchen.
        Safety - The health benefits of grapeseed oil are controversial. Part of this controversy is because of how the oil is processed. Most commercially available grapeseed oil is made using chemical solvents like hexane. Hexane is classified as an air pollutant and neurotoxin.
        Its unclear what effect consuming these solvents has on humans in trace amounts. During processing, grapeseed oil may also be heated to very high temperatures which may oxidize the oil and make it go bad.
        Grapeseed oil thats cold-pressed or expeller-pressed does not use chemical solvents or high heat during processing. Its a better choice than oil made with solvents.
        Health benefits of grapeseed oil - Grapeseed oil is high in polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs), mostly omega-6 fatty acids. According to the American Heart Association, PUFAs may be beneficial to your heart if they are used in place of saturated fats and trans fats in your diet.
        Research shows that PUFAS may reduce cholesterol and your risk of heart disease. But theres a catch: Optimal health depends on the proper balance of omega-6 fatty acids and omega-3 fatty acids in your body. Most people get more than enough omega-6 fatty acids in their diet and not nearly enough omega-3s.
        Studies show that too much omega-6 fatty acid may cause inflammation that may lead to chronic diseases, including cancer. If you are already getting enough omega-6 in your diet, regularly consuming grapeseed oil may put your omega-6 intake at unhealthy levels.
        Vitamin E - Grapeseed oil is a good source of vitamin E, even more so than olive oil. Vitamin E is a vitamin that works as a fat-soluble antioxidant, which helps protect your cells from damaging free radicals that have been associated with cancer, heart disease, and other chronic illnesses. Vitamin E also supports your immune system. Research shows it may slow the progression of dementia, but more study is needed.
        Vitamin E can withstand heat, and grapeseed oil has a high smoke point. But any cooking oil will deteriorate fast if overheated. Whenever possible, use cold-pressed or expeller-pressed grapeseed oil raw in your recipes.
        Beauty benefits of grapeseed oil - Beauty companies use grapeseed oil in their skin care and hair care products. But there are no clinical studies on the effectiveness of grapeseed oil on the skin or hair. Even so, many people use grapeseed oil as a natural remedy in their at-home beauty arsenal.
        Grapeseed oil for healthy skin - Many of grapeseed oils beauty benefits may be due to its vitamin E and omega-6 fatty acid content. Free radicals and environmental factors such as sun, wind, and pollution can do a number on your skin. They may increase the signs of aging and cause dry skin and discoloration.
        Vitamin E helps battles free radicals, so it may help improve your skin when consumed in your diet. The same benefits may apply when its applied directly to your skin in the form of grapeseed oil.
        According to the Linus Pauling Institute, omega-6 and omega-3 fatty acids are crucial to skin function and appearance. And omega-6 fatty acids are necessary for skin barrier functioning. The main omega-6 PUFA in grapeseed oil is linolenic acid. This fatty acid may help reduce inflammation in the skins middle and outer layers.
        Other reasons grapeseed oil is used are to - moisturize skin, heal acne, lighten skin, tighten pores, reduce the appearance of scars, remove makeup.
        Grapeseed oil penetrates your skin quickly and does not leave your skin feeling oily. To use grapeseed oil on your face, massage several drops into clean skin before you go to bed at night. You can repeat the process in the morning, if desired. Since grapeseed oil does not clog pores, its ideal for all skin types, including oily skin that needs moisturizing.
        Grapeseed oil for healthy hair - Grapeseed oil may improve the condition of your hair and scalp. If you have dandruff, which is often caused by a dry scalp, applying emollient grapeseed oil to your scalp can help loosen dead skin and restore moisture.
        Some natural oils including olive oil and coconut oil are good for your hair, but they leave it feeling greasy and weighed down. Grapeseed oil is lightweight and does not have that effect. When applied to your hair, grapeseed oil adds moisture, strength, and shine.
        Try massaging a couple of tablespoons of grapeseed oil (using more or less, depending on the length of your hair) into your hair and scalp before shampooing.
        Grapeseed oil is used as a natural remedy for baldness. Linolenic acid is thought to stimulate hair growth. The oil contains flavonoids called procyanidin oligomers. These are powerful antioxidants. In vitro and in vivo studies show procyanidin oligomers may induce hair growth, but more research is needed.
    </string>
    <string name="olive_oil_details">
        Olive oil, rich in monounsaturated fatty acids, is a major component of the Mediterranean diet. Populations from that region have longer life expectancies and lower risks of heart disease, high blood pressure and stroke, compared with North Americans and Northern Europeans.
        Monounsaturated fatty acids (MUFAs) are considered a healthy dietary fat, as opposed to saturated fats and trans fats.
        Olive oil is a fat obtained from the fruit of the Olea europaea (olive tree), a traditional tree crop of the Mediterranean region. Whole olives are pressed to produce this distinctive oil.
        The oil is used in cosmetics, medicine, cooking, and soaps, and was also used as a fuel for traditional lamps. Olive oil originally came from the Mediterranean, but today it is used worldwide.
        In the diet, olives can be eaten whole or chopped and added to pizzas and other dishes.
        The oil can be used as a dip for bread, for frying, or as a salad dressing. Some people even consume it by the small glassful for medicinal purposes.
        Benefits - Olive oil and the cardiovascular system - Olive oil is the main source of dietary fat in the Mediterranean diet. There appears to be a lower death rate from cardiovascular diseases in the Mediterranean area, compared with other parts of the world.
        A review of studies carried out in Barcelona, Spain, looked at the biological and clinical effects of olive oil.
        Results suggested that people who regularly consume olive oil are less likely to develop cardiovascular diseases, including hypertension (high blood pressure), stroke, and hyperlipidemia (high blood cholesterol and triglyceride levels).
        Olive oil intake also appears to help reduce inflammation, endothelial dysfunction (problems with the inner linings of blood vessels), thrombosis, and carbohydrate metabolism.
        Frying with olive oil and heart disease risk - People who regularly eat foods fried in olive oil or sunflower oil do not have a higher risk of heart disease or premature death, researchers from Madrid, in Spain, reported in the BMJ.
        Frying in extra virgin olive oil may enable food to retain more of their nutrients than boiling, according to research published by the University of Granada in 2016. The scientists say that phenols from the olive oil transfer to foods, making them more healthful.
        In 2017, another study found that olive oil is more stable and less likely to change the nutritional value of food that is fried in it, compared with sunflower oil.
        Olive oil may help prevent stroke - Scientists in France concluded that olive oil may prevent stroke in older people.
        The team found that older people who regularly used olive oil for cooking and salad dressing or with bread had a 41-percent lower risk of stroke, compared with those who never consumed it.
        The researchers suggested that olive oil might be a cheap and easy way to prevent stroke, a common problem in older people.
        Depression risk and olive oil - People whose diets are high in trans fats may have a higher risk of depression, compared with those whose diets are rich in mono-unsaturared and polyunsaturated fats. Trans fats are widely used in fast foods and mass-produced items, such as pastries.
        According to a study carried out at the University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria in Spain and published in PLoS ONE, olive oil appears to protect slightly against the risk of depression, even after taking into account peoples overall diet, physical activity, and lifestyle.
        Data on 12,000 volunteers over a period of 6 years showed that, compared with people whose dietary fat was mainly olive oil, those who consumed trans-fats regularly had a 48-percent higher risk of developing depression.
        The more trans-fats they ate, the higher the risk.
        Olive oil may reduce breast cancer risk - Scientists from Barcelona in Spain found a key mechanism by which virgin olive oil protects the body against breast cancer, in contrast to other vegetable oils.
        After decoding signals in the cells of breast tumors that are activated by virgin olive oil, they concluded that the oil reduces the activity of p21Ras, an oncogene. This oncogene prevents DNA damage, encourages tumor cell death, and triggers changes in protein signaling pathways.
        The activity of corn oil, meanwhile, an oil rich in n-6 polyunsaturated fatty acids, appears to increase the aggressiveness of tumors.
        The team demonstrated a link between virgin olive oil and a higher incidence of benign, or non-cancerous, breast tumors.
        Olive oil helps maintain healthy cholesterol levels - A Japanese study published in the Medical Science Monitor showed that LDL-cholesterol concentrations fell in 28 outpatients who took olive oil supplements once a day for 6 weeks.
        Low-density lipoprotein (LDL) is often referred to as bad cholesterol. The good cholesterol is high-density lipoprotein (HDL).
        The authors concluded, These results point to an overwhelmingly beneficial influence of olive oil on the lipoprotein spectrum.
        Extra virgin olive oil and Alzheimers disease - Oleocanthal is a type of natural phenolic compound found in extra-virgin olive oil.
        In laboratory experiments with mice, researchers noted that oleocanthal helped shuttle the abnormal Alzheimers disease proteins out of the brain.
        The team looked at whether oleocanthal might help prevent beta-amyloid from accumulating. Beta amyloid is believed to be a key factor in Alzheimers disease (AD).
        Findings suggested that oleocanthal boosts the production of two proteins and key enzymes that help removal beta-amyloid from the brain.
        Rates of Alzheimers disease are lower in Mediterranean countries, where consumption of olive oil is higher than anywhere else in the world.
        Researchers in Spain have suggested that following a Mediterranean diet supplemented with additional portions of antioxidant-rich extra virgin olive oil or mixed nuts could help protect cognitive functioning in older adults.
        Extra virgin olive oil and acute pancreatitis - Extra virgin olive oil is rich in oleic acid and hydroxytyrosol, which affect the development of acute pancreatitis, or sudden inflammation of the pancreas.
        In a laboratory experiment at the University of Granada in Spain, researchers found that the components of extra virgin olive oil appear to protect against acute pancreatitis.
        Olive oil and the liver - Investigators from Tunisia and Saudi Arabia carried out a study demonstrating that extra virgin olive oil may protect the liver from oxidative stress.
        Oxidative stress refers to cell damage associated with the chemical reaction between free radicals and other molecules in the body.
        After giving laboratory rats a moderately toxic herbicide, they were then fed on a diet containing olive oil. It appeared to protect them partially from liver damage.
        Olive oil may help protect from ulcerative colitis - Ulcerative colitis causes inflammation of the large intestine, or colon. It is a type of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) that is similar to Crohns disease.
        Scientists at the United Kingdome say that consuming more olive oil could help fend off ulcerative colitis.
        They looked at data for over 25,000 people, aged from 40 to 65 years and living in the U.K. None of them had ulcerative colitis at the start of the study.
        The findings showed that the participants with the highest intake of oleic acid, a component of olive oil, had a 90-percent lower risk of developing ulcerative colitis compared to those with the lowest intake.
        The researchers suggested that consuming two-to-three tablespoons of olive oil each day could have a protective effect.
    </string>
    <string name="hemp_oil_details">
        Hemp oil can refer to a full-spectrum oil from the Cannabis sativa plant or hemp seed oil, which is oil that comes from just the seeds of the hemp plant.
        There is very little risk of intoxication from hemp oil as all forms of hemp oil come from food-grain strains of hemp. The authors of a study in the journal Cannabis and Cannabinoid Research note that food-grain strains of hemp must contain less than 0.3 percent tetrahydrocannabinol (THC). THC is the compound that causes the so-called high of marijuana.
        powered by Rubicon Project. Hemp oil is not the same as cannabidiol (CBD) oil. The production of CBD oil uses the stalks, leaves, and flowers of the hemp plant, which contain a higher concentration of CBD, another potentially beneficial compound in the plant.
        Hemp seed oil comes from the small seeds of the Cannabis sativa plant. The seeds do not contain the same levels of compounds as the plant itself, but they still have a rich profile of nutrients, fatty acids, and useful bioactive compounds.
        Full-spectrum hemp oil that also contains plant matter may add other effective compounds, which may help with certain health issues, such as inflammation.
        Skin health - The oil from the hemp seed is highly nutritious and may be especially helpful for the skin. The vitamins and fatty acids in this oil may help keep the skin healthy and prevent breakouts.
        A 2014 study looking at the lipid profile of hemp seed oil found that it is rich in healthful oils and fatty acids. The abundance of fatty acids may make the oil an excellent choice for nourishing the skin and protecting it from inflammation, oxidation, and other causes of aging.
        The authors of a 2014 review note that the topical application of hemp seed oil strengthens the skin and makes it better able to resist infection. The authors also suggest that hemp seed oil may be a helpful treatment for a range of skin issues, including -
        eczema, dermatitis, psoriasis, varicose eczema, lichen planus, an inflammatory skin condition, acne rosacea.These benefits are likely to be due to the high quantity of beneficial fats and other helpful compounds in the oil.
        Brain health - The fatty acid content of hemp seed oil may also be good for the brain, which requires plenty of healthful fats to operate properly. Hemp seed oil is also rich in other compounds that may help protect the brain.
        A recent study in mice found that a hemp seed extract containing these active compounds was able to help protect the brain against inflammation. The authors note that hemp seed oil contains polyphenols, which may play a role in protecting the brain.
        Although these initial results look promising, scientists need to carry out studies in humans to confirm the benefits of this oil.
        Heart health - The comprehensive nutrient profile of hemp seed oil means that it may also be good for the heart. However, much of the information that is currently available comes from older studies or research that uses animal models.
        An older study in the journal Nutrition and Metabolism highlights the nutrient profile of hemp seeds and notes that they might have a positive effect on various health issues, such as high blood pressure, atherosclerosis, and cholesterol levels.
        A 2014 review concludes that an increase in alpha-linolenic acid, one of the fatty acids in hemp oil, appears to reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease. This fatty acid, which doctors call linolenic acid, is also present in fish oils and flaxseed oil. However, the researchers call for more clinical trials to confirm these results.
        Full-spectrum hemp oil benefits - Full-spectrum hemp oil also includes plant matter, which adds additional compounds, such as CBD. Although hemp seeds contain small amounts of these compounds, a higher concentration may bring some additional benefits to the body.
        Natural pain relief - Many people use hemp or CBD oil as a form of natural pain relief, especially if the pain is a result of inflammation. Those who do not want to take over-the-counter or prescription pain medications may turn to a high-quality hemp oil for relief.
        A 2018 review notes that CBD, one of the main compounds in full-spectrum hemp oil, and other cannabinoids show promise for the treatment of many types of pain.
        However, most of the research to date is on mice. While the current research suggests that CBD may be a helpful natural treatment for pain, more human studies could give these results more credibility.
        Acne - The fatty acids in hemp seed oil may help balance the skin and prevent inflammation that can result in acne. The addition of CBD from the plant matter may also help clear acne.
        A study in the Journal of Clinical Investigation found that CBD may affect the sebum glands in people with chronic acne, leading to reduced sebum production and potentially helping clear or prevent acne breakouts.
        Muscle tension - Full-spectrum hemp oil that contains CBD may also help with general stress and tension in the muscles. Like fatty acids, CBD has an anti-inflammatory effect on the body, which may help relieve the tension that many people carry from stress and promote recovery from exercise.
        Rubbing a bit of hemp seed oil or full-spectrum hemp oil into tight muscles may help release tension and relax them.
    </string>

    <!-- Nuts and Seeds-->
    <string name="hemp_seeds_details">
        Although hemp seeds come from the Cannabis sativa plant, they do not produce a mind-altering effect.
        These small, brown seeds are rich in protein, fiber, and healthful fatty acids, including omega-3s and omega-6s.
        They have antioxidant effects and may reduce symptoms of numerous ailments, improving the health of the heart, skin, and joints.
        In this article, we look at the various benefits of hemp seeds and provide tips for adding them to the diet.
        Nutritional benefits of hemp seeds -
        1. Protein - Hemp seeds contain almost as much protein as soybeans.
        In every 30 grams (g) of seeds, or about a tablespoon, there are 9.46 g of protein.
        These seeds are a complete source of protein, meaning that they provide all nine essential amino acids.
        Amino acids are the building blocks for all proteins. The body cannot produce nine of these acids, so a person must absorb them through the diet.
        Relatively few plant-based foods are complete sources of protein, making hemp seeds a valuable addition to a vegetarian or vegan diet.
        Hemp seeds are especially rich in an amino acid called arginine, which has benefits for heart health.
        2. Unsaturated fats - The health benefits of polyunsaturated fats, especially omega-3 fatty acids, are becoming increasingly well known.
        Hemp seeds are a great source of essential fatty acids, such as alpha-linolenic acid (ALA), which is an omega-3.
        The body cannot produce essential fatty acids, and the body must absorb them from the diet. They are crucial for long-term health.
        The ratio of omega-3s to omega-6s is also important.
        In general, people tend to eat too many omega-6s and too few omega-3s, but adding hemp seeds to the diet may help to promote a balance.
        According to results of a 2015 animal study, incorporating hemp seeds and hemp seed oil to hens
        diet led to eggs with increased levels of omega-3s in the yolks and a more healthful omega-3 to omega-6 ratio.
        Also, hemp seeds are low in saturated fats and contain no trans fats.
        3. Fiber - Much of the fiber in a hemp seed lies in its outer hull, or shell. If possible, purchase hemp seeds with the hulls intact.
        However, even without the shells, hemp seeds are a god source pf fiber, with three tablespoons containing approximately 1.2 g of fiber.
        Consuming enough fiber every day can - reduce the appetite, help with weight management, work to stabilize blood sugar levels, promote the health of the gut.
        4. Minerals and vitamins - Hemp seeds contain an impressive array of vitamins and minerals and are especially rich in, vitamin E, magnesium, phosphorous,
        potassium. They are also a good source of iron, zinc, and B vitamins, including - niacin, riboflavin, thiamine, vitamin B-6, folate.
        Health benefits of hemp seeds - 5. Protect the brain - A study published in the journal Food Chemistry found that hemp seed extract
        has antioxidant effects in lab tests. These effects may result from the seeds cannabidiol (CBD) content.
        Results of a review from 2018 suggest that CBD and other compounds in the seeds may have neuroprotective,
        anti-inflammatory, effects and may also help to regulate the immune system.
        The review suggests that, because of these potential properties, CBD may help with neurological conditions, including - Parkinsons disease,
        Alzheimers disease, multiple sclerosis, neuropathic pain, childhood seizure disorders.
        6. Boost heart health - The medical community believes that omega-3 fatty acids improve the health of the heart and reduce the
        risk of issues such as arrhythmias and heart disease. Hemp seeds contain high levels of omega-3s and a healthful ratio
        of omega-3 to omega-6 fatty acids. The seeds also contain high levels of arginine, an amino acid that turns into nitric oxide.
        Nitric oxide is essential for artery and vein dilation, and it helps keep blood vessel walls smooth and elastic.
        Lowering blood pressure, eating a healthful diet, and participating in varied forms of exercise may help to decrease the risk of heart failure.
        7. Reduce inflammation - The amount of omega-3s in hemp seeds and the seeds healthful omega-3 to omega-6 ratio can together
        help to reduce inflammation.
        In addition, hemp seeds are a rich source of gamma linolenic acid (GLA), a polyunsaturated fatty acid which may also have anti-inflammatory effects.
        Some studies on animals suggest that GLA can act as a potent anti-inflammatory.
        However, recent studies in humans suggest that the acid is not always effective.
        A review in The European Journal of Pharmacology states that humans process GLA in a very complicated way,
        which may explain why the studies in humans produce more varied results than those on animals.
        When looking at these studies, it is important to note that researchers usually use high concentrations
        of hemp seed extracts and that eating the seeds may produce less dramatic effects.
        Reducing inflammation may help manage the symptoms of chronic diseases, such as - metabolic syndrome, type 2 diabetes, arthritis, heart disease,
        non-alcohol-related fatty liver disease.
        8. Improve skin conditions - Atopic dermatitis (AD) and acne can both result from chronic inflammation.
        The anti-inflammatory compounds in hemp seeds may help.
        Among other possible dietary causes, acne may be linked to a deficiency in omega-3s.
        The high omega-3 content in hemp seeds may help to manage and reduce acne symptoms.
        A 2018 review explored the effects of dietary changes on skin diseases.
        While the authors found evidence that eating more omega-3s may improve symptoms of acne,
        determining the extent of the effects will require more research.
        The authors also note that prebiotics and plant fibers may help to manage symptoms of AD. Hemp seeds are a rich source of plant fiber.
        9. Relieve rheumatoid arthritis - Rheumatoid arthritis is an autoimmune condition.
        It causes the immune system to attack its own tissues, which leads to inflammation in the joints.
        In 2014, research conducted in human cells suggested that hemp seed oil could have anti-rheumatic effects.
        However, a 2018 review found a lack of conclusive evidence to suggest that cannabinoids could effectively treat rheumatic diseases.
        The authors noted that more research is needed.
    </string>
    <string name="sesame_seeds_details">
        Sesame seeds are tiny, oil-rich seeds that grow in pods on the Sesamum indicum plant.
        Unhulled seeds have the outer, edible husk intact, while hulled seeds come without the husk.
        The hull gives the seeds a golden-brown hue. Hulled seeds have an off-white color but turn brown when roasted.
        Sesame seeds have many potential health benefits and have been used in folk medicine for thousands of years.
        They may protect against heart disease, diabetes, and arthritis.
        However, you may need to eat significant amounts — a small handful per day — to gain health benefits.
        Here are 15 health benefits of sesame seeds - 1. Good Source of Fiber -
        Three tablespoons (30 grams) of unhulled sesame seeds provide 3.5 grams of fiber, which is 12 percent of the Reference Daily Intake (RDI).
        Since the average fiber intake in the United States is only half of the RDI, eating sesame seeds regularly could help increase your fiber intake.
        Fiber is well known for supporting digestive health.
        Additionally, growing evidence suggests that fiber may play a role in reducing your risk of heart disease, certain cancers,
        obesity, and type 2 diabetes.
        2. May Lower Cholesterol and Triglycerides - Some studies suggest that regularly eating sesame seeds may help decrease high cholesterol
        and triglycerides, which are risk factors for heart disease.
        Sesame seeds consist of 15 percent saturated fat, 41 percent polyunsaturated fat, and 39 percent monounsaturated fat.
        Research indicates that eating more polyunsaturated and monounsaturated fat relative to saturated fat may help lower your cholesterol
        and reduce heart disease risk.
        Whats more, sesame seeds contain two types of plant compounds, lignans and phytosterols, that may also have cholesterol-lowering effects.
        When 38 people with high blood lipids ate 5 tablespoons (40 grams) of hulled sesame seeds daily for 2 months,
        they experienced a 10 percent reduction in bad LDL cholesterol and an 8 percent reduction in triglycerides compared to the placebo group.
        3. Nutritious Source of Plant Protein - Sesame seeds supply 5 grams of protein per 3-tablespoon (30-gram) serving.
        To maximize protein availability, opt for hulled, roasted sesame seeds.
        The hulling and roasting processes reduce oxalates and phytates compounds that hamper your digestion and absorption of protein.
        Protein is essential for your health, as it helps build everything from muscles to hormones.
        Notably, sesame seeds are low in lysine, an essential amino acid more abundant in animal products.
        However, vegans and vegetarians can compensate by consuming high-lysine plant proteins particularly legumes, such as kidney beans and chickpeas.
        On the other hand, sesame seeds are high in methionine and cysteine, two amino acids that legumes do not provide in large amounts.
        4. May Help Lower Blood Pressure - High blood pressure is a major risk factor for heart disease and stroke.
        Sesame seeds are high in magnesium, which may help lower blood pressure.
        Additionally, lignans, vitamin E, and other antioxidants in sesame seeds may help prevent plaque buildup in your arteries,
        potentially maintaining healthy blood pressure.
        In one study, people with high blood pressure consumed 2.5 grams of powdered, black sesame seeds, a less common variety, in capsule form every day.
        At the end of one month, they experienced a 6 percent decrease in systolic blood pressure,
        the top number of a blood pressure reading, compared to the placebo group.
        5. May Support Healthy Bones - Sesame seeds both unhulled and hulled are rich in several nutrients that boost bone health,
        though the calcium is mainly in the hull. However, sesame seeds contain natural compounds called oxalates and phytates,
        antinutrients that reduce the absorption of these minerals. To limit these compounds impact, try soaking, roasting, or sprouting the seeds.
        One study found that sprouting reduced phytate and oxalate concentration by about 50 percent in both hulled and unhulled sesame seeds.
        6. May Reduce Inflammation - Sesame seeds may fight inflammation. Long-term, low-level inflammation may play a role in many chronic conditions,
        including obesity and cancer, as well as heart and kidney disease. When people with kidney disease ate a mixture of 18 grams
        of flax seeds and 6 grams each of sesame and pumpkin seeds daily for 3 months, their inflammatory markers dropped 51‒79 percent.
        However, because this study tested a mixture of seeds, the anti-inflammatory impact of sesame seeds alone is uncertain.
        Still, animal studies of sesame seed oil also suggest anti-inflammatory effects.
        This may be due to sesamin, a compound found in sesame seeds and their oil.
        7. Good Source of B Vitamins - Sesame seeds are a good source of certain B vitamins, which are distributed both in the hull and seed.
        Removing the hull may either concentrate or remove some of the B vitamins. B vitamins are essential for many bodily processes,
        including proper cell function and metabolism.
        8. May Aid Blood Cell Formation - To make red blood cells, your body needs several nutrients including ones found in sesame seeds.
        Soaked, roasted, or sprouted sesame seeds may increase absorption of these minerals.
        9. May Aid Blood Sugar Control - Sesame seeds are low in carbs while high in protein and healthy fats all of which may support blood sugar control.
        Additionally, these seeds contain pinoresinol a compound that may help regulate blood sugar by inhibiting the action of the digestive enzyme maltase.
        Maltase breaks down the sugar maltose, which is used as a sweetener for some food products.
        Its also produced in your gut from the digestion of starchy foods like bread and pasta.
        If pinoresinol inhibits your digestion of maltose, this may result in lower blood sugar levels. However, human studies are needed.
        10. Rich in Antioxidants - Animal and human studies suggest that consuming sesame seeds may increase
        the overall amount of antioxidant activity in your blood. The lignans in sesame seeds function as antioxidants,
        which help fight oxidative stress a chemical reaction that may damage your cells and increase your risk of many chronic diseases.
        Additionally, sesame seeds contain a form of vitamin E called gamma-tocopherol,
        an antioxidant that may be especially protective against heart disease.
        11. May Support Your Immune System - Sesame seeds are a good source of several nutrients crucial for your immune system,
        including zinc, selenium, copper, iron, vitamin B6, and vitamin E.
        For example, your body needs zinc to develop and activate certain white blood cells that recognize and attack invading microbes.
        Keep in mind that even mild to moderate zinc deficiency can impair immune system activity.
        Sesame seeds supply about 20 percent of the RDI for zinc in a 3-tablespoon (30-gram) serving.
        12. May Soothe Arthritic Knee Pain - Osteoarthritis is the most common cause of joint pain and frequently affects the knees.
        Several factors may play a role in arthritis, including inflammation and oxidative damage to the cartilage that cushions joints.
        Sesamin, a compound in sesame seeds, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects that may protect your cartilage.
        In a 2-month study, people with knee arthritis ate 5 tablespoons (40 grams) of sesame seed powder daily alongside drug therapy.
        They experienced a 63 percent decrease in knee pain compared to only a 22 percent decrease for the group on drug therapy alone.
        Additionally, the sesame seed group showed greater improvement in a simple mobility test and larger reductions
        in certain inflammatory markers compared to the control group.
        13. May Support Thyroid Health - Sesame seeds are a good source of selenium, supplying 18 percent of the RDI in both unhulled and hulled seeds.
        Your thyroid gland contains the highest concentration of selenium of any organ in your body.
        This mineral plays a vital role in making thyroid hormones. In addition, sesame seeds are a good source of iron, copper, zinc, and vitamin B6,
        which also support the production of thyroid hormones and aid thyroid health.
        14. May Aid Hormone Balance During Menopause - Sesame seeds contain phytoestrogens, plant compounds that are similar to the hormone estrogen.
        Therefore, sesame seeds might be beneficial for women when estrogen levels drop during menopause.
        For example, phytoestrogens may help counteract hot flashes and other symptoms of low estrogen.
        Whats more, these compounds may decrease your risk of certain diseases, such as breast cancer, during menopause.
        15. Easy to Add to Your Diet - Sesame seeds can give a nutty flavor and subtle crunch to many dishes.
        To enhance the flavor and nutrient availability of sesame seeds, roast them at 350℉ (180℃) for a few minutes,
        stirring periodically, until they reach a light, golden brown.

    </string>
    <string name="brazil_nuts_details">
        Brazil nuts (scientifically known as Bertholletia excelsa), are a nutrient-dense and delicious type of nuts that come from a tree
        in South America bearing the same name. The tree is native to South American countries – including Venezuela, Colombia, Peru, and Brazil – and
        can often be found along the banks of major rivers.
        These nuts are majorly exported from the South American continent and can now be found throughout the world.
        Brazil nuts are one of the healthiest nuts available, particularly due to their unusually high selenium content.
        According to the USDA National Nutrient Database, the nuts are a rich source of energy and protein and have an impressive mineral and vitamin profile.
        According to studies published in the journal Nutrients, Brazil nuts are rich in antioxidants and have high levels of monounsaturated fatty acids (MUFAs).
        The nuts are naturally gluten-free nuts and an excellent source of dietary fiber, too.
        Health Benefits of Brazil Nuts - 1. Top Source of Selenium - Brazil nuts are the number one source of selenium,
        with one ounce (about 6 kernels) serving 774 percent of the daily value. Selenium is a trace mineral which is extremely vital for the body,
        as it has strong antioxidant powers, fights free radicals and soothing inflammation.
        2. Improve Heart Health - As per a study conducted in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition consumption of nuts helps
        in lowering bad cholesterol by more than 25 percent due to their nutrient profiles.
        However, further research is needed to determine exactly why Brazil nuts have such a beneficial effect on heart health.
        Brazil nuts have a surprisingly high content of healthy unsaturated fats, commonly known as omega-3 fatty acids.
        This includes oleic acid and palmitoleic acid. These varieties of unsaturated fats, magnesium, vitamin E, and selenium content in Brazil nuts are,
        thus, connected with balancing the cholesterol profile of the body and improving heart health.
        3. Anti-inflammatory Properties - The high ellagic acid and selenium levels in the nuts make it a top anti-inflammatory food source.
        Ellagic acid also has potent neuroprotective properties. Furthermore, zinc in Brazil nuts reduces inflammations and helps flush out toxins.
        4. Boost Testosterone Levels - Brazil nuts, with their high selenium content, are often called a testosterone superfood.
        Dietary selenium can help to improve sperm quality, motility, and volume, according to a research study published in the Journal of Urology.
        This, in turn, is linked with testosterone levels in men as higher the testosterone, higher the sperm count.
        L-arginine in the nuts is also an effective treatment for erectile dysfunction.
        5. Antioxidant Properties - The abundant antioxidants in Brazil nuts may contribute to preventing many chronic illnesses.
        This is confirmed in a study conducted at the Department of Surgical Oncology at Roswell Park Cancer Institute in Buffalo, New York.
        The glutathione enabled by the presence of selenium is an enzymatic antioxidant that eliminates free radicals in all parts of the body.
        6. Mood Lifter - Low levels of selenium have been linked to anxiety, stress, and tiredness,according to recent research cited in
        Biological Psychiatry. Nut consumption increases the metabolism of serotonin,a feel-good brain chemical, which controls mood, appetite, and sleep.
        Thus, regular intake of selenium-rich Brazil nuts rich in selenium can help relieve the various issues caused by selenium deficiency.
        7. Regulate Thyroid Gland - The selenium content in Brazil nuts plays a major role in the proper functioning of your thyroid gland.
        The thyroid gland is the location from which some of the essential hormones in the body are produced, distributed, and regulated.
        8. Skin Care - The comprehensive profile of vitamins and nutrients in Brazil nuts makes it particularly good for improving skin health.
        The selenium, omega 3-fatty acids, and vitamins C and E in Brazil nuts give the skin a healthy glow and improve the skins elasticity,
        thereby reducing the signs of aging. Selenium stimulates the activity of glutathione,
        a powerful antioxidant compound that can remove free radicals from the skin cells that cause wrinkles.
        Also, Brazil nut oil is an excellent emollient, helping prevent skin dryness, eczema, and psoriasis.
        Additionally, grinding a handful of nuts and mixing this with an egg makes for a deeply nourishing skin exfoliator.
        Protects from UV Radiation - Copper in Brazil nuts aids in the production of melanin,
        a color pigment that protects the skin from harmful ultraviolet rays.
        Treat Acne - The high zinc content in Brazil nuts has been shown to protect against acne or lessen its appearance.
        This can be achieved through normal consumption of the nuts or by application of Brazil nut oil on the affected area.
        The rich vitamin and antioxidant content of the oil is the main cause of this protective quality
        9. High Protein Nut - Many people forget about the importance of protein in their diet,particularly if they are on
        a restricted diet or are a vegetarian. So, a handful of these nuts can be a helpful boost to keep your protein levels up.
        10. Zinc Deficiency - Zinc, in Brazil nuts, helps treat Acrodermatitis enteropathica.
        This is a rare genetic disorder in which the body is unable to absorb sufficient amounts of zinc.
        11. Hair Care - L-arginine, an amino acid in the nuts, is often used to treat alopecia or male baldness as it encourages the growth of lustrous,
        thick hair. Brazil nuts are also rich in omega 3s, vitamin E, and selenium, which help to make the hair shiny, healthy, and less prone to breakage.
        12. Weight Loss - Brazil nuts, which are high in protein and fiber, make for a nutrient-dense snack for weight watchers.
        They keep you feeling full for a longer time.
        13. Stimulate the Digestive System - The fiber content of Brazil nuts makes them great for tuning up your digestive system.
        Fiber facilitates peristaltic motion in the gastrointestinal system, moving food through the digestive system and extracting as many
        nutrients as possible. This can also help you prevent gastric ulcers, constipation, bloating, and cramps.
        Also, you will find an increase in energy levels and an improvement in weight loss by keeping your system clean and functioning smoothly.
        Muscle Function - Brazil nuts are a major source of complete protein, with all the essential amino acids present,
        which helps to improve and strengthen muscles.
        They also contain magnesium, which also aids in the build-up of lactic acid in the muscles, thus preventing soreness.
        Improve Bone Mineral Density - The copper content in the Brazil nut helps to improve bone mineral density and in the formation of bone tissues.
        It also helps in the absorption of iron into the bloodstream.
        14. Boost Immune System - Any food that has such a high concentration of nutrients is helpful for strengthening the immune system.
        The antioxidants and organic compounds present in this nut make it a strong contender for one of the most immune-boosting nuts around,
        as per a study conducted at the Memorial University of Newfoundland in Canada. Vitamin C couples wonderfully with selenium and
        zinc to stimulate the production of white blood cells and antioxidant compounds throughout the body to neutralize free radicals.
        Promote Growth and Repair - The protein content of these nuts is necessary for cellular growth, repair, and wound healing. Vitamin C, in Brazil nuts,
        is also a major component of collagen, another essential part of human growth and repair of blood vessels, tissues, and cells.
        Facilitate Nutrient Uptake - The high magnesium levels found in Brazil nuts help stimulate efficient nutrient uptake in the digestive system,
        which means that we get as many benefits as possible from our food.
        Zinc is also one of the hardest elements our body needs, and Brazil nuts natural high levels and facilitation of nutrient uptake
        helps balance that common deficiency.
        Mental Health - Brazil nuts, rich in thiamin (vitamin B1), help keep the nervous system healthy and strong.
        They are also thought to help relieve stress-related disorders.

    </string>
    <string name="walnuts_details">
        Walnuts are round, single-seeded stone fruits that grow from the walnut tree. They are a good source of healthful fats, protein, and fiber.
        They may enhance heart and bone health and help in weight management, among other benefits.
        Walnuts are also a good source of manganese, copper, magnesium, phosphorus, vitamin B6, iron.
        They are high in monounsaturated and polyunsaturated fats and omega-3 fatty acids. They are also a good source of protein.
        Nuts have a reputation for being a high-calorie and high-fat food. However, they are dense in nutrients and provide heart-healthy fats.
        The combination of healthy fats, protein, and fiber in walnuts helps to increase satisfaction and fullness.
        This makes them more healthful as a snack, compared with chips, crackers, and other simple carbohydrate foods.
        Health benefits - Consuming plant-based foods of all kinds has long been associated with a reduced risk of many lifestyle-related health conditions.
        The possible health benefits of walnuts may include boosting the cardiovascular system and bone health,
        reducing the risk of gallbladder disease, and treating epilepsy.
        Heart health - The monounsaturated and polyunsaturated fatty acids found in walnuts have been shown to decrease LDL (harmful) cholesterol
        and triglyceride levels. This, in turn, reduces the risk of cardiovascular disease, stroke, and heart attack.
        Weight management - According to research published in the Asia Pacific Journal of Clinical Nutrition,
        routine nut consumption is associated with higher levels of energy use while resting. In trials that compared weight loss using diets
        that include or exclude nuts, the diets that included nuts in moderation showed greater weight loss.
        A study published in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition also found that women who reported
        rarely eating nuts had a greater incidence of weight gain over an 8-year period than those who consumed nuts two times a week or more.
        Gallstone disease - According to another study in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, frequent nut consumption is associated
        with a reduced risk of cholecystectomy, an operation to remove the gallbladder.
        In over a million people documented over 20 years, women who consumed more than 5 ounces of nuts a week had a significantly
        lower risk of cholecystectomy than women who ate less than 1 ounce of nuts each week.
        Bone health - Walnuts are a good source of the mineral copper.
        Severe copper deficiency is associated with lower bone mineral density and an increased risk of osteoporosis.
        Osteoporosis is a condition where bones become thinner and less dense, making them easier to fracture and break.
        More research is needed on the effects of marginal copper deficiency and on the potential benefits of copper supplements
        to prevent and manage osteoporosis.
        Copper also plays an important role in the maintenance of collagen and elastin, major structural components of the body.
        Without sufficient copper, the body cannot replace damaged connective tissue or the collagen that makes up the building blocks for bone.
        This can lead to a range of issues including joint dysfunction.
        Walnuts contain a high amount of manganese. Manganese has been shown to prevent osteoporosis in combination with the minerals calcium and copper.
        Magnesium, another mineral in walnuts, is important for bone formation as it helps with the absorption of calcium into the bone.
        While manganese and copper supplements may provide quantities of minerals that can be harmful, getting these minerals through the diet is thought to be good for bone health.
        Epilepsy - Rats with manganese deficiency have been shown to be more susceptible to seizures.
        People with epilepsy have also been found to have lower whole blood manganese levels than those without epilepsy,
        although a manganese deficiency is not thought to cause epilepsy.
        More research is needed into whether manganese supplementation would benefit people with epilepsy.


    </string>

    <!--Fruits-->
    <string name="apple_details">
        Apples are extremely rich in important antioxidants, flavanoids, and dietary fiber.
        The phytonutrients and antioxidants in apples may help reduce the risk of developing cancer, hypertension, diabetes, and heart disease.
        Benefits - Improving neurological health - A 2006 study published in the journal Experimental Biology and Medicine found that
        quercetin (one of the antioxidants found abundantly in apples) was one of two compounds that helped to reduce cellular death that
        is caused by oxidation and inflammation of neurons. Another study presented at the same conference and published in the Journal of
        Alzheimers Disease suggested that apple juice consumption may increase the production in the brain of the essential neurotransmitter acetylcholine,
        resulting in improved memory among mice who have Alzheimers-like symptoms.
        Preventing dementia - A study published in the Journal of Food Science in 2008 suggested that eating apples may have benefit for your neurological health.
        The researchers found that including apples in your daily diet may protect neuron cells against oxidative stress-induced neurotoxicity
        and may play an important role in reducing the risk of neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimers disease.
        Reducing your risk of stroke - A study involving 9,208 men and women showed that those who ate the most apples over a 28-year period had the lowest
        risk for stroke. The researchers concluded that the intake of apples is related to a decreased risk of thrombotic stroke.
        Lowering levels of bad cholesterol - A group of researchers at The Florida State University stated that apples are a miracle fruit.
        They found that older women who ate apples everyday had 23% less bad cholesterol (LDL) and 4 percent more good cholesterol (HDL) after just six months.
        Reducing your risk of diabetes - Apples could also help lower your risk of diabetes. A study involving 187,382 people found that people who ate
        three servings per week of apples, grapes, raisins, blueberries or pears had a 7 percent lower risk of developing type 2 diabetes compared to those
        who did not.
        Warding off breast cancer - There is growing evidence suggesting that an apple a day may help prevent breast cancer, according to a series of studies
        conducted by prominent Cornell researcher Rui Hai Liu.
        Obesity - In a study published in the journal Food Chemistry in 2014, a team of researchers analyzed how the bioactive compounds of seven different
        varieties of apples - Granny Smith, Braeburn, Fuji, Gala, Golden Delicious, McIntosh and Red Delicious - affected the good gut bacteria of
        diet-induced obese mice. The researchers found that, compared with all other apple varieties, Granny Smiths appeared to have the most beneficial
        effect on good gut bacteria. They suggest that their findings may lead to strategies that prevent obesity and its associated disorders.
        Nutrition - Vitamin C - a powerful natural antioxidant capable of blocking some of the damage caused by free radicals, as well as boosting the
        bodys resistance against infectious agents, according to the University of Maryland Medical Center.
        B-complex vitamins (riboflavin, thiamin, and vitamin B-6) - these vitamins are key in maintaining red blood cells and the nervous system in good health.
        Dietary fiber - the British National Health Service says that a diet high in fiber can help prevent the development of certain diseases and
        may help prevent the amount of bad cholesterol in your blood from rising.
        Phytonutrients - apples are rich in polyphenolic compounds. These phytonutrients help protect the body from the detrimental effects of free radicals.
        Minerals such as calcium, potassium, and phosphorus.
    </string>
    <string name="banana_details">
        Bananas are one of the most widely consumed fruits in the world for good reason.
        Eating them could help lower blood pressure and reduce the risks of cancer and asthma.
        Fast facts about bananas - Bananas are rich in potassium and fiber. They may help prevent asthma, cancer, high blood pressure, diabetes,
        cardiovascular disease, and digestive problems. Ripen bananas at room temperature and add them to cereal for a tasty breakfast. People who use beta
        blockers should not suddenly increase their intake of bananas.
        Health benefits - Potassium - Bananas are rich in a mineral called potassium. This mineral is important as it helps maintain fluid levels in the
        body and regulates the movement of nutrients and waste products in and out of cells. Potassium also helps muscles to contract and nerve cells to
        respond. It keeps the heart beating regularly and can reduce the effect of sodium on blood pressure. Potassium may reduce the risk of kidney stones
        forming as people age. In turn, healthy kidneys make sure that the right amount of potassium is kept in the body. One medium-sized banana contains
        422 milligrams of potassium.
        Nutritional profile - One serving of banana is considered to be about 126 grams. One serving of banana contains 110 calories, 30 grams of
        carbohydrate and 1 gram of protein. Bananas are naturally free of fat, cholesterol, and sodium.
        Bananas provide a variety of vitamins and minerals - Vitamin B6, Manganese, Vitamin C, Potassium, Dietary Fiber, Protein, Magnesium, Riboflavin,
        Niacin, Vitamin A, Iron.
    </string>
    <string name="cantaloupe_details">
       Their high water content helps ward off dehydration and combat the heat while their refreshing taste provides a guilt-free,
        low maintenance dessert for kids and adults alike. The mildly sweet and juicy flavor of cantaloupe makes it a perfect fruit for
        even the pickiest palates. Cantaloupes are also commonly known as muskmelons, mush melons, rock melons, and Persian melons.
        They are a member of the botanical family Cucurbitaceae, along with honeydew and watermelons.
        Fast facts on cantaloupes - Cantaloupe compounds may protect against age-related macular degeneration. One cup of diced cantaloupe contains
        only 53 calories. Just 200 grams of cantaloupe exceeds your daily vitamin C requirements. Cantaloupe can be added to many foods, from smoothies to salsas.
        Benefits - Consuming fruits and vegetables of all kinds is associated with a reduced risk of many lifestyle-related health conditions. Many studies
        have suggested that increasing consumption of plant foods such as cantaloupe decreases the risk of obesity, overall mortality, diabetes,
        and heart disease while promoting a healthy complexion and hair, increased energy, and overall lower weight.
        Age-related macular degeneration - The antioxidant zeaxanthin, found in cantaloupe, filters out harmful blue light rays and is thought to
        play a protective role in eye health and possibly ward off damage from macular degeneration. A higher intake of all fruits (3 or more servings per
        day) has also been shown to decrease the risk of and progression of age-related macular degeneration.
        Asthma - The risks for developing asthma are lower in people who consume a high amount of certain nutrients. One of these nutrients
        is beta-carotene, found in yellow and orange fruits such as cantaloupe, pumpkin, carrots, and leafy greens, including spinach and kale.
        Vitamin C is another important nutrient that may protect against asthma and is found in abundance in cantaloupe, as well as citrus and
        tropical fruits. Blood pressure - The fiber, potassium, vitamin C, and choline content in cantaloupe all support heart health. Consuming foods that
        are high in potassium can help to decrease blood pressure. Getting enough potassium is almost as important as reducing sodium intake
        for the treatment of hypertension (high blood pressure). High potassium intakes are also associated with a reduced risk of stroke, protection
        against loss of muscle mass, preservation of bone mineral density, and reduction in the formation of kidney stones.
        Cancer - Diets rich in beta-carotene from plant foods such as cantaloupe may play a protective role against prostate cancer,
        according to a study conducted by the Harvard School of Public Healths Department of Nutrition.
        Digestion - Cantaloupe, because it is high in both fiber and moisture, helps to prevent constipation, promote regularity, and maintain
        a healthy digestive tract. Hydration - With its high water and electrolyte content, cantaloupe is a great snack to have on hand during the hot
        summer months to prevent dehydration. It is also a great go-to snack after a workout for this same reason.
        Inflammation - Choline is an essential and versatile nutrient that is present in cantaloupe, it aids the body in sleep, muscle movement, learning,
        and memory. Choline also helps to maintain the structure of cellular membranes, aids in the transmission of nerve impulses, assists
        in the absorption of fat, and reduces chronic inflammation. Skin and hair - Eating fruits such as cantaloupe are beneficial for hair because they
        contain vitamin A, a nutrient required for sebum production, which is a compound that keeps hair moisturized and healthy. Vitamin A is also
        necessary for the growth of all bodily tissues, including skin and hair. Adequate intake of vitamin C is needed for the building and maintenance
        of collagen, which provides structure to skin and hair. One cup of diced cantaloupe provides 97 percent of a persons daily needs for vitamin C.
        Cantaloupe also contributes to overall hydration, which is vital for having healthy looking skin and hair. It can even be used as a hair
        conditioner - mash together cantaloupe chunks and avocado, smooth onto hair and leave on for 10 minutes to replenish moisture and add shine.
    </string>
    <string name="figs_details">
        Figs grow on the Ficus tree (Ficus carica), which is a member of the Mulberry family. They are unique in that they have an opening,
        called the ostiole or eye, which is not connected to the tree, but which helps the fruits development by increasing its communication with
        the environment. Figs range dramatically in color and subtly in texture depending upon the variety. The majority of figs are dried, either
        by exposure to sunlight or through an artificial process, creating a sweet and nutritious dried fruit that can be enjoyed throughout the year.
        Health Benefits - Figs May Help Lower High Blood Pressure - Figs are a good source of potassium, a mineral that helps to control blood pressure.
        Since many people not only do not eat enough fruits and vegetables, but do consume high amounts of sodium as salt is frequently added to processed
        foods, they may be deficient in potassium. Low intake of potassium-rich foods, especially when coupled with a high intake of sodium,
        can lead to hypertension. In the Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (DASH) study, one group ate servings of fruits and vegetables in place of
        snacks and sweets, and also ate low-fat dairy food. This diet delivered more potassium, magnesium and calcium. Another group ate a usual diet low
        in fruits and vegetables with a fat content like that found in the average American Diet. After eight weeks, the group that ate the enhanced
        diet lowered their blood pressure by an average of 5.5 points (systolic) over 3.0 points (diastolic).
        Figs May be a Sweet Way to Lose Weight - Figs are a good source of dietary fiber. Fiber and fiber-rich foods may have a positive effect on weight
        management. In one study, women who increased their fiber intake with supplements significantly decreased their energy intake, yet their hunger and
        satiety scores did not change. Figs, like other high fiber foods, may be helpful in a weight management program.
        Fruit and Cereal Fiber—Which is Found in Figs—Protective against Postmenopausal Breast Cancer - Results of a prospective study involving 51,823
        postmenopausal women for an average of 8.3 years showed a 34 percent reduction in breast cancer risk for those consuming the most fruit fiber
        compared to those consuming the least. In addition, in the subgroup of women who had ever used hormone replacement, those consuming the most fiber,
        especially cereal fiber, had a 50 percent reduction in their risk of breast cancer compared to those consuming the least. Fruits richest in fiber include
        apples, dates, figs, pears and prunes. When choosing a high fiber cereal, look for whole grain cereals as they supply the most bran.
        Fig Leaf May Have Insulin-Lowering Properties - You probably do not think about the leaves of the fig tree as one of figs edible parts. But in some
        cultures, fig leaves are a common part of the menu, and for good reason. The leaves of the fig have repeatedly been shown to have antidiabetic
        properties and can actually reduce the amount of insulin needed by persons with diabetes who require insulin injections. In one study, a liquid
        extract made from fig leaves was simply added to the breakfast of insulin-dependent diabetic subjects in order to produce this insulin-lowering
        effect. Figs Potential Cardiovascular Effects - In animal studies, fig leaves have been shown to lower levels of triglycerides (a form in which
        fats circulate in the bloodstream), while in in-vitro studies, fig leaves inhibited the growth of certain types of cancer cells. Researchers have
        not yet determined exactly which substances in fig leaves are responsible for these remarkable healing effects. Besides their potassium and fiber
        content, figs emerged from our food ranking system as a good source of the trace mineral manganese.
    </string>
    <string name="grape_details">
        The nutrients in grapes offer a number of possible health benefits. They have been associated with prevention of cancer, heart disease, high blood
        pressure, and constipation.
        Fast facts about grapes - The nutrients in grapes may help protect against cancer, eye problems, cardiovascular disease, and other health conditions.
        Resveratrol is a key nutrient in grapes that may offer health benefits. Grapes are a good source of fiber, potassium, and a range of vitamins and
        other minerals. Grapes are suitable for people with diabetes, as long as they are accounted for in the diet plan.
        Benefits - Like other fruits and vegetables, grapes are a good source of fiber and water. Antioxidants and other nutrients in grapes may make
        them particularly healthful, although more research is needed to confirm some of their benefits.
        1. Cancer - Grapes contain powerful antioxidants known as polyphenols. These are thought to have anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties. One
        of these is resveratrol. It is found in the skins of red grapes. Laboratory studies have suggested that resveratrol may be able to slow or prevent
        the growth of tumors in lymph, liver, stomach, breast, colon, skin cancer, and leukemia.
        2. Heart health - Animal studies have indicated that quercetin and resveratrol may reduce the risk of atherosclerosis and protect against the
        damage caused by low-density lipoprotein (LDL), or bad cholesterol. These studies have mostly used doses of these flavonoids far higher than those
        usually consumed by humans. The polyphenols in grapes, such as resveratrol, are thought to have antioxidant, lipid-lowering, and anti-inflammatory
        actions that may help reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). They may achieve this by preventing platelet build-up and reducing blood
        pressure and the risk of irregular heart rhythms. Grapes contain fiber and potassium, both of which support heart health. The American Heart
        Association (AHA) recommends increasing potassium intake while decreasing sodium consumption to improve blood pressure and cardiovascular health.
        3. Blood pressure - Increasing potassium intake may help reduce the negative effects of too much sodium in the diet. Grapes have a high potassium
        content. This suggests they can help reduce the effects of sodium in people with high blood pressure. Fiber is important for maintaining a healthy
        cardiovascular system, including heart health and blood pressure. Grapes are a good source of fiber.
        4. Constipation - Grapes contain water and fiber. These can help people stay hydrated, keep bowel movements regular, and reduce the risk of
        constipation.
        5. Allergies - Because of the anti-inflammatory effects of quercetin, some suggest that consuming grapes may help to alleviate symptoms of allergies,
        including runny nose, watery eyes, and hives. However, no human studies have been done to prove this theory.
        6. Diabetes - In 2013, results of a study published in the BMJ suggested that certain fruits, but not juices, may reduce the risk of type 2
        diabetes in adults. During the study, which involved 187,382 participants and lasted 22 years, 6.5 percent of the participants developed diabetes.
        However, those who consumed three servings a week of blueberries, grapes, raisins, apples, or pears had a 7-percent lower risk of type 2 diabetes
        compared with those who did not. The relatively high level of sugar found in grapes leads some people to ask whether they are safe for people
        with diabetes to eat. The American Diabetes Association encourages people to consume grapes and other fruits, as long as the carbohydrate amount
        is counted as part of their meal plan. The vitamins, minerals, and fiber in grapes make them a healthful way to satisfy a sweet tooth.
        7. Diabetic neuropathy and retinopathy - Some studies have indicated that resveratrol may protect against diabetic neuropathy, which affects nerve
        function. Scientists believe this may be due to the neuroprotective effects of this compound. Animal studies have indicated that resveratrol may
        also protect against retinopathy, which can severely affect vision. Diabetic neuropathy and retinopathy can result when diabetes is poorly
        controlled.
        8. Eye health - Grapes contain the antioxidants lutein and zeaxanthin, which can help maintain eye health. They are thought to neutralize unstable
        molecules known as free radicals. In this way, they may reduce oxidative stress and damage to the retina, and help prevent cataracts and other
        conditions. Laboratory tests have suggested that resveratrol may protect against various eye problems, including age-related macular degeneration,
        glaucoma, cataract, and others. However, it remains unclear exactly how it works, and how it might be beneficial to humans.
        9. Acne - Results of an in vitro study published in the journal Dermatology and Therapy claims that resveratrol could help treat acne,
        especially if used with benzoyl peroxide as a topical treatment.
        10. Other conditions - Other health issues that resveratrol may help with include - Alzheimers disease, blood glucose control, osteoarthritis, boosting the immune system.
    </string>
    <string name="plum_details">
        Plums are loaded with minerals and is a great source of potassium. It is also rich in antioxidants, protecting the body against cell-damaging free
        radicals. Plums are also low in calories and hence will not increase your blood sugar levels.
        Health Benefits - 1. Improves the health of your heart - Rich in antioxidants, plum improves and maintains the health of your heart. The
        antioxidants fights the free radicals, preventing heart diseases and stroke scares. Antioxidants prevent oxidation of cholesterol and help in
        maintaining the health of the heart.
        2. Relieves constipation - Plums contain isatin and sorbitol, which help relieve constipation and improve digestion. It also keeps the bowel
        healthy. You can have plums or dried plums, which are known as prunes, to get relief from constipation and other digestive issues.
        3. Protects against cancer - The reddish blue color of the skin of the plum is due to the pigment, anthocyanins, which also fights free radicals.
        Plum also protects against breast cancer, cavity and oral cancer.
        4. Improves circulation of blood - Plums improve the bodys ability to absorb iron. The fruit also contains iron, which is required for the
        production of blood cells. Eating plums will improve the circulation of blood.
        5. Lowers cholesterol levels - The fruit contains soluble fiber, which helps reduce cholesterol levels and inhibit the production of cholesterol
        in the liver. The soluble fiber soaks up the bile, which is produced using cholesterol. So, when the bile is soaked up by the soluble fiber
        in the fruit, the liver uses cholesterol stored in the body, thereby lowering the cholesterol levels.
        6. Good for your skin - Consuming plum firms your skin and clears your skin texture. The fruit reduces wrinkles and rejuvenates your skin. Drink
        plum juice for younger looking skin.
        7. Good for your bones - According to several studies, consuming plums improves bone health. Plums contain boron, which is important for
        preservation of bone density and maintaining bone health. The fruit is also rich in flavonoids and phenolic compounds, which reverse the loss of bone.
        8. Reduces the appearance of scars - Plums increase the blood circulation to the scar, helping development of new skin and reducing the appearance
        of the scar. It helps the skin to heal faster and replace damaged skin with new skin. Consuming plums also improve skin texture and elasticity.
        It also reduces the appearance of dark spots, freckles and treats other skin conditions.
        9. Treats hair fall and promotes hair growth - Plums stop hair fall by reversing the adrenal gland fatigue. It also promotes hair growth as it has
        high content of iron and it improves blood circulation. Eat plums if you want to have thicker and stronger hair.
        10. Improves immunity - Eating plums will keep cold and flu at bay by improving your immunity. The fruit boosts your immunity and promotes
        development of healthy tissues.
    </string>
    <string name="melons_details">
        Melons are not only low in calories and fat, but they are also high in essential vitamins and minerals, and water content. In fact, a fresh
        watermelon, cantaloupe, and honeydew contains up to 90 percent water, making them some of the most thirst-quenching snacks around. And serving
        them is simple as can be. All you need is a knife and a plate and you’ll have yourself a poolside favorite. But melons are more than just
        refreshing. Here are some quick facts on the additional health benefits of melons.
        Honeydew provides you with natural sugars that will continue to fuel your cells throughout the day. It also is low in fat and contains several
        key vitamins and minerals, such as - 1. Vitamin C - proven to boost your immune system, as well as give you healthy skin, strengthen tissues, and
        promote healthy brain function. 2. Potassium - an important mineral for healthy heart function. A potassium shortage can result in an irregular
        heartbeat. 3. Copper - aids in skin cell regeneration, which helps promote healthy skin. 4. Vitamin B - helps rid the body of toxins that can cause
        illness and disease. Watermelon - This melon can be identified by its bright color, which not only makes it look appetizing, but also adds
        nutritional benefits, including - 1. Lycopene - a powerful antioxidant that can help prevent cell damage, and may help prevent several types of
        cancer. The deeper the color of the watermelon, then the more lycopene it contains. 2. Phytonutrients - may help boost cardiovascular health.
        3. Vitamins A and C - like the other melons, watermelon provides a rich source of these essential vitamins, as well as potassium.
    </string>
    <string name="limes_details">
        Fast facts on limes - One lime can provide 32 percent of the vitamin C needed in a day. The nutrients in limes can support heart, reduce the risk
        of asthma, and promote healthy skin. Lime juice and zest can also be used to flavor drinks and dishes. Be sure to wash the peel, even if you
        are planning to discard it. Limes are renowned for their vitamin C content. One lime with a 2-inch diameter provides 32 percent of an individuals
        recommended daily vitamin C intake. The juice from one lime provides 22 percent of the daily amount.
        Benefits - Heart health - Vitamin C is linked to a reduced risk of dying from cardiovascular issues, although other nutrients common in fruit and
        vegetables, such as fiber content, are also thought to play a role. In an animal study published by the ARYA Atherosclerosis journal, lime juice
        and peel was shown to decrease fatty streaks found in coronary arteries. These streaks are indicators of plaque buildup and cardiovascular disease.
        A 2013 meta-analysis of studies showed that low vitamin C levels are associated with an increased risk of stroke.
        Antimicrobial activity - Lime juice has demonstrated antibacterial and antifungal properties. A recent study published in Evidence-Based
        Complementary and Alternative Medicine linked the effects of consuming citrus to controlling Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) infections.
        Asthma prevention - The risks of developing asthma are lower in people who consume high amounts of certain nutrients. Low levels of vitamin C are
        commonly found in people with asthma, leading researchers to believe that there is a relationship between vitamin C consumption and
        asthma prevention. One recent study also showed that vitamin C could help protect against the triggering of asthma symptoms by air pollution.
        Increasing iron absorption - Iron deficiency is the most common nutrient deficiency in the world. Pairing foods that are high in vitamin C with
        foods that are rich in iron will maximize the bodys ability to absorb iron, particularly when taking in iron from plant-based iron sources.
        Boosting the immune system - Foods that are high in vitamin C and other antioxidants can help the immune system battle germs that cause a cold or
        flu. Vitamin C helps the immune system to produce more cells and also improves those cells ability to kill microbes and protect the body
        against disease. Maintaining a diet high in fruits and vegetables is especially important during the winter months. During this time,
        physical activity levels tend to decrease and seasonal diseases, such as the flu, gain momentum.
        Healthy skin - The natural form of vitamin C, when consumed from fresh produce rather than in supplements, has a number of cosmetic benefits.
        It can help fight skin damage caused by the sun and pollution, reduce wrinkles, and improve the overall texture of the skin.
        Adequate intake of vitamin C is also needed for building and maintaining the collagen that provides structure to skin and hair.
        Lowering risk of stroke - According to the American Heart Association, eating higher amounts of citrus fruits may lower ischemic stroke risk for
        women. In one study, participants who ate the highest amounts of citrus had a risk of ischemic stroke 19 percent lower than those who consumed the lowest.
    </string>
    <string name="mangoes_details">
        The mango is a member of the drupe family, a type of plant food with an outer fleshy part surrounding a shell (what we sometimes call a pit)
        that contains a seed. Olives, dates, and coconuts are also types of drupes. There are many different kinds of mangoes. They range in color, shape,
        flavor, and seed size. While the skin color of mangoes can vary from green to red, yellow, or orange, the inner flesh of the mango is mostly a
        golden yellow. They have a sweet and creamy taste and contain over 20 vitamins and minerals.
        Benefits - Many studies have suggested that increasing consumption of plant foods like mangoes decreases the risk of obesity and overall mortality,
        diabetes, and heart disease and promotes a healthy complexion and hair, increased energy, and overall lower weight. Mangoes can possibly help
        protect and strengthen the body in the following ways - Age-related macular degeneration - The antioxidant zeaxanthin, found in mangoes, filters
        out harmful blue light rays and is thought to play a protective role in eye health and possibly ward off damage from macular degeneration.
        A higher intake of all fruits (three or more servings per day) has also been shown to decrease the risk of and progression of age-related macular
        degeneration.
        Asthma prevention - The risk of developing asthma is lower in people who consume a high amount of certain nutrients. One of these nutrients is
        beta-carotene, found in mangoes, papaya, apricots, broccoli, cantaloupe, pumpkin, and carrots.
        Cancer - Diets rich in beta-carotene may also play a protective role against prostate cancer, according to a study conducted by the Harvard School
        of Public Healths Department of Nutrition and has been shown to reduce the risk of colon cancer in a Japanese study. In a study conducted by Texas
        AgriLife Research, food scientists tested mango polyphenol extracts on colon, breast, lung, leukemia, and prostate cancer tissue, mangoes were
        shown to have some impact on all cancers tested but were most effective with breast and colon cancers.
        Bone health - Low intakes of vitamin K are associated with a higher risk of bone fracture. Adequate vitamin K consumption can be achieved by
        eating a proper intake of fruits and vegetables. Vitamin K is important for improving calcium absorption, essential for optimal bone health.
        Diabetes - Studies have shown that people with type 1 diabetes who consume high-fiber diets have lower blood glucose levels, and individuals with
        type 2 diabetes may have improved blood sugar, lipids, and insulin levels. One cup of mango provides about 3 grams of fiber.
        Digestion - Mangoes, because of their fiber and water content, help to prevent constipation and promote regularity and a healthy digestive tract.
        Heart disease - The fiber, potassium, and vitamin content in mangoes all help to ward off heart disease. An increase in potassium intake along
        with a decrease in sodium intake is the most important dietary change that a person can make to reduce their risk of hypertension.
        Skin and Hair - Mangoes are also great for your hair because they contain vitamin A, a nutrient required for sebum production that keeps hair
        moisturized. Vitamin A is also necessary for the growth of all bodily tissues, including skin and hair. Adequate intake of vitamin C, found in just
        1 cup of mango per day, is needed for the building and maintenance of collagen, which provides structure to skin and hair.
    </string>
    <string name="nopal_details">
        The nopal cactus is more commonly known as the prickly pear cactus. It is native to Mexico and famous for its health benefits due to its high
        antioxidant, vitamin, mineral, and fiber content. Nopales or nopalitos are the pads of the nopal or prickly pear cactus. They are eaten as a
        vegetable and commonly found in restaurants, grocery stores, and farmers markets across the American Southwest and Mexico. They can be sautéed
        and used in many dishes, including tacos, scrambled eggs, or as a side dish with tomatoes and onions. Nopales can also be eaten raw. They resemble
        a green pepper when diced and are turned into juice, jams, or tea. Prickly pear fruit or the small, rounded, and often colorful part of the plant
        can also be consumed. Juice extracted from the fruit is a popular drink of choice for health-conscious consumers in Mexico.
        The prickly pear fruit, which comes in a variety of colors, contains the flavonoids kaempferol and quercetin, which are antioxidants that have
        anti-inflammatory properties. In a study comparing three different juices from various colors of prickly pear, red-purple, white-green, and
        yellow-orange, the red-purple variety had the most antioxidants.
        Health benefits - Both parts of the nopal plant, the nopales and the fruit, have been used in traditional medicine for disease treatment and
        prevention. The cactus has been used to treat - glaucoma, wounds, fatigue, liver conditions, ulcers.
        The purported benefits of fresh nopal juice include lowering blood sugar, healing wounds, and lowering cholesterol. Human studies on the nopal
        cactus and its ability to treat or prevent disease are limited. Nevertheless, many studies have confirmed the antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties of the plant.
        Diabetes - Cactus plants have been traditionally used in Mexico for the treatment of diabetes. In a small study of people with type 2 diabetes,
        two groups of participants were given a high carbohydrate breakfast. One group consumed nopal with their breakfast, while the other did not.
        The group who ate the nopal had significantly lower blood sugar levels after the meal, as well as lower insulin levels, compared to the group
        who did not have nopal. People with diabetes benefit from including high-fiber foods, such as nopal and prickly pear, in their diet. High-fiber
        diets can improve blood sugar, lower insulin levels, and improve blood lipids. The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics recommend consuming at least
        25 g of fiber per day for women and 38 g for men.
    </string>
    <string name="raisins_details">
        The health benefits of raisins include improved digestion, bone health, iron levels, acidosis, fever, and sexual dysfunction. They have also been
        known for aiding in a healthy weight gain, as well as for their positive impact on eyes, teeth, and hair.
        Raisins are created by drying grapes, either in the sun or in driers, which turns the grapes into golden, green or black dried fruit gems.
        Raisins Nutrition - As per the USDA National Nutrient Database, raisins are a good source of energy, fiber, protein, and carbohydrates. They are
        high in sugar and calories but still have a low glycemic index. Raisins contain zero cholesterol and are rich in various nutrients that include -
        Vitamins - Vitamin C, folate, thiamin, niacin, riboflavin, vitamin B-6, pantothenic acid.
        Minerals - Potassium, calcium, magnesium, phosphorus, iron, zinc and sodium.
        Benefits of Raisins - Fiber-Rich and Act as a Laxative - Raisins have an abundant supply of fiber in them, which helps to absorb the natural fluids
        present in the body. This type of fiber is considered insoluble fiber because it takes in water to gain volume. This adds bulk to the food moving
        through the intestinal tract, making for more regular bowel movements, and ultimately helps give relief from constipation. A study in the Journal
        of Medicinal Food, confirms that adding just two servings of raisins per day – a relatively small dietary change, as they mention can improve
        colon function and may decrease the risk of colon cancer.
        Treat Bloating - The fiber in raisins helps sweep out toxins and harmful materials from the digestive tract. This can protect people from
        intestinal diseases, bacterial growth, and discomfort from bloating.
        Prevent Acidity - Raisins are rich in potassium and magnesium, which are a natural remedy for acidosis. These minerals are two of the most common
        components of antacids because they are considered basic on the pH scale. There are two types of acidosis with a number of causes, including
        as a state of increased acidity of the blood (also known as toxicity of the blood) or the gases in our respiratory system that may cause boils,
        skin diseases, damage to the internal organs, gout, and renal calculi.
        Rich in Iron, Treat Anemia - Raisins contain a considerable amount of iron, which directly helps in the treatment of anemia. It also contains
        many members of the vitamin B complex that are essential for the formation of new blood. The high copper content also helps in the production
        of red blood cells.
        Promote Dental and Oral Health - Raisins are rich in calcium, which strengthens and helps to remineralize tooth enamel. Further, boron present in
        these dried fruits helps curb the growth of oral germs, promoting strong teeth. Oleanolic acid, one of the phytochemicals present in raisins,
        plays a crucial role in protecting your teeth against decay, cavities, and brittleness. It effectively prevents the growth of Streptococcus mutans
        and Porphyromonas gingivalis, two of the bacterial species that are most responsible for cavities. This is noted in a study by
        Dr. Christine D. Wu, Department of Pediatric Dentistry, College of Dentistry, University of Illinois, Chicago. As strange as it may sound,
        while eating the dried fruits, the longer they stick to your teeth, the better, because that ensures an extended contact of oleanolic acid with
        the teeth, increasing the preventive powers of bacterial growth.
        Rich in Antioxidants - Raisins have high levels of antioxidants that include catechins and polyphenolic phytonutrients. These antioxidants protect
        against the damage caused by free radicals, one of the primary underlying factors linked to the growth of cancer cells and other conditions such
        as macular degeneration. However, more scientific evidence is required to confirm these findings. Further, the fiber content helps promote
        excretion of bile from the body, thus flushing out toxins. Gin-soaked golden raisins are a popular folk remedy which helps relieve chronic pain
        and especially arthritic pain. Anecdotal evidence suggests that people show improvement in arthritic symptoms between 1-8 weeks of consuming
        10 of these drunken raisins daily.
        Promote Bone Health - Calcium, the main element of our bones, is present in raisins. These dried fruits are one of the best sources of boron,
        a micronutrient (a nutrient required by the body in a very small amount). Boron is vital for the proper bone formation, and efficient absorption
        of calcium. It is particularly helpful in preventing menopause induced osteoporosis in women and very beneficial for bones and joints. Potassium
        is another essential nutrient found in high levels, which can help strengthen bones and promote bone growth, thereby reducing the chances of osteoporosis.
        Increase Fertility - Raisins have long been known to stimulate the libido and induce arousal, primarily due to the presence of an amino acid called
        arginine, which is beneficial in treating erectile dysfunction. This is confirmed in research performed on 180 patients suffering from asthenospermia
        (a condition for reduced sperm motility). Arginine is a natural aphrodisiac that increases the levels of sperm motility, thereby increasing the
        chances of conception when engaging in sexual intercourse. Consuming these sweet dried fruits daily also helps increase sexual endurance.
        Improve Skin Health - Antioxidants and vitamin C in raisins help keep the skin radiant, taut, and youthful. Eating them can help prevent conditions like psoriasis and acne as they have strong germicidal properties.
        Promote Hair Health - Daily consumption of raisins helps promote shiny and thick hair as the vitamin C content prevents cell damage. Their anti-inflammatory properties help prevent scalp irritation, dandruff, and flakiness.
        Promote Good Sleep - Iron deficiency anemia can be a cause for your insomnia trouble, and therefore, intake of iron-rich raisins can help ensure a good nights sleep.
        Control Cholesterol Levels - The high levels of potassium, fiber, polyphenols, phenolic acid, tannins, and antioxidants in raisins replace the saturated fats in the diet that lead to artery-clogging cholesterol, thereby promoting good cardiac health.
        Reduce Hypertension - Studies show a positive correlation between reduced hypertension and consumption of raisins. Many of the nutrients packed into them are beneficial, however, experts believe that it is the high level of potassium that helps reduce the tension of blood vessels and decrease high blood pressure. A report published in the New England Journal of Medicine says that the dietary fiber in these dried grapes is also thought to affect the biochemistry of blood vessels, and reducing their stiffness, which in turn reduces hypertension.
        Promote Weight Gain - Raisins can help gain weight in a healthy way, since they are full of fructose and glucose. They form an ideal part of a diet for athletes or bodybuilders who need a powerful boost of energy, or for those who want to put on weight without accumulating unhealthy amounts of cholesterol.
        Control Diabetes - In a number of studies, the connection between raisins and blood glucose levels has been researched. Raisins have been linked to lower the postprandial insulin response, which means they can stabilize the spikes or plunges on the insulin after a meal. They also help regulate the release of leptin and ghrelin, which are the hormones responsible for telling the body when it is hungry or full – another key in thwarting the occurence of diabetes. By keeping a check on these hormones, people who eat raisins can improve their chances of maintaining a healthy diet and prevent overeating.
        Promote Kidney Health - Potassium in raisins can help prevent the formation and reoccurrence of kidney stones.
        Increase Nutrient Uptake - Raisins have a rich content of vitamins, amino acids, and minerals such as selenium and phosphorus, which facilitate absorption of other nutrients and proteins in the body. Including them in your diet helps improve your overall energy and immune system strength.
        Liver Health - Overnight-soaked raisins and raisin water are used as part of the liver cleanse diet as the dried fruits are rich in bioflavonoids that protect you from the free radical activity. Raisin water especially promotes good liver health, which helps purify the blood.
    </string>
    <string name="oranges_details">
        Oranges are low in calories and full of nutrients, they promote clear, healthy, skin and can help to lower our risk for many diseases as part of an overall healthy and varied diet. Orange trees are the most commonly cultivated fruit trees in the world. Oranges are a popular fruit because of their natural sweetness, wide variety of types and diversity of uses, from juices and marmalades to face masks and candied orange slices. An orange has over 170 different phytochemicals and more than 60 flavonoids. Many of these have been shown to have anti-inflammatory properties and strong antioxidant effects.
        Benefits - Stroke - According to the American Heart Association (AHA), eating higher amounts of a compound found in citrus fruits like oranges and grapefruit may lower ischemic stroke risk for women. Those who ate the highest amounts of citrus had a 19 percent lower risk of ischemic stroke than women who consumed the least.
        Blood pressure - Maintaining a low sodium intake is essential to lowering blood pressure, however increasing potassium intake may be just as important because of its vasodilation effects. According to the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES), fewer than 2 percent of US adults meet the daily 4700 mg recommendation. Also of note, a high potassium intake is associated with a 20 percent decreased risk of dying from all causes.
        Cancer - According to a study published in the American Journal of Epidemiology, consuming bananas, oranges and orange juice in the first two years of life may reduce the risk of developing childhood leukemia. As an excellent source of the strong antioxidant vitamin C, oranges can also help combat the formation of free radicals known to cause cancer. While an adequate vitamin C intake is necessary and very beneficial as an antioxidant, the amount necessary to consume for therapeutic purposes for cancer is more than we can consume. One study has concluded that vitamin C from oranges could one day be harnessed to impair colorectal cancer cells, but 300-oranges worth of vitamin C would be needed. High fiber intakes from fruits and vegetables are associated with a lowered risk of colorectal cancer.
        Heart health - The fiber, potassium, vitamin C and choline content in oranges all support heart health. An increase in potassium intake along with a decrease in sodium intake is the most important dietary change that a person can make to reduce their risk of cardiovascular disease, according to Dr. Mark Houston, an associate clinical professor of medicine at Vanderbilt Medical School and director of the Hypertension Institute at St. Thomas Hospital in Tennessee. In one study, those who consumed 4069 mg of potassium per day had a 49 percent lower risk of death from ischemic heart disease compared with those who consumed less potassium (about 1000 mg per day). High potassium intakes are also associated with a reduced risk of stroke, protection against loss of muscle mass, preservation of bone mineral density and reduction in the formation of kidney stones.
        Diabetes - Studies have shown that type 1 diabetics who consume high-fiber diets have lower blood glucose levels and type 2 diabetics may have improved blood sugar, lipids and insulin levels. One medium banana provides about 3 grams of fiber.
        Skin - The antioxidant vitamin C, when eaten in its natural form (as in an orange) or applied topically, can help to fight skin damage caused by the sun and pollution, reduce wrinkles and improve overall skin texture. Vitamin C plays a vital role in the formation of collagen, the support system of your skin.
        Nutrition - One medium orange (approximately 154 grams) contains 80 calories, 0 grams of fat, 250 milligrams of potassium, 19 grams of carbohydrate (14 grams of sugar and 3 grams of dietary fiber) as well as 1 gram of protein.
        One orange provides 130 percent of your vitamin C needs for the day, 2 percent of vitamin A needs, 6 percent of calcium and 0 percent of iron.
        Oranges also contain thiamin, riboflavin, niacin, vitamin B-6, folate, pantothenic acid, phosphorus, magnesium, manganese, selenium and copper. Because of their high vitamin C content (over twice the daily need) oranges are associated with boosting the immune system.
        Oranges also contain choline, zeaxanthin, and carotenoids.
        Choline is an important nutrient found in oranges that helps with sleep, muscle movement, learning and memory. Choline also helps to maintain the structure of cellular membranes, aids in the transmission of nerve impulses, assists in the absorption of fat and reduces chronic inflammation.
        Zeaxanthin and carotenoids have antioxidant effects and have been shown to have an inverse relationship with overall cancer rates and prostate cancer in particular.
    </string>
    <string name="papaya_details">
        The possible health benefits of consuming papaya include a reduced risk of heart disease, diabetes, cancer, aiding in digestion, improving blood glucose control in people with diabetes, lowering blood pressure, and improving wound healing.
        Papayas are a soft, fleshy fruit that can be used in a wide variety of culinary ways. Here we will explore more on the health benefits, uses, how to incorporate more of them into your diet, and what nutritional value papayas have.
        Benefits - Zeaxanthin, an antioxidant found in papaya, filters out harmful blue light rays. It is thought to play a protective role in eye health, and it may ward off macular degeneration. However, a higher intake of all fruits has been shown to decrease the risk of and progression of age-related macular degeneration.
        Asthma prevention - The risk of developing asthma is lower in people who consume a high amount of certain nutrients. One of these nutrients is beta-carotene, contained in foods like papaya, apricots, broccoli, cantaloupe, pumpkin, and carrots.
        Cancer - Consuming the antioxidant beta-carotene, found in papayas, may reduce cancer risk. Among younger men, diets rich in beta-carotene may play a protective role against prostate cancer, according to a study published in the journal Cancer Epidemiology and Prevention Biomarkers.
        Bone health - Low intakes of vitamin K have been associated with a higher risk of bone fracture. Adequate vitamin K consumption is important for good health, as it improves calcium absorption and may reduce urinary excretion of calcium, meaning there is more calcium in the body to strengthen and rebuild bones.
        Diabetes - Studies have shown that people with type 1 diabetes who consume high-fiber diets have lower blood glucose levels, and people with type 2 diabetes may have improved blood sugar, lipid, and insulin levels. One small papaya provides about 3 grams of fiber, which is equivalent to just 17 grams of carbohydrates.
        Digestion - Papayas contain an enzyme called papain that aids digestion; in fact, it can be used as a meat tenderizer. Papaya is also high in fiber and water content, both of which help to prevent constipation and promote regularity and a healthy digestive tract.
        Heart disease - The fiber, potassium, and vitamin content in papaya all help to ward off heart disease. An increase in potassium intake along with a decrease in sodium intake is the most important dietary change that a person can make to reduce their risk of cardiovascular disease.
        Inflammation - Choline is a very important and versatile nutrient found in papayas that aids our bodies in sleep, muscle movement, learning, and memory. Choline also helps to maintain the structure of cellular membranes, aids in the transmission of nerve impulses, assists in the absorption of fat, and reduces chronic inflammation.
        Skin and healing - When used topically, mashed papaya appears to be beneficial for promoting wound healing and preventing infection of burned areas. Researchers believe that the proteolytic enzymes chymopapain and papain in papaya are responsible for their beneficial effects. Ointments containing the papain enzyme have also been used to treat decubitus ulcers (bedsores).
        Hair health - Papaya is also great for hair because it contains vitamin A, a nutrient required for sebum production, which keeps hair moisturized. Vitamin A is also necessary for the growth of all bodily tissues, including skin and hair. Adequate intake of vitamin C, which papaya can provide, is needed for the building and maintenance of collagen, which provides structure to skin.
    </string>
    <string name="peaches_details">
        The inner flesh of a peach can range in color from white to yellow or orange. There are two different varieties of peaches: freestone and clingstone, depending on whether the flesh sticks to the inner seed or easily comes apart.
        Benefits - According to a study from Texas A and M, stone fruit like peaches, plums, and nectarines have been shown to ward off obesity-related diseases such as diabetes, metabolic syndrome, and cardiovascular disease.
        The study suggests that stone fruits have bioactive and phenolic compounds with anti-obesity and anti-inflammatory properties that may also reduce the bad cholesterol (LDL) associated with cardiovascular disease.
        The authors attribute the benefits to four major phenolic groups in stone fruits: anthocyanins, chlorogenic acids, quercetins, and catechins, all of which work together and complement each other to fight off obesity-related illness.
        Cancer - As an excellent source of the strong antioxidant vitamin C, peaches can also help combat the formation of free radicals known to cause cancer. While an adequate vitamin C intake is necessary and very beneficial as an antioxidant, the amount necessary to consume for treatment purposes for cancer is thought to be beyond oral intake.
        High fiber intakes from all fruits and vegetables are associated with a lowered risk of colorectal cancer.
        Skin - The antioxidant vitamin C, when eaten in its natural form (in whole foods such as peaches) or applied topically, can reduce wrinkles, improve overall skin texture and help to fight skin damage caused by the sun and pollution. Vitamin C also plays a vital role in the formation of collagen, the support system of your skin.
        Diabetes - Another study from Texas A and M showed that peaches and plum extracts were effective in killing even the most aggressive types of breast cancer cells and did not harm normal healthy cells in the process.
        Studies have shown that type 1 diabetics who consume high-fiber diets have lower blood glucose levels and type 2 diabetics may have improved blood sugar, lipids, and insulin levels. One medium peach provides about 2 grams of fiber.
        Heart health - The fiber, potassium, vitamin C, and choline content in peaches all support heart health. An increase in potassium intake along with a decrease in sodium intake is the most important dietary change that a person can make to reduce their risk of cardiovascular disease, according to Dr. Mark Houston, an associate clinical professor of medicine at Vanderbilt Medical School and director of the Hypertension Institute at St. Thomas Hospital in Tennessee.
        Eye health - It is important to note that the benefits of consuming fruits and vegetables of all kinds, including peaches, are infinite. As plant food consumption goes up, the risk of all lifestyle related diseases (such as obesity, diabetes, and heart disease) goes down. High fruit and vegetable intake is also associated with healthy complexion and hair, increased energy, lower weight, and lower risk of mortality.
    </string>
    <string name="pears_details">
        Pears are a mild, sweet fruit with a fibrous center. They are rich in important antioxidants, flavonoids, and dietary fiber and pack all of these nutrients in a fat-free, cholesterol-free, 100-calorie package.
        Consuming pears may help with weight loss and reduce the risk of developing cancer, hypertension, diabetes, and heart disease if eaten as part of an overall healthy diet.
        Benefits - Fiber - The easiest way to increase fiber intake is to increase the consumption of fruits and vegetables. Just one medium-sized pear provides 6 grams of fiber, about 24 percent of the daily need for a woman under 50.
        Treating diverticulosis - Diverticulitis is when bulging sacs in the lining of the large intestine become infected or inflamed. High fiber diets are thought to decrease the frequency of flare-ups of diverticulitis by absorbing water in the colon and making bowel movements easier to pass. Eating a healthful diet including plenty of fruit, vegetables, and fiber can reduce pressure and inflammation in the colon.
        Weight loss - Fruits and vegetables that are high in fiber help keep you feeling fuller for longer and are also low in calories. Increased fiber intake has been associated with enhanced weight loss for obese individuals.
        Cardiovascular disease and cholesterol - Increased fiber intake has also been shown to lower cholesterol levels. A review of 67 separate controlled trials found that even a modest 10-gram per day increase in fiber intake reduced LDL (low-density lipoprotein or bad cholesterol) and total cholesterol.
        Recent studies have shown that dietary fiber may even play a role in regulating the immune system and inflammation, and may have the potential to decrease the risk of inflammation-related conditions such as cardiovascular disease, diabetes, cancer, and obesity.
        Diabetes - A high-fiber diet is associated with a lower risk of developing diabetes and more stable blood sugar levels in people with diabetes.
        Digestion - The fiber content in pears prevents constipation and promotes regularity for a healthy digestive tract.
        Detox - Regular, adequate bowel movements are crucial for the daily excretion of toxins through the bile and stool. Pears are approximately 84 percent water, which helps keep stools soft and flush the digestive system of toxins.
        Fighting free radicals - Pears contain high levels of antioxidants, including vitamin C and K, and copper. These chemicals mop up free radicals, protecting our cells from the damage they can cause.
        Nutrition - Eating one medium pear provides 12 percent of daily vitamin C needs, as well as 10 percent of vitamin K, 6 percent of potassium and smaller amounts of calcium, iron, magnesium, riboflavin, vitamin B-6, and folate. Pears, especially those with red skin, also contain carotenoids, flavonols, and anthocyanins. In the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging, pears and apples were found to be among the top contributors of flavonols in the diet.
    </string>
    <string name="prune_details">
        Prunes are dried plums, and they are known for their laxative qualities. Many people try eating prunes or drinking prune juice to alleviate constipation.
        There are many different types of plums, which range in color, texture, and taste. Any dried plum is technically a prune, but the term usually applies to the dried version of the widely available European plum called Prunus domestica.
        Other common types of plum are Prunus salicina and Prunus americana. Together, these three types of plum are responsible for most of the prune production in the world.
        All three are all freestone plums, meaning that it is easy to remove the pit. This makes drying and storage simple and ensures that the prune stays whole throughout the process.
        Drinking prune juice is an easy way to make the most of these sweet, nutritious fruits.
        Benefits - People have used prunes in traditional medicine for centuries, adding them as an ingredient to treatments for - high blood pressure, jaundice, fever, diabetes, digestion, constipation.
        Bowel function - The most well-known benefit of prunes is their laxative effect. Eating prunes can mobilize the digestive system and decrease the time between bowel movements. This effect may be due to the fruit being rich in fiber and containing high levels of sorbitol, which is a known laxative. People with constipation may find that drinking between half a cup and 1 cup of prune juice in the morning helps stimulate digestion. A second cup 30 minutes to 1 hour after a heavy meal may also be beneficial. In a 2014 review in the journal Alimentary Pharmacology and Therapeutics, researchers noted that prune consumption was more effective than psyllium husk at treating constipation. Psyllium is a popular over-the-counter (OTC) remedy for constipation, and it consists mainly of soluble fiber. The authors concluded that prunes may help increase the frequency of bowel movements in people with constipation and improve the consistency of the stools. They also noted that more research is necessary to determine the digestive benefits of prune juice in individuals who do not have constipation.
        Controlling appetite - Prunes can help prolong satiety, meaning that people will feel full for longer after eating them. Prune juice can also offer this benefit. This feeling of fullness occurs because the soluble fiber content in prunes slows digestion. Prunes also have a low glycemic index (GI), which means that they increase blood sugar levels at a slow rate. A low-GI diet offers a range of health benefits and may also allow people to go longer without feeling hungry.
        Preventing high blood pressure - The potassium content in prune juice helps balance the levels of sodium in the bloodstream. Elevated sodium levels may contribute to high blood pressure and a range of circulation and heart problems. People who take in at least 4,700 mg of potassium per day reduce their risk of hypertension. According to estimates, hypertension may be responsible for almost half of the cases of ischemic heart disease worldwide. Fewer than 2 percent of adults in the United States consume this amount of potassium.
        Protecting bone strength - Dried plums contain a range of plant compounds that may promote bone strength. A 2017 review found that including prunes and prune extracts in the diet helped preserve bone mineral density and prevent bone loss in women who had been through menopause. This area of bone health is still under investigation. Although research is yet to provide significant evidence of this benefit, including prune juice in the diet is unlikely to cause adverse effects.
        Preserving liver health - As part of traditional medicine, people used prunes as a remedy for hepatitis, a liver infection. A study in 2010 showed that prune juice can help reduce some of the more harmful chemicals that occur as a result of problems with the liver. However, more research is necessary to explore the full potential of prune juice as a treatment in liver health.
        Prune juice for children and infants - Because the digestive system has not fully developed in younger children, their needs are different than those of adults. The authors of an article in Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition recommend fruit juices, such as prune, apple, and pear juices, as a treatment for constipation in children. However, caregivers should be sure to monitor the amount that they give a child and be ready to scale it back if the child has any signs or symptoms of diarrhea.
    </string>
    <string name="tamarind_details">
        Tamarind is a delicious sweet and sour fruit that has a wide variety of uses, both for medicinal and culinary purposes. It is a medium-sized bushy tree with evergreen leaves and a fruit that develops in pods. Its pods are characterized by long, brown shells. Inside the pods is sticky, fleshy, and juicy pulp, which is the tamarind fruit. This is where nutrition and taste reside. As it has both a sweet and sour taste, people either tend to immediately like it or have a natural disposition against it.
        Tamarind Nutrition Facts - According to the USDA National Nutrient Database, tamarind provides energy (calories) along with essential nutrients like potassium, phosphorus, magnesium, calcium, and vitamin C. It also contains iron, sodium, zinc, B-vitamins (niacin, riboflavin, thiamin, folate), and vitamins A and K. There are also a number of organic compounds that make it a powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory agent.
        The health benefits of tamarind - mproves Digestion - Tamarind has long been considered a natural laxative, given its dietary fiber content. Eating it as a fruit or as a spice can increase the efficiency of your digestive system, as the insoluble fiber can bulk up your stool, making it move through the smooth muscles of the intestinal tract easily. It is also a bilious substance, meaning that it stimulates the activity of bile and bile acids, which aids in the absorption of fats and fat-soluble vitamins in the small intestine.
        This combination of digestive events together means that food runs through your digestive tract faster, making it a powerful laxative if you are suffering from chronic constipation. Tamarind also contains some soluble fiber which has the opposite effect of insoluble fiber, assisting in reducing loose stools. Studies have shown the tropical fruit to be effective against chronic diarrhea as well.
        Protects Heart Health - A study published in the Food and Chemical Toxicology journal has shown tamarind to have potential in reducing blood pressure and cholesterol. The fiber content in the sour fruit certainly plays a role with its potential for the reduction in cholesterol, since it is known to scrap excess LDL cholesterol from the veins and arteries. The potassium in tamarind may be responsible for a reduction in blood pressure as well since it is known as a vasodilator that reduces the stress on the cardiovascular system.
        Vitamin C-containing tamarind is an antioxidant that can reduce the impact of free radicals, the pesky by-products of cellular metabolism that have been linked to heart diseases and a number of other health conditions.
        Improves Circulation - Tamarind is a very good source of iron, with a single serving providing more than 10 percent of your daily requirement. A healthy supply of iron in the body guarantees proper red blood cell count, which can ensure appropriate oxygenation of different muscles and organs to function properly. Also, iron deficiency results in anemia, characterized by weakness, fatigue, headaches, cognitive disorders, and stomach issues.
        Improves Nerve Function - One of the most significant vitamins in tamarind is the B-complex. Thiamine, an important part of the vitamin B family, is found in high quantities in this fruit. Thiamine is responsible for improving nerve function, as well as muscle development, which can help you remain active, maintain reflexes, and stay strong.
        Weight Loss - One of the unique compounds that can be extracted from tamarind or found in the tamarind spice is called hydroxycitric acid (HCA). HCA is connected to weight loss because it has been shown to inhibit an enzyme in the body that specifically helps in fat storage. Furthermore, it has been known to suppress the appetite by increasing the neurotransmitter serotonin.
        Manages Diabetes - Along with its ability to thwart weight gain, it also inhibits the enzyme alpha-amylase, which mainly stops carbohydrates from being absorbed in the body. A carbohydrate-heavy diet can increase the chances of uncontrolled glucose and insulin levels, which is a significant issue for those suffering from diabetes. Tamarind may help control these fluctuations.
        The high content of magnesium in tamarind may further help to prevent or alleviate diabetes.
        Anti-inflammatory Capacity - Lupeol, found in tamarind leaves, possesses anti-inflammatory and anti-cancer properties, according to a study done at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison. The essential oil of tamarind has been connected to a number of anti-inflammatory capabilities, including the reduction of joint pain and inflammation, arthritis, rheumatic conditions, and gout. It also reduces eye irritation – one of the most common forms of which is conjunctivitis, also known as pink eye. It has shown a definite soothing and anti-inflammatory ability and is, therefore, used in many herbal remedies for inflammation.
        Boosts Immunity - One study published in Elseviers LWT – Food Science and Technology journal sheds light on the potent antioxidant properties of tamarind. Thus, enormous amounts of antioxidants as well as high levels of vitamin C, make tamarind a wonderful way to boost your immune system, staving off microbial and fungal infections. It also reduces the occurrence of parasites in the body due to its antiseptic and antimicrobial effects. Tamarind has specifically been linked to eliminating stomach worms in children in tropical areas where it is cultivated.
    </string>
    <string name="berries_details">
        Berries are among the healthiest foods you can eat. They are delicious, nutritious, and provide a number of impressive health benefits.
        1. Loaded with antioxidants - Berries contain antioxidants, which help keep free radicals under control. Free radicals are unstable molecules that are beneficial in small amounts but can damage your cells when their numbers get too high, causing oxidative stress. Berries are a great source of antioxidants, such as anthocyanins, ellagic acid, and resveratrol. In addition to protecting your cells, these plant compounds may reduce disease risk. One study showed that blueberries, blackberries, and raspberries have the highest antioxidant activity of commonly consumed fruits, next to pomegranates. In fact, several studies have confirmed that the antioxidants in berries may help reduce oxidative stress. One study in healthy men found that consuming a single, 10-ounce (300-gram) portion of blueberries helped protect their DNA against free radical damage. In another study in healthy people, eating 17 ounces (500 grams) of strawberry pulp every day for 30 days decreased a pro-oxidant marker by 38 percent.
        2. May help improve blood sugar and insulin response - Berries may improve your blood sugar and insulin levels. Test-tube and human studies suggest that they may protect your cells from high blood sugar levels, help increase insulin sensitivity, and reduce blood sugar and insulin response to high-carb meals. Importantly, these effects appear to occur in both healthy people and those with insulin resistance. In one study in healthy women, eating 5 ounces (150 grams) of puréed strawberries or mixed berries with bread led to a 24–26 percent reduction in insulin levels, compared to consuming the bread alone. Moreover, in a six-week study, obese people with insulin resistance who drank a blueberry smoothie twice per day experienced greater improvements in insulin sensitivity than those who consumed berry-free smoothies.
        3. High in fiber - Berries are a good source of fiber, including soluble fiber. Studies show that consuming soluble fiber slows down the movement of food through your digestive tract, leading to reduced hunger and increased feelings of fullness. This may decrease your calorie intake and make weight management easier. Whats more, fiber helps reduce the number of calories you absorb from mixed meals. One study found that doubling your fiber intake could make you absorb up to 130 fewer calories per day. In addition, the high fiber content of berries means that they are low in digestible or net carbs, which are calculated by subtracting fiber from total carbs.
        4. Provide many nutrients - Berries are low in calories and extremely nutritious. In addition to being high in antioxidants, they also contain several vitamins and minerals. Berries, especially strawberries, are high in vitamin C. In fact, 1 cup (150 grams) of strawberries provides a whopping 150 percent of the RDI for vitamin C. With the exception of vitamin C, all berries are fairly similar in terms of their vitamin and mineral content.
        5. Help fight inflammation - Berries have strong anti-inflammatory properties. Inflammation is your bodys defense against infection or injury. However, modern lifestyles often lead to excessive, long-term inflammation due to increased stress, inadequate physical activity, and unhealthy food choices. This type of chronic inflammation is believed to contribute to conditions like diabetes, heart disease, and obesity. Studies suggest that the antioxidants in berries may help lower inflammatory markers. In one study in overweight people, those drinking a strawberry beverage with a high-carb, high-fat meal noticed a more significant decrease in certain inflammatory markers than the control group.
        6. May help lower cholesterol levels - Berries are a heart-healthy food. Black raspberries and strawberries have been shown to help lower cholesterol in people who are obese or have metabolic syndrome. In an 8-week study, adults with metabolic syndrome who consumed a beverage made from freeze-dried strawberries daily experienced an 11 percent drop in LDL (bad) cholesterol. Whats more, berries may help prevent LDL cholesterol from becoming oxidized or damaged, which is believed to be a major risk factor for heart disease. In a controlled study in obese people, those eating 1.5 ounces (50 grams) of freeze-dried blueberries for 8 weeks noticed a 28 percent reduction in their oxidized LDL levels.
        7. May be good for your skin - Berries may help reduce skin wrinkling, as their antioxidants help control free radicals, one of the leading causes of skin damage that contributes to aging. Though research is limited, ellagic acid appears responsible for some of the skin-related benefits of berries. Test-tube and animal studies suggest that this antioxidant may protect skin by blocking the production of enzymes that break down collagen in sun-damaged skin. Collagen is a protein that is part of your skins structure. It allows your skin to stretch and remain firm. When collagen is damaged, your skin may sag and develop wrinkles. In one study, applying ellagic acid to the skin of hairless mice exposed to ultraviolet light for eight weeks decreased inflammation and helped protect collagen from damage.
        8. May help protect against cancer - Several antioxidants in berries, including anthocyanins, ellagic acid, and resveratrol, may reduce cancer risk. Specifically, animal and human studies suggest that berries may protect against cancer of the esophagus, mouth, breast, and colon. In a study in 20 people with colon cancer, eating 2 ounces (60 grams) of freeze-dried raspberries for 1–9 weeks improved tumor markers in some participants, though not all. Another test-tube study found that all types of strawberries had strong, protective effects on liver cancer cells, regardless of whether they were high or low in antioxidants.
        9. Can be enjoyed on nearly all types of diets - Berries can be included in many kinds of diets. Though people on low-carb and ketogenic diets often avoid fruit, you can usually enjoy berries in moderation. For example, a half-cup serving of blackberries (70 grams) or raspberries (60 grams) contains less than 4 grams of digestible carbs. Liberal amounts of berries can be incorporated into paleo, Mediterranean, vegetarian, and vegan diets.For people who want to lose weight, the few calories in berries make them ideal to include in meals, snacks, or desserts. Organic and wild berries are now widely available in many parts of the world. When they are not in season, frozen berries can be purchased and thawed as needed. The only people who need to avoid berries are those who require a low-fiber diet for certain digestive disorders, as well as individuals who are allergic to berries. Allergic reactions to strawberries are most common.
        10. May help keep your arteries healthy - In addition to lowering cholesterol, berries provide other benefits for heart health, including improving the function of your arteries. The cells that line your blood vessels are called endothelial cells. They help control blood pressure, keep blood from clotting, and perform other important functions. Excessive inflammation can damage these cells, inhibiting proper function. This is referred to as endothelial dysfunction, a major risk factor for heart disease. Berries have been found to improve endothelial function in studies in healthy adults, individuals with metabolic syndrome, and people who smoke. In a controlled study in 44 people with metabolic syndrome, those consuming a daily blueberry smoothie showed significant improvements in endothelial function, compared to the control group. Though fresh berries are considered healthiest, berries in processed form may still provide some heart-healthy benefits. Baked berry products are considered processed, whereas freeze-dried berries are not. One study found that although baking blueberries reduced their anthocyanin content, total antioxidant concentrations remained the same. Arterial function improved similarly in people who consumed baked or freeze-dried berries.
        11. Delicious alone or in healthy recipes - Berries are undeniably delicious. They make a wonderful snack or dessert, whether you use one type or a mix of two or more. Though they are naturally sweet and require no additional sweetener, adding a bit of heavy or whipped cream can transform them into a more elegant dessert. For breakfast, try berries topped with either plain Greek yogurt, cottage cheese, or ricotta cheese, along with some chopped nuts. Another way to include berries in your diet is as part of a salad.
    </string>
    <string name="cherries_details">
        Cherries are a good source of fibre, vitamins and minerals, including potassium, calcium, vitamin A and folic acid. They are also well known for their antioxidant properties. A portion of 14 cherries counts as one of your five-a-day.
        Antioxidants are vital for good health as they protect our cells from damage caused by oxidants, or free radicals. Cherries contain antioxidants known as anthocyanins and cyanidin which may have anti-inflammatory effects and initial research has shown that these antioxidants could be beneficial in inflammatory conditions such as arthritis, although more research is needed to replicate these results in human studies.
        Research by the British Journal of Nutrition found that cherry juice may help reduce blood pressure due to its high polyphenol content.
        There has been a fair amount of research over the years into cherries, and specifically tart cherries, and the role they can play in exercise and exercise recovery. Research by the Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition found that drinking tart cherry juice for seven days before and during a strenuous running event minimised post-run muscle pain. Another small study found that tart cherry juice appears to aid recovery and muscle function after strenuous exercise.
        Tart cherries contain high concentrations of key phytochemicals including melatonin which is involved in the regulation of our sleep cycles. There has been slightly mixed research as to whether cherries, and specifically cherry juice, is of benefit to those who have trouble sleeping but the signs are encouraging. Research by the European Journal of Nutrition found that tart cherry juice is beneficial in improving sleep both in quality and duration, and may be of benefit to those who have disturbed sleep, whilst another small study suggests that cherry juice may be beneficial to those with insomnia.
        There has been some research into the effects of cherry juice on gout. One study demonstrated that consuming cherries and cherry juice over a two-day period is associated with a lower risk of gout attacks while another study suggests that cherry juice needs to be consumed for at least four months to reduce acute attacks. Further research suggests that drinking cherry juice lowers the blood uric acid levels (which can trigger an attack of gout) in healthy volunteers. However, as the NHS points out, these results have not yet been replicated in a large-scale study involving participants with gout. Currently, more research needs to be carried out before we can say that cherry juice prevents or eases gout.
    </string>

    <!--Vegetables-->
    <string name="squash_details">
        Squash is one of the most versatile and delicious foods available throughout the world, and it packs a serious punch in terms of health and medicinal benefits. Different varieties of squash have the ability to improve vision, aid in skin care, strengthen the immune system, prevent cancer, manage symptoms of diabetes, build strong bones, protect heart health, and reduce the symptoms of insomnia. It also helps prevent inflammatory conditions, relieves symptoms of arthritis, eliminates ulcers, eliminates parasites and infections, improves prostate health, protects against birth defects, boosts respiratory health, and reduces blood pressure.
        Nutritional Value of Squash - Squash has a very rich nutritional profile that consists of various organic compounds, nutrients, vitamins, and minerals, which are responsible for providing all its impressive health benefits. This list includes a huge amount of vitamin A, as well as significant amounts of vitamin C, vitamin E, vitamin B6, niacin, thiamin, pantothenic acid, and folate. In terms of minerals, squash contains magnesium, potassium, manganese, copper, phosphorus, calcium, and iron. It is also a very good source of carotenoids and other important anti-inflammatory and antioxidant compounds.
        Health Benefits of Squash - Boosts Immunity - Squash is an important source of many nutrients, including vitamin C, magnesium, and other antioxidant compounds. These vitamins and minerals are important antioxidant components in the body, which help to neutralize free radicals throughout the body. Free radicals are the dangerous by-products of cellular metabolism, and they have been connected with a wide swath of illnesses, including cancer, heart diseases, and premature aging. According to the American Institute for Cancer Research, intake of winter squash helps lower cancer risk. Furthermore, it contains very high levels of vitamin A, including carotenoid phytonutrients like lutein and zeaxanthin. All of this together helps the body boost its immune response and defend against foreign substances, as well as the free radicals produced by our own body that may do us harm over the long term.
        Manages Diabetes - Proper, regulated metabolism of sugar in the body is the best way to manage the symptoms of diabetes, a disease which afflicts millions of people all around the world. Squash is a great source of B-complex vitamins, all of which are essential in metabolic activity. Furthermore, certain types of squash contain good amounts of dietary fiber, including the polysaccharide known as pectin. According to The Nutrition Source, Harvard TH Chan School of Public Health, winter squash has a very low glycemic index, which stabilizes sugar levels. Pectin is an essential element in blood sugar regulation throughout the body, making sure that the insulin and glucose activities within the body remain constant and smooth. This ensures proper function of different organ systems and a reduction in the plunges and peaks that can make the life of diabetics difficult.
        Anti-inflammatory Capacity - Although talking about inflammation usually includes a discussion of arthritis or gout, it can occur throughout the body and is often a symptom of other conditions, like a fever that is a signal of an infection attacking the body. The anti-inflammatory activity of squash is due to the presence of omega-3 fatty acids, carotenoids like lutein, zeaxanthin, and beta-carotene, as well as somewhat unusual anti-inflammatory polysaccharides called homogalacturonan. Although anti-inflammatory effects can certainly extend to arthritis and gout, studies on squash have specifically linked its impact to reducing gastric and duodenal ulcer reduction, as well as to general anti-inflammation of the cardiovascular system. Inflammation in the body is closely linked to type-2 diabetes, which is yet another way in which it can help those suffering from that condition.
        Prevents Infections - The natural immune-boosting ability of squash is great for general illnesses, but specific toxins and foreign bodies can also cause serious health issues. The seeds of squash can also be eaten or chewed to get a number of health benefits. These seeds have been directly connected to antiparasitic, antimicrobial, and antifungal activity within the body, protecting us from a wide variety of diseases, including tapeworms and other intestinal parasites.
        Improves Lung Health - The vitamin in highest quantities within squash is vitamin A, and studies have linked vitamin A to a reduction in emphysema, particularly for those who are consistently exposed to carcinogens like cigarette smokes. There is also an important carotenoid called beta-cryptoxanthin that has been linked to a reduction in the occurrence of lung cancer. Lung cancer is one of the most common forms of this terrible disease, so an increase in foods that contain vitamin A can be a very important protective element.
        Prevents Neural Tube Defects - Squash has significant levels of folate, which has long been known as an essential vitamin for pregnant women. Folic acid, or folate, is integral in developing the neural aspects of infant health. Neural tube defects have been directly linked to a deficiency in folic acid, so adding squash to your diet is always a good idea.
        Protects Heart Health - The magnesium and potassium present in squash combine to form a very effective defense line against cardiovascular issues. Potassium is a vasodilator, which means that it relaxes the tension of blood vessels and arteries, thereby increasing blood flow and reducing the stress on the heart. This also increases oxygenation to various organs of the body and improves their functioning. The fiber, including pectin, found in squash is very good at scraping excess cholesterol from the walls of arteries, thereby reducing the chances of atherosclerosis, heart attack, and stroke. Finally, the high levels of folate in squash are able to neutralize harmful levels of homocysteine that builds up in the body. Homocysteine has been linked to increased chances of developing cardiovascular diseases.
        Relieves Symptoms of Asthma - The antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties of squash have been linked to a reduction in asthmatic conditions, primarily because the irritation that causes asthma can be eliminated by eating a diet that includes this vegetable.
        Regulates Blood Circulation - Many varieties of squash have high levels of iron and copper, both of which are essential components of red blood cells. What this means is that with enough squash in your diet, you can reduce your chances of developing anemia (iron deficiency) and you can generally increase circulation within your bloodstream, which can increase oxygenation, brain function, and overall energy levels.
        Improves Vision - It may be hard to believe, but a single serving of squash can contain more than 400 percent of your daily requirement for vitamin A, due to the massive amount of beta-carotene found in it. Beta-carotene can actually be split by an enzyme to form vitamin A, but the body will only convert as much as is necessary. In other words, eating this wonderful vegetable will give your body all the vitamin A it needs, with plenty of beta-carotene to spare. Beta-carotene is an antioxidant compound essential for good eye health. High levels of beta-carotene have been connected with reduced chances of macular degeneration, cataracts, glaucoma, and other vision issues.
        Strengthens Bones - The high levels of essential vitamins found in squash make it a very important part of developing bone matter and bone mineral density. Squash is a valuable source of zinc, calcium, manganese, and other very important trace elements, according to a Michigan State University Extension report. This can help reduce your chances of developing osteoporosis as you age and ensure the strength and durability of your bones.
    </string>
    <string name="zucchini_details">
        Zucchini has been used in folk medicine to treat colds, aches, and various health conditions.
        1. Rich in Many Nutrients - Zucchini is rich in several vitamins, minerals, and other beneficial plant compounds. It also contains small amounts of iron, calcium, zinc, and several other B vitamins. In particular, its ample vitamin A content may support your vision and immune system. Raw zucchini offers a similar nutrition profile as cooked zucchini, but with less vitamin A and more vitamin C, a nutrient which tends to be reduced by cooking.
        2. High in Antioxidants - Antioxidants are beneficial plant compounds that help protect your body from damage by free radicals. Carotenoids, such as lutein, zeaxanthin, and beta-carotene, are particularly plentiful in zucchini. These may benefit your eyes, skin, and heart, as well as offer some protection against certain types of cancer, such as prostate cancer. Research indicates that the skin of the plant harbors the highest levels of antioxidants. Yellow zucchinis may contain slightly higher levels than light green ones.
        3. Contributes to Healthy Digestion - Zucchini may promote healthy digestion in several ways. For starters, it’s rich in water, which can soften stools. This makes them easier to pass and reduces your chances of constipation. Zucchini also contains both soluble and insoluble fiber. Insoluble fiber adds bulk to stools and helps food move through your gut more easily, further reducing constipation risk. This benefit is compounded if you have enough fluids in your diet. Meanwhile, soluble fiber feeds the beneficial bacteria living in your gut. In turn, these friendly bacteria produce short-chain fatty acids (SCFAs) that nourish your gut cells. Whats more, SCFAs may help reduce inflammation and symptoms of certain gut disorders, such as irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), Crohns disease, and ulcerative colitis.
        4. May Reduce Blood Sugar Levels - Zucchini may help lower blood sugar levels in people with type 2 diabetes. At 3 grams of carbs per cooked cup (232 grams), zucchini provides a great low-carb alternative to pasta for those looking to reduce carb intake. It can be spiralized or sliced to replace spaghetti, linguini, or lasagna noodles in dishes. Low-carb diets can significantly lower blood sugar and insulin levels, both of which may keep blood sugar levels stable and reduce the need for medication in people with type 2 diabetes. Whats more, zucchinis fiber helps stabilize blood sugar, preventing levels from spiking after meals. Diets rich in fiber from fruits and vegetables — including zucchini — are consistently linked to a lower risk of type 2 diabetes. The fiber found in zucchini may also help increase insulin sensitivity, which can help stabilize blood sugar as well. Additionally, animal studies note that zucchini peel extract may help reduce blood sugar and insulin levels. This may be due to the skins potent antioxidants.
        5. May Improve Heart Health - Its high fiber content may be largely responsible. Observational studies show that people who eat more fiber have a lower risk of heart disease. Pectin, one type of soluble fiber found in zucchini, appears particularly effective at reducing total and bad LDL cholesterol levels. Zucchini is also rich in potassium, which may help reduce high blood pressure by dilating your blood vessels. Healthier blood pressure is linked to a lower risk of heart disease and stroke. Moreover, diets rich in carotenoids, likewise found in zucchini, appear particularly protective against heart disease.
        6. May Strengthen Your Vision - Adding zucchini to your diet may aid your vision. That is partly because zucchini is rich in vitamin C and beta-carotene — two nutrients important for eye health. Zucchini also contains the antioxidants lutein and zeaxanthin. Research shows that these antioxidants can accumulate in your retina, improving your vision and reducing your risk of age-related eye diseases. This may include a lower risk of macular degeneration, which is the leading cause of irreversible vision loss in older adults. In addition, diets high in lutein and zeaxanthin may also lower your likelihood of developing cataracts, a clouding of the lens which can lead to poor eyesight.
        7. May Aid Weight Loss - Regular consumption of zucchini may help you lose weight. This fruit is rich in water and has a low calorie density, which may help you feel full. Its fiber content may also reduce hunger and keep your appetite at bay. Moreover, studies consistently link high fruit and vegetable intake to weight loss and a slower rate of weight gain over time. Whats more, intake of non-starchy, dark green or yellow vegetables, with similar nutrition profiles to zucchini, appears particularly beneficial to weight loss.
        8. Bone health - Zucchini is rich in the antioxidants lutein and zeaxanthin, as well as vitamin K and magnesium, all of which can help strengthen bones.
        9. Anticancer effects - Test-tube and animal studies indicate that zucchini extracts may help kill or limit the growth of certain cancer cells. However, human research is needed.
        10. A healthy prostate -  Animal research shows that zucchini seed extracts may help limit prostatic hyperplasia, an enlargement of the prostate that commonly causes urinary and sexual difficulties in older men.
        11.Thyroid function - Testing in rats reveals that zucchini peel extracts may help keep thyroid hormone levels stable. That said, research in humans is needed.
        12. Easy to Add to Your Diet - Zucchini is incredibly versatile and can be eaten raw or cooked.
    </string>
    <string name="amaranth_greens_details">
        Botanically, amaranth species meant for its leaves are different from those grown for the purpose of grains (pseudocereals). Vegetable amaranths distinguished by features like short spike inflorescence, glossy, brownish-black seed, and indeterminate growth habit. A. tricolor and A. dubius are some of the important leafy-amaranths. Grain Amaranths are characterized by apical large inflorescence comprising aggregates of cymes and white or cream colored seeds. Grain Amaranths includes A. hypochondriacus, A. caudatus, A. cruentus, etc.
        Health Benefits of Amaranth Greens - Amaratnh leaves are storehouse for many phytonutrients, antioxidants, minerals and vitamins which contribute immensely to health and wellness.
        Its greens carry just 23 calories or 100g. Amaranth leaves contain only traces of fats and no cholesterol.
        The leaves and stems carry a good amount of soluble and insoluble dietary fibers. For the same reason, leafy greens including amaranth often recommended by dieticians in the cholesterol controlling and weight reduction programs.
        Fresh 100 g of leaf amaranth contains 29 percent DRI of iron. Iron is an essential trace element required by the human body for red blood cell (RBCs) production and as a co-factor for the oxidation-reduction enzyme, cytochrome oxidase during the cellular metabolism.
        Fresh amaranth leaves are one of the richest sources of vitamin-C. 100 g of fresh leaves carry 43.3 mg or 70 percent of recommended daily intake of this vitamin. Vitamin-C is a powerful water-soluble antioxidant which plays a vital role in wound healing and help fight against viral infections.
        Amaranth has several vital antioxidant vitamins like vitamin-A (2917 IU or over 97 percent of daily recommended levels per 100 g) and flavonoid polyphenolic antioxidants such as lutein, zeaxanthin, and β-carotene. Together, these compounds help act as protective scavengers against oxygen-derived free radicals and reactive oxygen species (ROS), and thereby play a healing role in aging and various disease processes.
        In addition, vitamin-A is essential for maintaining healthy mucosa and skin, and is essential factor for ocular (eye) health. Consumption of natural vegetables and fruits rich in vitamin-A and flavonoids are also known to help the body protect from lung and oral cavity cancers.
        Amaranth greens perhaps have the highest concentrations of vitamin-K of all the edible green-leafy vegetables. 100 g of fresh greens provides 1140 μg or 950 percent of daily vitamin-K requirements. Vitamin-K plays a vital role in strengthening the bone mass by promoting osteoblastic activity in the bone cells. Additionally, it also has an established role in patients with Alzheimers disease by limiting neuronal damage in the brain.
        Amaranth greens also contains ample amounts of B-complex vitamins such as folates, vitamin-B6 (pyridoxine), riboflavin, thiamin (vitamin B-1), and niacin. Folates rich diet help prevent neural tube defects in the newborns.
        Moreover, its leaves carry more potassium than that of in the spinach. Potassium is an important component of the cell and body fluids that helps regulate heart rate and blood pressure.
        Additionally, it has higher levels of other minerals than spinach such as calcium, manganese, magnesium, copper and zinc. The human body uses manganese and copper as a co-factor for the antioxidant enzyme, superoxide dismutase. Copper is also required for the production of red blood cells. Zinc is a co-factor for many enzymes that regulate growth and development, digestion and nucleic acid synthesis.
        In a way similar to other kinds of greens like spinach, kale, etc., amaranth in the diet helps prevent osteoporosis (weakness of bones), iron-deficiency anemia.
    </string>
    <string name="asparagus_details">
        Asparagus, officially known as Asparagus officinalis, is a member of the lily family.
        This popular vegetable comes in a variety of colors, including green, white and purple. It is used in dishes around the world, including frittatas, pastas and stir-fries.
        Asparagus is also low in calories and packed with essential vitamins, minerals and antioxidants.
        1. Many Nutrients But Few Calories - Asparagus is low in calories but boasts an impressive nutrient profile. Asparagus also possesses small amounts of other micronutrients, including iron, zinc and riboflavin. It is an excellent source of vitamin K, an essential nutrient involved in blood clotting and bone health. In addition, asparagus is high in folate, a nutrient that is vital for a healthy pregnancy and many important processes in the body, including cell growth and DNA formation.
        2. Good Source of Antioxidants - Antioxidants are compounds that help protect your cells from the harmful effects of free radicals and oxidative stress. Oxidative stress contributes to aging, chronic inflammation and many diseases, including cancer. Asparagus, like other green vegetables, is high in antioxidants. These include vitamin E, vitamin C and glutathione, as well as various flavonoids and polyphenols. Asparagus is particularly high in the flavonoids quercetin, isorhamnetin and kaempferol. These substances have been found to have blood pressure-lowering, anti-inflammatory, antiviral and anticancer effects in a number of human, test-tube and animal studies. What is more, purple asparagus contains powerful pigments called anthocyanins, which give the vegetable its vibrant color and have antioxidant effects in the body. In fact, increasing anthocyanin intake has been shown to reduce blood pressure and the risk of heart attacks and heart disease.
        3. Can Improve Digestive Health - Dietary fiber is essential for good digestive health. Just half a cup of asparagus contains 1.8 grams of fiber, which is 7 percent of your daily needs. Studies suggest that a diet high in fiber-rich fruits and vegetables may help reduce the risk of high blood pressure, heart disease and diabetes. Asparagus is particularly high in insoluble fiber, which adds bulk to stool and supports regular bowel movements. It also contains a small amount of soluble fiber, which dissolves in water and forms a gel-like substance in the digestive tract. Soluble fiber feeds the friendly bacteria in the gut, such as Bifidobacteria and Lactobacillus. Increasing the number of these beneficial bacteria plays a role in strengthening the immune system and producing essential nutrients like vitamins B12 and K2.
        4. Helps Support a Healthy Pregnancy  - Asparagus is an excellent source of folate, also known as vitamin B9. Just half a cup of asparagus provides adults with 34 percent of their daily folate needs and pregnant women with 22 percent of their daily needs. Folate is an essential nutrient that helps form red blood cells and produce DNA for healthy growth and development. It is especially important during the early stages of pregnancy to ensure the healthy development of the baby. Getting enough folate from sources like asparagus, green leafy vegetables and fruit can protect against neural tube defects, including spina bifida. Neural tube defects can lead to a range of complications, ranging from learning difficulties to lack of bowel and bladder control to physical disabilities. In fact, adequate folate is so vital during pre-pregnancy and early pregnancy that folate supplements are recommended to ensure women meet their requirements.
        5. Helps Lower Blood Pressure -High blood pressure affects more than 1.3 billion people worldwide and is a major risk factor for heart disease and stroke. Research suggests that increasing potassium intake while reducing salt intake is an effective way to lower high blood pressure. Potassium lowers blood pressure in two ways - by relaxing the walls of blood vessels and excreting excess salt through urine. Asparagus is a good source of potassium, providing 6 percent of your daily requirement in a half-cup serving.
        6. Can Help You Lose Weight - Currently, no studies have tested the effects of asparagus on weight loss. However, it has a number of properties that could potentially help you lose weight. First, it is very low in calories, with only 20 calories in half a cup. This means you can eat a lot of asparagus without taking in a lot of calories. Furthermore, it is about 94 percent water. Research suggests that consuming low-calorie, water-rich foods is associated with weight loss. Asparagus is also rich in fiber, which has been linked to lower body weight and weight loss.
        7. Easy to Add to Your Diet - In addition to being nutritious, asparagus is delicious and easy to incorporate into your diet. It can be cooked in a variety of ways, including boiling, grilling, steaming, roasting and sautéing. You can also purchase canned asparagus, which is precooked and ready to eat.
    </string>
    <string name="bell_peppers_details">
        Bell peppers (Capsicum annuum) are also called sweet peppers or capsicums, bell peppers can be eaten either raw or cooked. Like their close relatives, chili peppers, bell peppers are sometimes dried and powdered. In that case, they are referred to as paprika. They are low in calories and exceptionally rich in vitamin C and other antioxidants, making them an excellent addition to a healthy diet. Bell peppers come in various colors, such as red, yellow, orange, and green, which are unripe. Green, unripe peppers have a slightly bitter flavor and are not as sweet as fully ripe ones.
        Nutrition facts - Fresh, raw bell peppers are mainly composed of water (92 percent). The rest is carbs and small amounts of protein and fat. Bell peppers are primarily composed of carbs, which account for most of their calorie content, with 3.5 ounces (100 grams) holding 6 grams of carbs. The carbs are mostly sugars, such as glucose and fructose — which are responsible for the sweet taste of ripe bell peppers. Bell peppers also contain small amounts of fiber, 2 percent by fresh weight. Calorie for calorie, they are a very good fiber source.
        Vitamins and minerals - Vitamin C - One medium-sized red bell pepper provides 169 percent of the Reference Daily Intake (RDI) for vitamin C, making it one of the richest dietary sources of this essential nutrient.
        Vitamin B6 - Pyridoxine is the most common type of vitamin B6, which is a family of nutrients important for the formation of red blood cells.
        Vitamin K1 - A form of vitamin K, also known as phylloquinone, K1 is important for blood clotting and bone health.
        Potassium - This essential mineral may improve heart health.
        Folate - Also known as vitamin B9, folate has a variety of functions in your body. Adequate folate intake is very important during pregnancy.
        Vitamin E - A powerful antioxidant, vitamin E is essential for healthy nerves and muscles. The best dietary sources of this fat-soluble vitamin are oils, nuts, seeds, and vegetables.
        Vitamin A - Red bell peppers are high in pro-vitamin A (beta carotene), which your body converts into vitamin A.
        Other plant compounds - Bell peppers are rich in various antioxidants, especially carotenoids, which are much more abundant in ripe specimens.
        Capsanthin - Especially high in red bell peppers, capsanthin is a powerful antioxidant responsible for their brilliant red color.
        Violaxanthin - This compound is the most common carotenoid antioxidant in yellow bell peppers.
        Lutein - While abundant in green (unripe) bell peppers and black paprika, lutein is absent from ripe bell peppers. Adequate intake of lutein may improve eye health.
        Quercetin - Studies indicate that this polyphenol antioxidant may be beneficial for preventing certain chronic conditions, such as heart disease and cancer.
        Luteolin - Similarly to quercetin, luteolin is an polyphenol antioxidant that may have a variety of beneficial health effects.
        Health benefits of bell peppers - Eye health - Lutein and zeaxanthin, carotenoids found in relatively high amounts in bell peppers, may improve eye health when consumed in adequate amounts. In fact, they protect your retina, the light-sensitive inner wall of your eye, from oxidative damage. A number of studies indicate that regular consumption of foods rich in these carotenoids may cut the risk of both cataracts and macular degeneration. Thus, adding bell peppers to your diet may help lower your risk of visual impairments.
        Anemia prevention - Anemia is a common condition characterized by a reduced ability of your blood to carry oxygen. One of the most common causes of anemia is iron deficiency, the main symptoms of which are weakness and tiredness. Not only are red bell peppers a decent source of iron, they are also exceptionally rich in vitamin C, which increases the absorption of iron from your gut. In fact, one medium-sized red bell pepper may contain 169 percent of the RDI for vitamin C. Dietary iron absorption increases significantly when you consume fruits or vegetables high in vitamin C.
    </string>
    <string name="chayote_details">
        Chayote (Sechium edule) is a type of squash that belongs to the gourd family Cucurbitaceae.
        Chayote is loaded with an array of nutrients and antioxidant compounds that provide many potential health benefits.
        1. Rich in nutrients - One of the greatest attributes of chayote squash is its nutrition content, as it offers various essential vitamins, minerals, and fiber. Notably, chayote is particularly high in folate, which promotes proper cell division. Alongside its nutrient density, chayote also happens to be low in calories, fat, sodium, and total carbs. As such, its quite healthy and makes for a good fit for various diets.
        2. Contains potent antioxidants - Antioxidants are compounds found in a variety of foods that protect against cellular damage, reduce inflammation, and lower stress within your body. Chayote squash provides the antioxidants quercetin, myricetin, morin, and kaempferol. Of these, myricetin occurs in the highest amounts. Research suggests that myricetin carries strong anticancer, antidiabetes, and anti-inflammatory properties. Additionally, chayote squash is an excellent source of vitamin C, which serves as an antioxidant in your body.
        3. May promote heart health - Eating chayote squash may improve several heart disease risk factors, such as high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and poor blood flow. Animal and test-tube research indicates that chayote compounds may help relax blood vessels, thereby improving blood flow and reducing blood pressure. Myricetin, a prominent antioxidant in chayote squash, has also been shown to lower cholesterol in some animal studies. Moreover, this squash is a good source of fiber, providing about 14 percent of the RDI. Higher intake of fiber-rich foods like chayote is associated with a reduced risk of heart disease.
        4. May promote blood sugar control - Chayote squash is low in total carbs and high in soluble fiber, which may help regulate blood sugar levels. Soluble fiber slows down your digestion and absorption of carbs, which reduces your blood sugar response after eating. Chayote may also improve blood sugar control by affecting insulin. Insulin resistance is a condition that occurs when your cells become less sensitive to insulin, a hormone that regulates blood sugar levels. This leads to progressively higher blood sugar levels and can eventually result in diabetes. Research suggests that unique plant compounds in chayote may play a role in increasing your sensitivity to insulin by reducing the activity of enzymes linked to poor blood sugar control and type 2 diabetes.
        5. May support a healthy pregnancy - Folate, or vitamin B9, is essential for all people — but it is particularly important for those who are pregnant or planning to become pregnant. During early pregnancy, folate is required for proper development of the fetal brain and spinal cord. Adequate folate intake may also play a role in preventing preterm births. Chayote is an excellent source of folate, providing over 40 percent of the RDI in one squash. Thus, including chayote and other folate-rich foods as part of a balanced diet is a great way to support a healthy pregnancy.
        6. May have anticancer effects - Higher fruit and vegetable consumption is associated with a reduced risk of various types of cancer, including those of the digestive tract. Test-tube studies note that certain chayote compounds may slow the growth and progression of some cancer cells, such as those of cervical cancer and leukemia. Although these results are promising, current evidence isn’t strong enough to suggest that chayote has cancer-fighting effects in humans.
        7. May slow visible signs of aging - One of the main theories of aging centers on molecules called free radicals that inflict damage on your cells, ultimately leading to reduced functionality over time. Some research indicates that consuming foods high in antioxidants may slow the aging process by protecting cells from free radical damage. Chayote squash happens to be full of antioxidants, one of which is vitamin C. In addition to its antioxidant capacity, vitamin C is necessary for producing collagen, one of the primary proteins found in your skin. Collagen is often credited with giving skin its firm, youthful appearance. Thus, adequate intake of vitamin-C-rich foods like chayote squash may help reduce visible signs of aging. Whats more, a recent test-tube study revealed a strong protective effect of chayote extract on human skin cells against damage from UV radiation.
        8. May support liver function - Fatty liver disease is a condition in which excess fat is deposited into liver tissue. Too much fat in your liver can affect its ability to function properly. Both test-tube and animal studies suggest that chayote squash extract may protect against fat accumulation in the liver, thus potentially preventing or treating fatty liver disease. In one study, rats fed a high-fat diet and treated with chayote extract had significantly lower cholesterol and fatty acid deposits in their livers than control rats. This was due to apparent changes in the function of enzymes involved in fat metabolism. At this point, more research is needed to understand how chayote squash may support liver health in humans.
        9. May promote a healthy weight - Chayote squash boasts very few calories but a lot of fiber, two attributes which can support a healthy weight. A whole chayote squash (203 grams) provides 39 calories and 4 grams of fiber. Fiber slows down the rate at which your stomach empties, leaving you feeling full and satisfied for longer, which may decrease food intake and promote weight loss. Moreover, research suggests that consumption of dietary fiber may increase fullness hormones like GLP-1 and peptide YY. Thus, adding chayote squash to your diet may help you stay on track with your weight loss goals.
        10. May support digestive health - Your digestive tract is responsible for a variety of essential functions, including detoxification, immunity, and digestion and absorption of nutrients. Consumption of fruits and vegetables like chayote squash can boost digestive function. Flavonoids, plant compounds which support digestion, are found in high amounts in chayote. Research indicates that flavonoid-rich foods aid digestive enzymes involved in the removal and excretion of waste products in your digestive tract. What is more, adequate intake of fiber-rich foods like chayote can encourage healthy intestinal function and maintenance of healthy gut bacteria. In turn, these benefits promote bowel regularity and may play a role in preventing various chronic conditions, such as heart disease, type 2 diabetes, and colon cancer.
    </string>
    <string name="chickpea_details">
        Originally cultivated in the Mediterranean and the Middle East, chickpeas, also known as garbanzo beans, have spread their culinary influence across the world. They also come with a range of potential health benefits.
        Though the most common type of chickpea appears round and beige, other varieties can be black, green, and red.
        Like other legumes, such as beans, peas, and lentils, chickpeas are high in fiber and protein, and contain several key vitamins and minerals.
        Fast facts on chickpeas - Chickpeas are sometimes known as garbanzo beans. They are featured extensively in the Mediterranean diet and Middle-Eastern food. They are a good source of protein, carbohydrates, and fiber. Soak them in water for 8 to 10 hours before cooking for the best results.
        Benefits - 1. Diabetes - Chickpeas are particularly high in fiber. Studies have shown that people with type 1 diabetes who consume high-fiber diets have lower blood glucose levels. For people with type 2 diabetes, higher fiber intake may improve blood sugar, lipid, and insulin levels.
        2. Bone health - The iron, phosphate, calcium, magnesium, manganese, zinc, and vitamin K in chickpeas all contribute to building and maintaining bone structure and strength. Though phosphate and calcium are both important in bone structure, the careful balance of the two minerals is necessary for proper bone mineralization - consumption of too much phosphorus with too little calcium intake can result in bone loss. Bone matrix formation requires the mineral manganese, and iron and zinc play crucial roles in the production and maturation of collagen. Adequate vitamin K consumption is important for good bone health because it improves calcium absorption and may reduce urinary excretion of calcium, making sure that enough calcium is available for building and repairing bone. Low intake of vitamin K is associated with a higher risk for bone fracture.
        3. Blood pressure - Maintaining a low-sodium (low-salt) intake is essential for maintaining a low blood pressure, however increasing potassium intake may be just as important because of its vasodilation effects.
        4. Heart health - The high fiber, potassium, vitamin C, and vitamin B-6 content all support heart health. Chickpeas contain significant amounts of fiber, which helps lower the total amount of cholesterol in the blood, thereby decreasing the risk of heart disease.
        5. Cancer - Although the mineral selenium is not present in most fruits and vegetables, it can be found in chickpeas. It helps the enzymes of the liver to function properly and detoxify some cancer-causing compounds in the body. Additionally, selenium prevents inflammation and decreases tumor growth rates. Chickpeas also contain folate, which plays a role in DNA synthesis and repair, and so helps prevent the formation of cancer cells from mutations in the DNA. Saponins, phytochemicals present in chickpeas, prevent cancer cells from multiplying and spreading throughout the body. High-fiber intakes from chickpeas and other legumes, whole grains, fruits, and vegetables are associated with a lowered risk of colorectal cancer. Vitamin C functions as a powerful antioxidant and helps protect cells against free radical damage.
        6. Cholesterol - Research shows that including chickpeas in the diet lowers the amount of low-density lipoprotein, or bad cholesterol, in the blood.
        7. Inflammation - The choline in chickpeas helps with sleep, muscle movement, learning, and memory. Choline also helps to maintain the structure of cellular membranes, aids in the transmission of nerve impulses, assists in the absorption of fat and reduces chronic inflammation.
        8. Digestion and regularity - Because of their high fiber content, chickpeas help to prevent constipation and promote regularity for a healthful digestive tract.
        9. Weight management and satiety - Many studies have suggested that increasing consumption of plant foods like chickpeas decreases the risk of obesity, overall mortality, diabetes, heart disease, promotes a healthful complexion, healthful hair, increased energy, and overall lower weight.
        10. Irritable bowel syndrome - Although chickpeas do not ease the symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome, they can be helpful to people affected by the condition. Patsy Catsos, a registered dietitian and author of IBS - Free at Last suggests that increasing fiber consumption in individuals who have irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) can be a challenge. However, chickpeas offer a source of fiber that is well-tolerated by some IBS patients.
        Nutrition - One cup of cooked chickpeas contains - 269 calories, 45 g of carbohydrate, 15 g of protein, 13 g of dietary fiber, 4 g of fat, 0 g of cholesterol.
        Additionally, chickpeas contain vitamin K, folate, phosphorus, zinc, copper, manganese, choline, and selenium. Besides being an excellent vegan and gluten-free source of protein and fiber, chickpeas also contain exceptional levels of iron, vitamin B-6, and magnesium.
        Note - it is not recommended to eat raw chickpeas, or any other pulses due to the content of toxins and anti-nutrients. These components are reduced with sprouting and cooking.
    </string>
    <string name="tomatoes_details">
        The tomato (Solanum lycopersicum) is a fruit from the nightshade family native to South America. Despite botanically being a fruit, it is generally eaten and prepared like a vegetable. Tomatoes are the major dietary source of the antioxidant lycopene, which has been linked to many health benefits, including reduced risk of heart disease and cancer. They are also a great source of vitamin C, potassium, folate, and vitamin K.
        Nutrition facts - The water content of tomatoes is around 95 percent. The other 5 percent consists mainly of carbohydrates and fiber. Carbs - Carbs comprise 4 percent of raw tomatoes, which amounts to fewer than 5 grams of carbs for a medium specimen (123 grams).
        Fiber - Tomatoes are a good source of fiber, providing about 1.5 grams per average-sized tomato. Most of the fibers (87 percent) in tomatoes are insoluble, in the form of hemicellulose, cellulose, and lignin.
        Tomatoes are a good source of several vitamins and minerals - Vitamin C - This vitamin is an essential nutrient and antioxidant. One medium-sized tomato can provide about 28 percent of the Reference Daily Intake (RDI). Potassium - An essential mineral, potassium is beneficial for blood pressure control and heart disease prevention. Vitamin K1 - Also known as phylloquinone, vitamin K is important for blood clotting and bone health. Folate (vitamin B9) - One of the B vitamins, folate is important for normal tissue growth and cell function. It is particularly important for pregnant women.
        The main plant compounds in tomatoes are - Lycopene - A red pigment and antioxidant, lycopene has been extensively studied for its beneficial health effects.
        Beta carotene - An antioxidant that often gives foods a yellow or orange hue, beta carotene is converted into vitamin A in your body.
        Naringenin - Found in tomato skin, this flavonoid has been shown to decrease inflammation and protect against various diseases in mice.
        Chlorogenic acid - A powerful antioxidant compound, chlorogenic acid may lower blood pressure in people with elevated levels.
        Chlorophylls and carotenoids like lycopene are responsible for the rich color of tomatoes. When the ripening process starts, the chlorophyll (green) is degraded and carotenoids (red) are synthesized.
        Health benefits of tomatoes - Heart health - Heart disease, including heart attacks and strokes, is the worlds most common cause of death. A study in middle-aged men linked low blood levels of lycopene and beta-carotene to increased risk of heart attacks and strokes. Increasing evidence from clinical trials suggests that supplementing with lycopene may help lower LDL (bad) cholesterol. Clinical studies of tomato products indicate benefits against inflammation and markers of oxidative stress. They also show a protective effect on the inner layer of blood vessels and may decrease your risk of blood clotting.
        Cancer prevention - Cancer is the uncontrolled growth of abnormal cells that spread beyond their normal boundaries, often invading other parts of the body. Observational studies have noted links between tomatoes, and tomato products, and fewer incidences of prostate, lung, and stomach cancers. While the high lycopene content is believed responsible, high-quality human research needed to confirm the cause of these benefits. A study in women shows that high concentrations of carotenoids, found in high amounts in tomatoes, may protect against breast cancer.
        Skin health - Tomatoes are considered beneficial for skin health. Tomato-based foods rich in lycopene and other plant compounds may protect against sunburn.
    </string>
    <string name="kale_details">
        The nutrients it contains support healthy skin, hair, and bones. The fiber content enhances digestion and contributes to cardiovascular health. With more nutritional value than spinach, it may help improve blood glucose control in diabetes, lower the risk of cancer, reduce blood pressure, and help prevent the development of asthma.
        Fast facts on kale - Kale is a green, leafy, winter vegetable that is high in fiber. The potassium content of kale may help reduce the risk of heart disease. It can be a tasty and nutritious side dish or an addition to smoothies and salads. Anyone who is taking blood thinning medication or who has a kidney problem should check with a doctor before adding more kale to the diet.
        Benefits - The nutrients in kale can help boost wellbeing and prevent a range of health problems. It contains fiber, antioxidants, calcium, and vitamin K, among others. Even the chlorophyll in kale may have health benefits. It is also a good source of vitamin C and iron.
        Diabetes - The fiber and antioxidants in kale may offer protection against diabetes. Fiber - Studies have shown that a high intake of fiber may lower blood glucose levels in people with type-1 diabetes. Those with type-2 diabetes may see improved blood sugar, lipids, and insulin levels. One cup of chopped fresh kale, weighing about 16 grams (g), provides 0.6 g of fiber. A cup of cooked kale (about 130 g) provides 2.6 g of fiber.
        Antioxidants - Kale contains an antioxidant known as alpha-lipoic acid. Studies suggest that this can help lower glucose levels, increase insulin sensitivity, and prevent oxidative stress-induced changes in patients with diabetes. It may also decrease peripheral neuropathy and autonomic neuropathy in these patients. Most studies have used high doses of alpha-lipoic acid administered intravenously, rather than dietary sources. Nevertheless, kale can contribute to a healthy daily intake of this nutrient, which is also produced in our bodies naturally.
        Heart disease - The fiber, potassium, vitamin C, and vitamin B6 found in kale all support heart health. Increasing potassium intake while decreasing sodium intake is recommended to reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). A high potassium intake is also associated with a reduced risk of stroke, protection against loss of muscle mass, preservation of bone mineral density, and reduction in the formation of kidney stones. For lowering blood pressure, consuming more potassium may be as important as decreasing sodium intake, because potassium dilates the blood vessels.
        Kale can help boost this intake - One cup of chopped fresh kale provides 79 mg of potassium. One cup of cooked kale provides 296 mg of potassium. A high potassium intake is associated with a 20 percent lower risk of dying from all causes.
        Cancer - Kale and other green vegetables that contain chlorophyll can help prevent the body from absorbing heterocyclic amines. These chemicals are produced when grilling animal-derived foods at a high temperature, and they are associated with cancer. Although the human body cannot absorb much chlorophyll, the chlorophyll in kale binds to these carcinogens and prevents the body from absorbing them. In this way, it may help limit the risk of cancer.
        Bone health - Some research has suggested that a low intake of vitamin K is associated with a higher risk of bone fracture. While the human body creates most of the vitamin K it needs, adequate vitamin K consumption is important for good health. It helps modify bone matrix proteins, improves calcium absorption, and may reduce the amount of calcium excreted in urine. Kale is a good source of vitamin K.
        Digestion - Kale is high in fiber and water. Both of these help prevent constipation and promote regularity and a healthy digestive tract. It also contains B vitamins, and vitamin C, which promotes iron absorption. These are essential for the release of energy from food.
        Healthy skin and hair - Kale is high in beta-carotene, the carotenoid that is converted by the body into vitamin A as needed. A cup of cooked kale provides 885 mcg of retinol A equivalent, or 17,707 International Units (IU) of vitamin A. This nutrient enables all bodily tissues to grow, including skin and hair. It is also essential for the production of sebum, the oil that helps keep skin and hair moisturized. Immune function, eyesight, and reproductive function also rely on vitamin A. A cup of cooked kale also provides 53.3 mg of vitamin C, which is needed to build and maintain collagen, the key protein that provides structure for skin, hair and bones. Vitamin C and iron are also present in kale. Vitamin C helps the body absorb iron. One cup of cooked kale contains 1.17 mg of iron. An adequate intake of iron can help prevent anemia.
        Nutrition - Kale is a green and leafy cruciferous vegetable that is rich in nutrients and fiber. One cup of cooked kale has over 1,000 percent more vitamin C than a cup of cooked spinach. Unlike spinach, kale is low in oxalate, so the calcium and iron it provides are more easily absorbed by the human digestive system.
    </string>
    <string name="lettuce_details">
        The health benefits of lettuce include lower cholesterol levels, protection of neurons, regular sleep, anxiety control, lower inflammation, and a constant supply of antioxidants.
        During medieval times in Europe, lettuce was considered to possess medicinal qualities, which were mentioned in several medieval texts. One can find instances of the plant being prescribed as a medicine for several diseases in the Unani medicine system as well. It was prescribed for bilious eructation, disturbed blood pressure, loss of appetite, insomnia, and was used as a tonic for the intestines and digestive system, and as a method to stop sexual urges.
        The dried latex of lettuce was prescribed for inducing sleep and was used as nasal drops, a sedative, an anti-spasmodic, and an anodyne.
        Lettuce Nutrition Facts - Lettuce contains moisture, energy, protein, fat, carbohydrates, dietary fiber, and sugars. The minerals and vitamins found in it include calcium, iron, magnesium, phosphorus, potassium, sodium, and zinc along with vitamins like thiamin, riboflavin, niacin, folate, vitamin B6, C, A, E, and vitamin K.
        Health Benefits of Lettuce - Anti-inflammatory Agent - Lettuce possesses anti-inflammatory properties that help in controlling inflammation. In experimental models, lettuce extracts have shown significant controlling power over inflammation induced by biocatalysts like lipoxygenase and carrageenan.
        Protects Neuronal Cells - Neurons are brain cells that form physical connections to make up memory. The death of neurons in particular connections or circuits can result in the loss of memory. In some extreme cases, significant neuronal death can result in the onset of diseases like Alzheimers. The extracts from lettuce showed considerable control of neuron cell death due to its role in glucose or serum deprivation (GSD). The research also mentioned that lettuce has the potential to be used in neuroprotection as a common remedy for neurodegenerative diseases.
        Lowers Cholesterol Levels - Lettuce can be beneficial in lowering high cholesterol levels that often lead to cardiovascular diseases and other dangerous conditions. High LDL cholesterol levels are harmful and can cause heart attack and stroke. A study was conducted on mice to test the impact of lettuce consumption on fat and cholesterol. The results indicated a significant reduction of cholesterol levels compared to mice that were not fed lettuce. Lipid peroxidation was observed in most cases, which was concluded to be responsible for this form of cholesterol control.
        Induces Sleep - One of the major traditional uses of lettuce in Unani medicine was as a sleep inducer. Research into the extracts of lettuce resulted in the isolation of a depressant chemical. This chemical, when administered in experimental animals, showed significant sedative effects. A 2013 research report, suggests that the main component(s) responsible for this effect in lettuce is most likely to be the non-polar agent(s),which are found in the n-butanol fraction (NBF)of this plant. Decreased heart rate and ventricular contractions were also observed. This particular chemical acts by blocking the excitatory signal processes of muscular and neural tissues.
        Antioxidant Agent - Munish Garg, Chanchal Garg et al, I.S.F. College of Pharmacy, Moga, Punjab in association with J.S.S. College of Pharmacy, Ooty Tamilnadu, published a study in the Ancient Science of Life Journal that stated that lettuce possesses antioxidants with significant free radical-scavenging capabilities. Antioxidants are a wide range of biochemicals mostly found in our diet, they are also very necessary for human health. Antioxidants act as barriers to free radicals, which are produced during cellular metabolism. These free radicals attack healthy tissues, cells, and the DNA inside them. They can often cause healthy cells to mutate into cancer cells. The result is the development of various diseases. Antioxidants, on the other hand, counteract these free radicals and neutralize them before the free radical attacks take place.
        Antimicrobial Agent - The latex of lettuce possesses antimicrobial properties. Candida albicans and a number of other yeasts were completely deformed upon coming into contact with the latex from lettuce. Biochemicals that are considered to possess these antimicrobial properties are the terpenes and cardenolides, as well as enzymes like glucanases.
        Controls Anxiety - The neurological properties of lettuce have long been suggested and exploited during ancient times and the Middle Ages in medical treaties such as the Unani system. A 2012 research paper published in the Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Disease has led to the conclusion that lettuce possesses anxiolytic properties. When lab animals were given lettuce extracts, their locomotive activity was reduced, suggesting considerable anxiolysis.
        Anti-Cancer Potential - Lettuce leaf extracts can prevent certain types of cancer. According to a research published by the researchers at the Institute of Clinical Pathology, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria, in the Oncology Reports, the water extract of the lettuce Lactuca sativa, and not the ethyl acetate extract, inhibited the growth of leukaemia cells and breast cancer cells. This emphasizes that lettuce has anti-cancer potential. The experiments also suggested that the weight ratio of human lettuce consumption required to kill 50% of leukemia cells would be 3 kg.
    </string>
    <string name="okra_details">
        Okra is a warm-season vegetable, also known as gumbo or ladies fingers. It is a good source of minerals, vitamins, and fiber. It contains a characteristic viscous juice that can be used to thicken sauces.
        It is considered an important crop in many countries, because of its nutritional value, and because many parts of the plant can be used, including the fresh leaves, buds, flowers, pods, stems, and seeds.
        The taste is mild, but it has a unique texture with peach-like fuzz on the outside and small, edible seeds on the inside of the pod.
        It offers a wide range of health benefits - Fast facts about okra - Okra is a green, finger-shaped vegetable with a characteristic viscous juice. It provides fiber, folate, and vitamin K. Its nutritional content means it can promote heart health and strong bones and protect against cancer. Buy okra when it is firm and keep it dry. Store for no more than 3 to 4 days in paper or plastic in a crisper drawer. Cooking it whole makes it the mucilaginous juice, unpopular with some people, less obvious. People who use blood thinners should not eat too much okra, as the vitamin K levels can interact with the drug.
        Nutrition - According to the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) National Nutrient Database, one cup of raw okra, weighing around 100 grams (g) contains - 33 calories, 1.93 g of protein, 0.19 g of fat, 7.45 g of carbohydrate, 3.2 g of fiber, 1.48 g of sugar, 31.3 milligrams (mg) of vitamin K, 299 mg of potassium, 7 mg of sodium, 23 mg of vitamin C, 0.2 mg of thiamin, 57 mg of magnesium, 82 mg of calcium, 0.215 mg of vitamin B6, 60 micrograms (mcg) of folate, 36 mcg of vitamin A.
        Okra also provides some iron, niacin, phosphorus, and copper. Okra is also a source of antioxidants. Okra seeds contain oligomeric catechins and flavonoid derivatives, both of which have been linked to a lower risk of cancer. The gumbo itself contains quercetin derivatives, and both pods and seeds contain phenolic compounds. These compounds are believed to have antioxidant, antimicrobial, and anti-inflammatory properties.
        Benefits - A diet rich in fruits and vegetables can reduce the risk of a range of health conditions, including obesity, diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. The mucilage of okra is also said to bind cholesterol and bile acid. It collects toxins from the liver and carries them out of the body. The nutrients in okra may make it useful for preventing a number of health problems.
        Cancer - Lectin is a type of protein found in okra, beans, peanuts, and grains. Lectin from okra was used in a study to treat human breast cancer cells. The treatment reduced cancer cell growth by 63 percent and killed 72 percent of the human cancer cells. More studies need to be done to see if okra has an effect on cancer in humans.
        Pregnancy and breastfeeding - Folate is important for preventing fetal problems during a pregnancy. Low folate levels can lead to a loss of pregnancy or problems for the child in later life. Low folate levels have been linked to conditions such as spina bifida. Getting enough folate is especially important for women before and during pregnancy, and while breastfeeding.
        Diabetes - In 2011, researchers made a powder from the peel and seeds of okra to treat rats with diabetes. The rats that were treated with the powder had lower blood sugar and fat levels than rats that did not receive the powder. If this affects humans in the same way, it could lead to new therapies.
        Heart health - According to the American Heart Association (AHA), eating foods that are high in fiber can reduce harmful cholesterol levels in the blood. High-fiber foods lower the risk of heart disease, stroke, obesity, and diabetes. Fiber can also slow heart disease in people who already have it.
        Osteoporosis - Foods that are high in vitamin K, such as okra, are good for the bones. Vitamin K helps the bones absorb calcium. In theory, people who eat enough vitamin K are more likely to have strong bones and fewer fractures. Okra and leafy greens such as Swiss chard, arugula, and spinach add vitamin K and calcium to a diet.
        Gastrointestinal health - Dietary fiber helps prevent constipation and maintain a healthy digestive system. Research suggests that the more fiber a person eats, the less chance they have of developing colorectal cancer. Fiber in the diet also helps to reduce appetite, and it may contribute to weight loss. In Asian medicine, okra extract is added to foods to protect against irritation and inflammatory gastric diseases. The anti-inflammatory and antimicrobial action may help protect against gastrointestinal problems.
        Other health-related uses - Okra seeds can also provide oil and protein, and they have been used as a source of oil in small-scale production. In poor regions of the world, the seeds can offer a source of high-quality protein. The viscous extract of okra also has potential for use in medicine, for example, as a tablet binder and a suspending agent in medicines. Another possible medical application of this ingredient is as a serum albumin extender. Research has suggested that it could be used as a plasma replacement or blood volume expander.
    </string>
    <string name="mushroom_details">
        Mushroom Nutrition - The earths soil is home to large populations of natural agents that help promote the environment. One of them is the fungi mushroom, which helps restore pollution-damaged habitats, acts as natural pesticides, and even provides a sustainable fuel called Econol. While mushrooms have the ability to support Mother Nature, they are also capable of promoting your own health, from helping strengthen your immune system to preventing debilitating diseases. Some benefits that you may enjoy from consuming mushrooms are - Weight management – One study showed that substituting red meat with white button mushrooms may support a healthy weight.
        Improved nutrition – Adding more mushrooms to your diet may help improve diet quality. Optimal vitamin D levels– Eating certain mushroom species is seen in a study to be more effective than taking vitamin D2 supplements. Optimal digestive function – Mushrooms support your gastrointestinal health, thanks to their supply of dietary fiber and fungal enzymes. Antibacterial properties – Penicillin, streptomycin, and tetracycline are all derived from fungal extracts.
        Mushrooms contain long-chain polysaccharides, specifically alpha- and beta-glucans. These molecules have beneficial effects on your immune system. In fact, did you know that medications like penicillin, streptomycin, and tetracycline are all derived from fungal extracts.
        Other naturally-occurring compounds like fungal proteins, lectines, peptides, and laccases in mushrooms also support your immune function. In fact, studies show that mushrooms have cancer-fighting and anti-tumor properties.
        Mushrooms are also great sources of protein, fiber, B vitamins (especially niacin), vitamin C, calcium, minerals, and selenium. They also contain antioxidants that are unique to mushrooms, such as ergothioneine, which according to studies is a highly powerful antioxidant. It is produced by fungi and certain mycobacteria found in soils.
        A study published in the journal Nature states that ergothioneine is a derivative of the amino acid histidine. The antioxidant also contains sulfur, which may help protect your DNA from oxidative damage.
        Mushrooms also owe some of their beneficial properties to the mycelium, a cobweb-like structure that is found in nearly all landscapes. Through the mycelia, fungi absorb nutrients from the soil. When two compatible mycelia join, they form mushrooms, which make spores. These spores, which fly away, are responsible for making new mycelial colonies.
        In spite of the many positive effects of mushrooms, Americans consume very limited types. For instance, they consume roughly 900 million pounds of mushrooms per year, but 95 percent of that is just from one species, the button mushrooms.
        At the same time, not all mushrooms may be beneficial to your health. Out of 10,000 species of this fungus, 50 to 100 types are toxic. These can cause symptoms such as gastrointestinal problems, visual issues, palpitations, chills, and kidney and liver failure.  Avoid eating these harmful varieties of mushrooms at all costs.
    </string>
    <string name="wild_arugula_details">
        Arugulas aromatic, peppery flavor adds a wonderful dimension to a salad, to your health and maybe even your sex life. Arugula has been used as an aphrodisiac since the first century. Arugula is also known by other names such as salad rocket, garden rocket, roquette, rucola, rugula or colewort. The scientific name of arugula is Eruca sativa.
        Arugula Health Benefits - 1. Cancer Fighting Powerfood - Arugula is one of the brassica family vegetables along with broccoli, cauliflower and cabbage. These vegetables are high in fiber and antioxidants, and also rich in glucosinolates, which studies show may reduce the risk of developing lung, prostate, breast and pancreatic cancer.
        2. Rich in Chlorophyll - Chlorophyll can help to prevent liver and DNA damage from aflatoxins. To get the most chlorophyll in arugula, it is best to eat it raw.
        3. Hydrating Leafy Green - Arugula is composed of 90 percent water. That is why it is a perfect hydrating and cooling food in the summer.
        4. Good for Bone Health - Vitamin K is needed for bone health; it is needed for the absorption of calcium into the bones and teeth. Half cup of arugula contains 10.9 micrograms of vitamin K. Three cups of arugula daily will supply you with 100 percent of your bodies need of vitamin K. It also contains eight times more calcium than iceberg lettuce.
        5. Helps Reduce Inflammation in the Body - It contains indole-3-carbinol and isothiocyanates, which have been shown to suppress the production of inflammation in the body.
        6. Cleanses and Detoxifies the Body - The fiber content helps clean out the colon promoting healthy bowel movements. The phytochemicals, antioxidants and essential minerals found in arugula help cleanse out toxins in the body.
        7. Protects the Aging Brain From Cognitive Decline - Arugula is high in most B vitamins but contains especially high amounts of folate. In high-functioning older adults, low levels of folate have been shown to be a risk factor for cognitive decline.
        8. Weight Loss - Arugula in your diet can benefit you with so many nutrients. The extra benefit is that two cups contain only 80 calories, making it a good choice for those on a diet.
        9. Aphrodisiac - Arugula has used as an aphrodisiac since the first century. Research has shown us that the trace minerals and antioxidants in dark, leafy greens are essential for our sexual health. They help block environmental contaminants which are thought to be negative to our libido. A study, published March 2013 in the journal of Al-Nahrain University, found that arugula leaf extracts boosted testosterone levels and sperm activity in mice. The results suggest that the phytochemicals and/or nutrients in arugula may have aphrodisiac properties.
    </string>

    <!--Spices and Seasoning-->
    <string name="sage_details">
        Sage is a staple herb in various cuisines around the world. Its other names include common sage, garden sage and Salvia officinalis. It belongs to the mint family, alongside other herbs like oregano, rosemary, basil and thyme. Sage has a strong aroma and earthy flavor, which is why it is typically used in small amounts. Even so, it is packed with a variety of important nutrients and compounds. Sage is also used as a natural cleaning agent, pesticide and ritual object in spiritual sage burning or smudging. This green herb is available fresh, dried or in oil form, and has numerous health benefits.
        1. High in Several Nutrients - Sage packs a healthy dose of vitamins and minerals. One teaspoon (0.7 grams) of ground sage contains - Calories - 2, Protein - 0.1 grams, Carbs - 0.4 grams, Fat - 0.1 grams, Vitamin K - 10% of the reference daily intake (RDI), Iron - 1.1% of the RDI, Vitamin B6 - 1.1% of the RDI, Calcium - 1% of the RDI, Manganese - 1% of the RDI. As you can see, a small amount of sage packs 10% of your daily vitamin K needs. Sage also contains small amounts of magnesium, zinc, copper and vitamins A, C and E. What is more, this aromatic spice houses caffeic acid, chlorogenic acid, rosmarinic acid, ellagic acid and rutin — all of which play a role in its beneficial health effects. Since it is consumed in tiny amounts, sage provides only minuscule amounts of carbs, calories, protein and fiber.
        2. Loaded With Antioxidants - Antioxidants are molecules that help fortify your bodys defenses, neutralizing potentially harmful free radicals that are linked to chronic diseases. Sage contains over 160 distinct polyphenols, which are plant-based chemical compounds that act as antioxidants in your body. Chlorogenic acid, caffeic acid, rosmarinic acid, ellagic acid and rutin, all found in sage, are linked to impressive health benefits, such as a lower risk of cancer and improved brain function and memory. One study found that drinking 1 cup (240 ml) of sage tea twice daily significantly increased antioxidant defenses. It also lowered both total cholesterol and bad LDL cholesterol, as well as raised good HDL cholesterol.
        3. May Support Oral Health - Sage has antimicrobial effects, which can neutralize microbes that promote dental plaque. In one study, a sage-based mouthwash was shown to effectively kill the Streptococcus mutans bacteria, which is notorious for causing dental cavities. n a test-tube study, a sage-based essential oil was shown to kill and halt the spread of Candida albicans, a fungus that may also cause cavities. One review noted that sage may treat throat infections, dental abscesses, infected gums and mouth ulcers. However, more human research is needed to make comprehensive recommendations.
        4. May Ease Menopause Symptoms - During menopause, your body experiences a natural decline in the hormone estrogen. This can cause a wide range of unpleasant symptoms. Symptoms include hot flashes, excessive sweating, vaginal dryness and irritability. Common sage was traditionally used to reduce menopause symptoms. It is believed that compounds in sage have estrogen-like properties, allowing them to bind to certain receptors in your brain to help improve memory and treat hot flashes and excessive sweating. In one study, daily use of a sage supplement significantly reduced the number and intensity of hot flashes over eight weeks.
        5. May Reduce Blood Sugar Levels - The leaves of common sage have been used traditionally as a remedy against diabetes. Human and animal research indicates that it may help lower blood sugar levels. In one study, sage extract reduced blood glucose levels in rats with type 1 diabetes by activating a specific receptor. When this receptor is activated, it can help clear excess free fatty acids in the blood, which in turn improves insulin sensitivity. Another study in mice with type 2 diabetes found that sage tea acts like metformin, a drug prescribed to manage blood sugar in people with the same disease. In humans, sage leaf extract has been shown to lower blood sugar and improve insulin sensitivity with a similar effect as rosiglitazone, another anti-diabetes drug. However, there is still not enough evidence to recommend sage as a diabetes treatment. More human research is needed.
        6. May Support Memory and Brain Health - Sage can help support your brain and memory in several ways. For one, it is loaded with compounds that can act as antioxidants, which have been shown to buffer your brains defense system. It also appears to halt the breakdown of the chemical messenger acetylcholine (ACH), which has a role in memory. ACH levels appear to fall in Alzheimers disease. In healthy adults, sage was shown to improve memory in low doses. Higher doses also elevated mood and increased alertness, calmness and contentedness. In both younger and older adults, sage appears to improve memory and brain function.
        7. May Lower Bad LDL Cholesterol - Sage may help lower bad LDL cholesterol, which can build up in your arteries and potentially cause damage. In one study, consuming sage tea twice daily lowered bad LDL cholesterol and total blood cholesterol while raising good HDL cholesterol after just two weeks.
        8. May Protect Against Certain Cancers - Cancer is a leading cause of death in which cells grow abnormally. Interestingly, animal and test-tube studies demonstrate that sage may fight certain types of cancer, including those of the mouth, colon, liver, cervix, breast, skin and kidney. In these studies, sage extracts not only suppress the growth of cancer cells but also stimulate cell death. While this research is encouraging, human studies are needed to determine whether sage is effective at fighting cancer in humans.
        9. May alleviate diarrhea - Fresh sage is a traditional remedy for diarrhea. Test-tube and animal studies found that it contains compounds that may alleviate diarrhea by relaxing your gut.
        10. May support bone health - Vitamin K, which sage offers in large amounts, plays a role in bone health. A deficiency in this vitamin is linked to bone thinning and fractures.
        11. May combat skin aging - Several test-tube studies suggest that sage compounds may help fight signs of aging, such as wrinkles.
        12. Easy to Add to Your Diet - Sage comes in several forms and can be used in a variety of ways. Fresh sage leaves have a strong aromatic flavor and are best used sparingly in dishes. Dried sage is often preferred by cooks and comes ground, rubbed or in whole leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="habanero_details">
        Habanero is a common kind of chili pepper. Habanero naming after the Cuban city of La Habana. They have some colors variant, but the most common are orange and red. Habanero originally comes from Amazon. It is known as one of the hottest chili in the world. Therefore, many people use this pepper as the main ingredients of chili sauce.
        Habanero contains a number of nutrients which gives many health benefits. They contain a high concentration of vitamins, minerals and dietary fiber. As same as most of the chili pepper family, habanero also contain capsaicin. This compound gives many health benefits for people.
        Nutrients of Habanero Pepper - A single serving of Habanero (26gr) contains below nutrition - Calories 15cal, Total fat 0mg, Sodium 3mg, Protein 1gr, Sugar 2gr, Carbohydrates 4gr, Dietary Fiber 1gr, Potassium 128mg, Cholesterol 0mg, Calcium 2mg, Iron 3mg, Vitamin C 2.4mg, Vitamin A 0mg.
        There are main health benefits of eating habanero pepper. Those are - 1. Anti-Inflammatory - Habanero has anti-inflammatory effect. The capsaicin acting as an anti-inflammatory by slow down the production of substance. So that the inflammatory effect can be reduced, such as swelling and pain associated. That is why consuming this pepper is good to fight arthritis and also headache. It is a natural way to eliminate migraine and another type of pain. Another thing that habanero can avoid food bacteria. Therefore, it reduces the risk of having inflammation.
        2. Weight Loss - Capsaicin stimulate the body to a fast fat burning. The hot sensation increases human thermogenesis. It is a condition in which human body temperature is raised and the energy is output. The released energy was coming from fat burning; therefore, it helps to reduce weight. In case that habanero pepper is consume together during meal time, the thermogenesis will release an energy resulted from food. So that the body will not absorb the food into fat. But release it as an energy. People will feel hot and get sweat as its effect. The lipid metabolism inside the body is increased, so that the body avoid creating fat. Capsaicin also works to reduce human appetite, which avoid people to gain fat and become overweight.
        3. Prevent Diabetes - The contain of capsaicin in the habanero believed can help to reduce diabetes. It works by reduce the level of insulin. This will work maximize in overweight person, which mostly get risk of diabetes type 2. By consuming habanero, this can help blood glucose control. The blood glucose will reduce significant and avoid people getting diabetes. This is not mean that habanero pepper can cure diabetes. But it is precisely prevent and managed the body from diabetes. Be noted that the pepper will work optimize in controlling the sugar level on the blood if consuming uncooked. The cooked one may not be as effective as the raw one.
        4. Prevent Cardiovascular Disease - Inside the harbanero, the capsaicin stimulates the body nerves in a way that favours increase blood flow. The blood vessels will dilate and lowering the blood pressure. Therefore, it is increase circulation and might benefit people with high blood pressure. It is increase the insulin-like growth factor IGF-I. This help the blood cholesterol level to lower down. So that any type of the cardiovascular disease can be avoid. People with risk of heart attacks, stroke and high blood pressure is suggested to consume the pepper. This can be a natural way to keep a healthy blood flows. Furthermore, it is also able to reverse the damage blood vessel. And prevent the bad cholesterol of building up in the blood vessel.
        5. Anti-Cancer - Some research found that capsaicin is a best anti-oxidant. Therefore, habanero believed can help to reduce cancer. There is a research in the US that treat cancer patient with giving them hot peppers. They resulted an improved health condition. The cancer cells growth is significantly slowed down. In a research by Yucatan University mentioned that hot peppers including Habanero are known to be a good source of phenolic compounds such aspolyphenols, carotenoids and ascorbic acid. These phytochemicals exhibit high antioxidant activity, and their consumption has been linked to a decreased risk of developing chronic diseases including cancer.
        6. Pain Relief - Capsaicin is well known treatment for neuralgia. A condition in which a pain comes from the nerve that lie close to the skin surface. The use of capsaicin can be used to relieving pain from many different conditions, including arthritis, fibromyalgia, nerve pain and lower back pain. Capsaicin lower the amount of substance P, a chemical that helps transmit pain signals to the brain, when applied directly to the skin. Having habanero as a pain relief has been proven to be effective.
        7. Respiratory Treatment - Habanero pepper can eliminate sinuses. As the same way with other spicy food, the effect is good for opening up slogged sinuses. It means that it leads to a fast recover of cold. It works by giving a relief breathe system in human. The hot sensation feeling help to relief the respiratory system. It acts as decongestant and help the mucous out. So that you can breathe easier and relaxed. It is good for people with allergic symptoms such as asthma. It can soothe the lining of the lungs.
    </string>
    <string name="sea_salt_details">
        The health benefits of sea salt include skin care, improved dental health, and relief from rheumatoid arthritis, muscle cramps, psoriasis, and osteoarthritis. It also helps in providing relief from acne and rhinosinusitis. Furthermore, it is beneficial for exfoliation, nasal and eye wash, and an improved electrolytic balance of the body. It has healing properties that play a vital role in maintaining the acid-alkali ratio, regular heartbeat, and relaxed sleep, along with providing relief from fatigue.
        Sea salt, also known as bay salt, is produced by the process of evaporation of salt water bodies. It is darker in color as compared to refined salt due to the absorption of essential minerals from the clay lining of the body of water. Normally, the harvesting of refined table salt involves heavy processing, including mining followed by iodizing, bleaching, and diluting with anti-caking agents. More chemicals are added during the processing of salt, which often steals all of its beneficial minerals and trace elements, except sodium and chloride.
        Unlike refined salts, the preparation of sea salt usually includes very little processing, so it retains its moisture and mineral treasure. These minerals are present in a form that is easily utilized and absorbed by the human body. The climate and the geographical location of the region also play a significant role in the quality and combination of minerals offered by sea salt.
        The Mediterranean Sea, the Atlantic Ocean, and the North Sea are the most common hubs for harvesting sea salt. The method involved in harvesting also helps retain its natural state and therapeutic qualities. These healing properties of sea salt help in maintaining the good cellular functioning of the body and have been appreciated for ages. In ancient times, it was valuable for healing hand injuries and wounds of fishermen.
        Nutritional Value of Sea Salt - Sea salt derives 82 essential trace nutrients from the mineral treasure trove present in seawater. These natural minerals are valuable for the healthy functioning of the body. The nutritional wealth of sea salt includes vital minerals like sodium, potassium, calcium, magnesium, bromide, chloride, iron, copper, and zinc, among other beneficial elements.
        Health Benefits of Sea Salt - Sea salt consists of a similar assortment of minerals and natural healing elements as those found on skin cells. This makes it a perfect natural ingredient to be used for therapeutic treatments and beauty products.
        Skin Care - The mineral content in Dead Sea salt has long been appreciated for its rejuvenating effects on the skin. Bathing in a Dead Sea salt solution helps in keeping the skin moisturized and revitalized. Dead Sea salt baths also help in improving the skin barrier function and eliminating the roughness and inflammation on the skin’s surface. Studies have shown that this anti-inflammatory effect is attributed to the presence of a high content of magnesium in these salts. It also helps in the detoxification of the body by flushing out toxins from the pores, while also aiding in improving blood circulation.
        Oral Health - Sea salt contains fluoride, which is beneficial for promoting dental health. Fluoride aids in protecting the teeth from acidic damage and prevents the development of caries and cavities. Regular rinsing and gargling with tepid sea salt water help alleviate mouth sores, bleeding gums, ulcers, and the pain of sore throats.
        Relief from Rheumatoid Arthritis - Dead Sea salts have been proven to be effective in providing therapeutic relief to patients suffering from rheumatoid arthritis. Studies have made it clear that baths containing these salts possess anti-inflammatory qualities and have demonstrated significant improvements in such ailments as compared to normal sodium chloride baths.
        Encourages Exfoliation - Sea salt finds another use in the cosmetic industry in the manufacturing of scrubs and other skin care products like antiperspirants and deodorants. Exfoliation with sea salts helps remove dead skin particles, tone up the skin tissues, encourage peripheral blood circulation, and also promote skin renewal. Unlike table salt, the granular texture of sea salt works very well in providing clean and smooth skin. Sea salt scrub therapy is also advised for patients suffering from low blood pressure, epilepsy, poor blood circulation, and general body fatigue as it promotes healthy blood circulation.
        Relieve Symptoms of Psoriasis - Sea salt is considered to be a natural remedy useful for the treatment of psoriasis, along with the appropriate medication. Use of sea salt has shown noteworthy improvements in patients suffering from skin conditions like itching and scaling. The efficacy of balneotherapy, which is done using a sea salt treatment with mud packs and sulfur baths on those suffering from psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis has also demonstrated promising results with respect to a reduction in spinal pain and increased flexibility of the spine.
        Reduces Osteoarthritis Risk - Studies have demonstrated improvements in patients suffering from knee osteoarthritis after treatment using balneotherapy with Dead Sea salt. In addition to this, some patients were able to sustain their improved health parameters even after a few weeks, unlike those who took the bath treatment with normal sodium chloride.
        Rhinosinusitis - Research studies have proven that the Dead Sea salt solution is also effective in providing relief from rhinosinusitis. The study also concluded that nasal irrigation and sprays done with sea salt showed better symptomatic relief as compared to those made of a hypertonic saline solution. The anti-inflammatory effects of Dead Sea salts make them a natural and healthy alternative to be considered for relieving nasal allergies and other respiratory disorders as compared to nasal steroids, which have certain side effects like inflammation that can lead to mucus secretion. The mineral content present in Dead Sea salts helps alleviate swelling and congestion as well.
        Maintains Electrolyte Balance - Sea salt helps in maintaining a healthy electrolyte balance in the body, which is necessary for maintaining optimum blood composition and circulation, muscular strength, and overall functioning of the body. Minerals like potassium, calcium, magnesium, and sodium contribute to the electrolytic equilibrium of the body.
        Gives Relief from Acne - Sea salts contain sulfur which may help in cleansing and treating skin conditions like dermatitis and acne scars.
        Relaxes Aching Feet - Soaking your tired feet in a warm sea salt solution helps relax the muscles, and relieve the soreness and pain in your aching feet.
        Regulates Blood Sugar - Sea salts also help in maintaining balanced levels of blood sugar. It is effective in reducing the bodys dependency on insulin medication for the regulation of sugar levels.
        Encourages Restful Sleep - Sea salt baths have a calming and soporific effect, thus helping in inducing profound and rejuvenating sleep. They also help in preventing excess salivation that flows out of the mouth during sleep, keeping your body hydrated.
        Normalizes Heartbeat - Sea salt aids in maintaining healthy levels of blood pressure and helps normalize irregular heartbeats. It has also shown beneficial effects in preventing the occurrence of various cardiac disorders.
        Prevents Hair Loss - One of the lesser known benefits of sea salt is the stimulation of healthy hair growth. Massaging the scalp with the sea salt aids in the improved circulation of blood and it strengthens the hair follicles.
        Relieves Muscle Cramps - Sea salt is beneficial in relieving muscle cramps and enhancing muscular strength. Essential minerals like magnesium and potassium have therapeutic and rejuvenating qualities, thus making sea salts a natural remedy to cure aches and pains. The osmosis effect created by the solute content in a sea salt bath prevents the build-up of toxins in the body. This helps in easing any stiffness and discomfort caused by muscle fatigue and tension.
        Eye Care - A sea salt solution helps in relieving puffiness around your tired eyes. A sea salt compress aids in reducing the dark circles and sagging bags under the eyes, while inducing a calming, stress-relieving effect.
        Reduces Acidity - Sea salts help in alkalizing the cells of the body by facilitating the excretion of excess acids through urination. This helps in maintaining the optimal acid-alkali ratio of the body. In case the pH value of the blood moves towards the acidic side, it can disturb the natural, healthy balance of the body and may result in chronic medical conditions.
        Healing and Purifying Properties - The electromagnetic force field that surrounds our body tends to attract negative energies and impurities from the environment. These energies may influence the health and well-being of some people. Baths enriched with sea salts are believed to have purifying qualities as they absorb such energies within themselves and relieve the body of toxins.
    </string>
    <string name="basil_details">
        Basil, also known as Saint Josephs Wort, is an herb belonging to the mint family. It is used as in cooking and may have some health benefits. Basils proposed benefits include reducing inflammation, and it is said to have anti-aging and antibacterial properties.
        Fast facts on basil - The herb may have anti-inflammatory qualities. Basil is a potent antibacterial. Containing just 22 calories per 100 grams, basil is nutrient-heavy and calorie-light. Basil may contain compounds that fight the effects of aging.
        Basil is used in traditional Tamil and Ayurvedic medicine, which is a form of traditional medicine popular on the Indian subcontinent.  There are a number of types of basil, which differ in taste and smell. Sweet basil (the most commercially available basil used in Italian food) has a strong clove scent because of its high concentration of the chemical agent eugenol. Alternatively, lime and lemon basil have a strong citrus scent due to their high concentration of limonene.
        Benefits - Studies have shown that basil contains a wide range of essential oils, rich in phenolic compounds, and a wide array of other natural products including polyphenols such as flavonoids and anthocyanins. According to research conducted at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, basil contains (E)-beta-caryophyllene (BCP), which may be useful in treating arthritis and inflammatory bowel diseases.
        Fighting cancer - A review, published in 2013, investigated the potential for holy basil to prevent cancer. They concluded that, thanks to the phytochemicals it contains, including eugenol, rosmarinic acid, apigenin, myretenal, luteolin, β-sitosterol, and carnosic acid, it may help prevent certain types of skin, liver, oral, and lung cancers. It appears to do this by increasing antioxidant activity, changing gene expression, triggering cell death, and slowing cell division.
        Reducing the effects of oxidative stress - An adaptogen is a herbal medicine that helps the body adapt to stress; ginseng is perhaps the most well known. Basil may also fall into this category. In one study, rabbits were exposed to oxidative stress (an increase in damaging free radicals). The rabbits were given 2 grams of fresh basil leaves each day for 30 days, and cardiovascular and respiratory adaptation were monitored. The researchers measured a significant decrease in blood sugar levels and an increase in antioxidant activity. The basil appeared to help the rabbits deal better with oxidative stress.
        Anti-aging properties - According to research presented at the British Pharmaceutical Conference (BPC) in Manchester, basil also has properties that might help prevent some of the harmful effects of aging. Holy basil extract was effective at killing off harmful molecules and preventing damage caused by some free radicals in the liver, brain, and heart. The researchers, led by Dr. Vaibhav Shinde from Poona College of Pharmacy, Maharashtra, India, studied the herb for antioxidant and anti-aging properties. Dr. Shinde said: "The study validates the traditional use of the herb as a youth-promoting substance in the Ayurvedic system of medicine. It also helps describe how the herb acts at a cellular level."
        Reduce inflammation and swelling - One study, presented at the Royal Pharmaceutical Societys annual event, found - "Extracts of O. tenuiflorum (Holy basil) were shown to reduce swelling by up to 73 percent, 24 hours after treatment." These effects on swelling were similar in extent to those seen with the drug diclofenac, an anti-inflammatory medication that is widely used in the treatment of arthritis.
        Rich in antioxidants - Results of a study published in the Journal of Advanced Pharmacy Education and Research showed that ethanol extract - Ocimum basilicum - had more antioxidant activity than standard antioxidants.
        Antibacterial properties - Lab studies have demonstrated that basil has antibacterial properties; this may be because of the volatile oils it contains, which include estragole, linalool, cineole, eugenol, sabinene, myrcene, and limonene. Basil restricts the growth of numerous bacteria, including Listeria monocytogenes, Staphylococcus aureus, Escherichia coli O157:H7, Yersinia enterocolitica, and Pseudomonas aeruginosa. This could mean that adding fresh basil to a salad not only adds flavor, it also helps reduce the number of harmful bacteria on the plate.
        Nutrition - Basil is rich in vitamin A, vitamin K, vitamin C, magnesium, iron, potassium, and calcium. As with any foodstuff, basil should be eaten alongside the full range of components that make up a healthy diet.
    </string>
    <string name="cayenne_details">
        Cayenne pepper is a hot chili pepper in the Capsicum family that is frequently added to dishes to enhance their flavor.
        Fast facts on cayenne pepper - The chili originated in Central and South America, and it is named after a city of the same name in French Guiana. Cayenne pepper has been a part of Native American cuisine and medicine for at least 9,000 years. Many of the health benefits of cayenne pepper are attributed to the ingredient capsaicin. The pepper contains vitamin C, vitamin B6, vitamin E, potassium, manganese, and flavonoids. Open wounds or breaks in the skin should not be exposed to capsaicin.
        The thin, red pepper has a deceptively mild smell but a powerful, fiery taste. The peppers are often dried and ground to make a powdered spice used for seasoning. The peppers are also used in their whole form in Korean, Sichuan, and other Asian cuisines. Capsaicin, the active ingredient in cayenne peppers, gives the powder its spiciness and is used to treat aches and pains of the muscles and joints. Cayenne pepper has also been used in traditional Chinese and Ayurvedic medicines to help treat circulatory problems and increase appetite.
        Benefits - Relieving pain - Capsaicin, the active ingredient found in cayenne peppers, may have pain-relieving properties. One review of research into cayenne peppers ability to reduce pain, concluded that it may have benefits as a long-term analgesia, without bringing about other sensory changes. Capsaicin has also been shown to reduce the amount of substance P, a chemical that carries pain messages to the brain. With less substance P, fewer pain messages reach the brain, and less pain is felt. Capsaicin is currently used in topical ointments and creams to relieve pain and tenderness from osteoarthritis, nerve pain from shingles, pain after surgery, pain from diabetic neuropathy, and lower back pain. Capsaicin has been investigated in relation to cancer treatment and pain relief related to cancer. It appears to be effective in reducing pain. However, conflicting results have shown that it may help prevent cancer, or that it may promote tumor growth. Caution is recommended.
        Burning calories and suppressing appetite - There are many products containing cayenne pepper that claim to boost metabolism and promote weight loss. However, not all scientific studies agree. Researchers at Purdue University found that cayenne pepper consumption increased core body temperature slightly, which would, in turn, burn calories.
        Relieving congestion - Cayenne pepper is often used as a home remedy for coughs, colds, and congestion. There are no studies to support this use, but cayenne may help to temporarily relieve congestion by shrinking the blood vessels in the nose and throat. One popular home recipe combines 1/4 teaspoon of cayenne pepper, 1/4 teaspoon of ground ginger, 1 tablespoon of honey, 1 tablespoon of apple cider vinegar, and 2 tablespoons of water to take by the teaspoon. Other people mix cayenne pepper and apple cider vinegar into a hot tea to clear the sinuses.
        Nutrition - According to the USDA National Nutrient Database, one tablespoon of cayenne pepper, weighing 5.3 grams (g) contains: 17 calories, 0.64 g of protein, 0.92 g of fat, 3 g of carbohydrates, including 1.4 g of fiber and 0.6 g of sugar., 8 mg of calcium, 0.41 mg of iron, 8 mg of magnesium, 16 mg of phosphorus, 107 mg of potassium. Other nutrients include vitamin C, thiamin, riboflavin, niacin, vitamin B-6, and folate. It is also high in flavonoids and carotenoids, which give the spice its red color.
    </string>
    <string name="cloves_details">
        Cloves are dried flower buds from the clove tree. They are a popular spice that people use in soups, stews, meats, sauces, and rice dishes. Their name comes from the Latin word clavus, which means nail since the shape of a dried clove resembles that of a nail.
        Health benefits of cloves - Oral health - Researchers are studying clove oil as a natural method for maintaining oral health due to its effect on plaque, gingivitis, and bacteria in the mouth. Researchers compared the effectiveness of an herbal mouth rinse containing clove, basil, and tea tree oil with a commercially available essential oil mouth rinse. Both mouth rinses were effective against plaque and gingivitis, showing that they may help decrease oral inflammation and bacteria. The researchers also found that the mouth rinse that contained clove decreased the number of harmful bacteria more than the commercial mouth rinse.
        Diabetes - A study in mice found that clove extract and nigericin, a component of clove extract, reduced insulin resistance in mouse muscle cells. Mice with diabetes that consumed nigericin also had less insulin resistance and improvements in glucose tolerance, insulin secretion, and beta cell function. Another animal study looked at the effect of clove bud powder on laboratory markers in a rat model of diabetes. They found that blood sugar level was lower in rats that received the clove powder compared to those in the control group that did not receive the clove powder.
        Cancer - Many herbs and spices are high in antioxidants, which are chemicals that play a part in reducing damage to cells that could lead to cancer. According to Todays Dietitian, "just 1/2 teaspoon of ground clove is said to contain more antioxidants than 1/2 cup of blueberries." In one laboratory study, scientists found that clove extract was able to slow the growth of multiple types of human cancer cells. Clove extract also increased cell death in colon cancer cells. The same study also looked at the effect of clove extract on tumor growth in mice. Tumors grew significantly less in the mice treated with clove extract compared to those in the control group. In another study, scientists looked at the effect of different preparations of clove extract on human breast cancer cells. They found that clove essential oil and ethanol extract of clove were both toxic to breast cancer cells. The authors reported that cloves might have a beneficial role in the future of cancer treatment since they can cause cell death and slow cell multiplication.
        Obesity - Scientists have also studied cloves regarding their potential effect on obesity. In a study of mice, researchers found that clove extract reduced the incidence of obesity resulting from a high-fat diet. Mice who received the clove extract had lower body weight, less abdominal fat, and less liver fat than those in the control group.
        Nutritional information - According to the United States Department of Agriculture National Nutrient Database, 2.1 grams (g) or 1 teaspoon of ground cloves contains: 6 kilocalories (kcal), 0.13 grams (g) of protein, 0.27 g total fat, 1.38 g carbohydrate, 0.7 g fiber. The same amount of ground cloves also provides 1.263 milligrams (mg) of manganese, which is 63 percent of the Daily Value (DV) for manganese.
    </string>
    <string name="dill_details">
        Dill (Anethum graveolens), or dill weed, is an easy-to-find and commonly used annual herb that is part of the celery (Apiaceae) family. Dill weed is native to native to the Mediterranean and southern Russia but can be grown in most parts of the world, including in North America. The feathery green is often added to salads or soups, or used as a garnish. Some people also use dill to gain certain health benefits.
        Health Benefits - Dill is packed with micronutrients that provide health benefits. For example, a 100-gram serving of dill boosts your vitamin A intake. Vitamin A is a fat-soluble vitamin that helps you to maintain healthy vision, skin, immune function, growth, and reproductive health. You will also get a significant boost of vitamin C, an important antioxidant that helps your body to resist infection.
        Dill is also a good source of fiber, folate (important for cell division and production of DNA), calcium for healthy bones, riboflavin for cell function and development, manganese, and iron.
        However, the amount of dill you consume makes a difference. You might not consume a full 100-gram serving (that is about 2/3 cup). Many people use a much smaller amount and will get smaller doses of micronutrients.
        Dill has been used for centuries in traditional Asian and Ayurvedic medicine. Currently, people use dill for certain medicinal purposes, including: Gastrointestinal disorders, Loss of appetite, Kidney disease, Flatulence, Fever and colds, Cough, Bronchitis, Infectious disease, Liver and gallbladder complaints, Urinary tract disorders, Hemorrhoids, Spasms, Neuropathy, Renal colic, Dysuria, Genital ulcers, Dysmenorrhea, Insomnia and other sleep disorders.
        Research studies have suggested that dill may have an antidiabetic effect, with authors of one review stating, "It can be suggested for the management of diabetic patients." More studies are needed to confirm this benefit.
        There are also some studies suggesting that dill may help you manage cholesterol. But other studies have shown that dill has no effect, so it is unclear if there is enough evidence to support this benefit.
        Lastly, scientists are investigating whether or not dill may have an effect on metabolic syndrome. One 12-week study found that dill extract had a beneficial effect on triglyceride levels but no effect on waist circumference, blood pressure, and fasting blood sugar.
        Nutrition - A 100-gram serving of fresh, raw garden dill provides about 43 calories. A serving of the herb also provides 3.5 grams of protein and just over 1 gram of fat. Two-thirds cup of dill also provides 7 grams of carbohydrate, and about 2 grams of fiber, according to USDA data. Vitamins in dill include vitamin A (7717 IU, or 154 percent of your daily recommended intake), vitamin C (85 mg, or 142 percent of your daily recommended intake), folate (about 38 percent of your recommended daily intake) and riboflavin (17 percent of your recommended intake). You will also get small amounts of thiamin, niacin, vitamin B6, and pantothenic acid. Minerals in dill include calcium (208 mg), iron (6.6 mg), magnesium (55 mg), phosphorus (66 mg), potassium (738 mg), manganese (1.3 mg), and small amounts of sodium, zinc, and copper.
    </string>
    <string name="onions_details">
        Onions are part of the allium family of vegetables and herbs, which also includes chives, garlic, scallions, and leeks. Allium vegetables have been cultivated for centuries for their characteristic, pungent flavors and for their medicinal properties.
        Onions can vary in size, shape, color, and flavor. The most common types are red, yellow, and white onions. Flavors can be sweet and juicy to sharp, spicy, and pungent, often depending on the season in which they are grown and consumed. The possible health benefits of consuming onions include lowering the risk of several types of cancer, improving mood, and maintaining the health of skin and hair.
        Fast facts on onions: Onions have been used as food for thousands of years; in ancient Egypt, they were worshiped and used in burial rituals. Onions have many possible health benefits including reducing the risk of obesity, heart disease, and cancer. They are high in vitamins, minerals, and antioxidants. Incorporating onions into a diet is very simple, with a versatile range of ways they can be prepared and cooked in regular foods.
        Benefits - Many studies have suggested that increasing consumption of plant foods like onions decreases the risk of overall mortality, diabetes, and heart disease. Plant foods also promote a healthful complexion, hair, increased energy, and overall lower weight.
        Cancer - Allium vegetables have been studied extensively in relation to cancer, especially stomach and colorectal cancers. Their beneficial and preventive effects are likely due in part to their rich organosulfur compounds. The exact mechanism by which these compounds inhibit cancer is unknown, but hypotheses include the inhibition of tumor growth and mutagenesis, and prevention of free radical formation. Onions are also a source of the strong antioxidant vitamin C that helps to combat the formation of free radicals known to cause cancer.
        Colon cancer - High fiber intake from all fruits and vegetables are associated with a lowered risk of colorectal cancer. One study showed that consuming greater than 7 servings of onions per week was associated with a decrease in colorectal cancer.
        Prostate cancer - In a paper, published by the Journal of the National Cancer Institute, researchers used a population-based, case-controlled study to investigate the relationship between allium vegetable intake and prostate cancer. They found that men with the highest intake of allium vegetables had the lowest risk of prostate cancer.
        Esophageal and stomach cancer - Frequent intake of allium vegetables has been shown to reduce the risk of esophageal and stomach cancer. Several survey-based human studies have demonstrated the potential protective effects of consuming alliums, as well as reports of tumor inhibition of allium compounds in animal experiments.
        Sleep and mood - Folate, found in onions, might help reduce depression. Homocysteine prevents blood and other nutrients from reaching the brain, and folate prevents this chemical from building up. Excess homocysteine also interferes with the production of the feel-good hormones serotonin, dopamine, and norepinephrine, which regulate not only mood, but also sleep and appetite.
        Skin and hair - Onions are high in vitamin C, which is needed for the building and maintenance of collagen, which provides structure to skin and hair.
        Nutrition - Onions are a nutrient-dense food, meaning that while they are low in calories, they are high in beneficial nutrients like vitamins, minerals, and antioxidants. One cup of chopped onion contains approximately 64 calories, 15 grams of carbohydrate, 0 grams of fat, 0 grams of cholesterol, 3 grams of fiber, 7 grams of sugar, 2 grams of protein, and 10 percent or more of the daily value for vitamin C, vitamin B-6, and manganese. Onions also contain small amounts of calcium, iron, folate, magnesium, phosphorus, and potassium, and the antioxidants quercetin and sulfur.
    </string>
    <string name="oregano_details">
        Oregano is a culinary and medicinal herb from the mint, or Lamiaceae family. It has been used in medicine and cooking for thousands of years. It adds flavor, and it may have a number of health benefits.
        The name of the herb comes from the Greek words "oros," meaning mountain, and "ganos," meaning joy. It typically grows around 50 cm tall and has purple leaves around 2 to 3 centimeters in length. The chemicals that give the herb its unique and pleasant smell are thymol, pinene, limonene, carvacrol, ocimene, and caryophyllene. It is believed to contain potent antioxidants and to have anti-bacterial properties.
        Fast facts on oregano: Oregano is a Mediterranean herb that is used for cooking and medicinal purposes, ranging from treating infections to repelling insects. Active ingredients in oregano could one day help treat osteoporosis, cancer, and diabetes. Use it to flavor sauces, make herby bread rolls, and in marinades for meat. People with an allergy to mint should take care when consuming oregano.
        Benefits - Oregano was used in herbal medicine as long ago as the Ancient Greeks. Hippocrates used it as an antiseptic. Possible medicinal uses of oregano include treating respiratory tract disorders, gastrointestinal (GI) disorders, menstrual cramps, and urinary tract disorders. Applied topically, it may help treat a number of skin conditions, such as acne and dandruff.
        1. Antibacterial properties - Oregano oil contains an essential compound called carvacrol, which has antimicrobial properties. The herb has shown antimicrobial activity in a number of studies. One group of researchers found that Origanum vulgare essential oils were effective against 41 strains of the food pathogen Listeria monocytogenes. Another team from India and the United Kingdom (U.K.) reported that the essential oil of Himalayan oregano has strong antibacterial properties that may protect against the hospital superbug, MRSA.
        2. Anti-inflammatory properties - Scientists from Germany and Switzerland identified an active ingredient in oregano, known as beta-caryophyllin (E-BCP), which may help treat disorders such as osteoporosis and arteriosclerosis. E-BCP is a dietary cannabinoid.
        3. Protecting against cancer - Research published in the journal PLoS ONE in 2013 suggested that oregano exhibits anticancer activity. The scientists concluded that Origanum majorana could help prevent and treat breast cancer by slowing or preventing its progression. In 2014, food scientists discovered that the popular culinary herbs oregano, rosemary, and marjoram contain compounds that may have the potential to manage type 2 diabetes in a similar way to some currently prescribed drugs.
        Other possible health benefits - According to The Natural Medicines Comprehensive Database, oregano can be used for the following illnesses and conditions: cold sores, muscle pain, acne, dandruff, bronchitis, toothache, bloating, headaches, heart conditions, allergies, intestinal parasites, earache, sore throat, fatigue, repelling insects, menstrual cramps.
        Oregano essential oil, made from Origanum vulgare or Thymus capitatus, may help with the following problems: Foot or nail fungus: Put a few drops in water and soak the feet in it, or apply diluted oil topically to the affected area. Sinus infections and colds: Use a few drops in a steam bath and inhale. Any essential oil should be diluted before use, either with a carrier oil, such as olive oil, or in water, as for a steam bath.
        Oregano contains some important nutrients. One teaspoon of dried oregano contains: energy: 5 calories, fiber: 0.8 grams (g), calcium: 29 milligrams (mg), iron: 0.66 mg, magnesium: 5 g, manganese: 0.09 mg, potassium: 23 mg, vitamin E: 0.33 mg, vitamin K: 11.2 micrograms (mcg). Vitamin K is important for bone growth, maintaining bone density, and the production of blood clotting proteins. Calcium is necessary for the formation of bones and teeth. Oregano is also a rich source of dietary antioxidants, which help protect cells against the effects of free radicals and improve the bodys ability to fight infection.
    </string>
    <string name="thyme_details">
        Thyme is a Mediterranean herb with dietary, medicinal, and ornamental uses. The flowers, leaves, and oil of thyme have been used to treat a range of symptoms and complaints. These include diarrhea, stomach ache, arthritis, and sore throat.
        Fast facts on thyme - Thyme is thought to have antibacterial, insecticidal, and possibly antifungal properties. People used thyme throughout history for embalming and to protect from the Black Death. Forms of thyme include fresh and dried herbs and essential oil.
        Benefits - Thymol is one of a naturally occurring class of compounds known as biocides. These are substances that can destroy harmful organisms, such as infectious bacteria. Used alongside other biocides, such as carvacrol, thyme has strong antimicrobial properties. One study from 2010 suggests that thymol can reduce bacterial resistance to common drugs, including penicillin.
        Killing the tiger mosquito - The tiger mosquito is native to tropical and subtropical areas of Southeast Asia. Since the 1990s, it has spread around the world, carrying West Nile virus, Yellow fever, St. Louis encephalitis, dengue fever, and Chikungunya fever. A team at Chungbuk National University in South Korea reported that a combination of thymol, alpha-terpinene, and carvacrol was effective in killing off tiger mosquito larvae.
        High blood pressure - Researchers at the University of Belgrade, Serbia, found that an aqueous extract obtained from wild thyme reduced blood pressure in tests on rats. Rats respond to hypertension in a similar way to people, so the findings might have implications for humans.
        Foodborne bacterial infections - A team at the Center for Studies of Animal and Veterinary Sciences, Portugal, studied the antimicrobial activity of essential oils extracted from a range of aromatic plants, including thyme oil. They reported that thyme oil, even at low concentrations, showed potential as a natural preservative of food products against several common foodborne bacteria that cause human illness. A Polish study tested thyme oil and lavender oil, and they that observed that thyme oil was effective against resistant strains of Staphylococcus, Enterococcus, Escherichia and Pseudomonas bacteria.
        Colon cancer - A study carried out in Lisbon, Portugal, found that extracts of mastic thyme might protect people from colon cancers.
        Breast cancer - Researchers in Turkey looked at the effect of wild thyme on breast cancer activity, and specifically how it affected apoptosis, or cell death, and gene-related events in breast cancer cells. They found that wild thyme caused cell death in breast cancer cells.
        Yeast infection - The fungus Candida albicans (C. albicans) is a common cause of yeast infections in the mouth and vagina, a recurring condition called "thrush." Researchers at the University of Turin, Italy, found that essential oil of thyme significantly enhanced the destruction of the C. albicans fungus in the human body.
        Prolonging the stability of cooking oils - Lipid oxidation is a serious problem during food processing and storage. It can cause food to lose quality, stability, safety, and nutritional value. Scientists from Warsaw, Poland, examined whether thyme extract might prolong the stability of sunflower oil at different temperatures. They suggest that thyme might be a potent antioxidant for stabilizing sunflower oil.
        Common skin problems - Skin problems are common worldwide. In some countries, herbal preparations are important medicines. A team at Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia, carried out a study to assess the therapeutic benefits of a 10 percent chamomile extract cream and a 3 percent thyme essential oil antifungal cream for eczema-like lesions. They noted that full healing occurred in 66.5 percent of people treated with a fungal cream containing thyme essential oil, compared with 28.5 percent of those using a placebo. Results for the chamomile cream were similar to those for the placebo.
        The researchers conclude: "A 3 percent thyme essential oil cream could represent a relatively economical and easily available opportunity to treat and heal mild to moderate cases of fungal infections." However, they recommend further research.
        Acne - Scientists from Leeds, England, tested the effects of myrrh, marigold, and thyme tinctures on Propionibacterium acnes (P. acnes), the bacterium that causes acne. They found that thyme might be effective in treating acne. Its antibacterial effect proved stronger than that of standard concentrations of benzoyl peroxide, the active ingredient in most acne creams and washes. Benzoyl peroxide also causes a burning sensation and irritation on the skin, which means that a thyme tincture might be a solution to acne that leads to fewer unwanted effects.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_question_model">QuestionModel</string>

</resources>
